[zh:]-=The Last Fantasy=- 出品：TLF HalfCD Team  压制：20qq 本作品仅供交流学习，严禁商用 THE LAST FANTASY | TLF HALFCD TeaM 白日焰火  | 压制:cp3you | 字幕:OCR 仅供交流  严禁商用
[ar:]ترجمة: أحمد البوقس[fix]
[ko:]자막 제작 : 아이디스크 고전 명작 전문 클럽     클래식 무비(Classic Movies) '호림아'[fix]
[zh:]北京
[en:]Peiking has changed so fast.
[fre:]Pékin a changé si vite.[fix]
[ar:]...بكين
[ko:]http://club.nate.com/classicmovies[fix]
[ru:]Пекин изменился так быстро.
[zh:]变得这么快
[ar:]تغيرت بسرعة كبيرة
[ko:]베이징은 너무 빨리 변했다.[fix]
[zh:]20年的功夫她已经成为一个现代化的城市
[en:]In 20 years, it's become a modern city.
[fre:]En 20 ans, c'est devenu une ville moderne.
[ar:]في 20 عام، أصبحت مدينة حديثة[fix]
[ko:]20년 사이에, 그곳은 현대적 도시가 되버렸다.[fix]
[ru:]За 20 лет он стал современным городом
[zh:]我几乎从中找不到任何记忆里的东西
[en:]Almost nothing is as I remembered.
[fre:]Il ne reste presque plus rien comme dans mes souvenirs.
[ar:]لا شيء تقريباً يبدو كما أذكره[fix]
[ko:]기억나는 것이라곤 거의 없다.[fix]
[ru:]От города моего детства почти ничего не осталось.
[zh:]事实上这种变化已破坏了我的记忆
[en:]Change has wiped out my memorize.
[fre:]Le changement a balayé ma mémoire.
[ar:]هذه التغيرات مسحت ذكرياتي[fix]
[ko:]변화가 내 기억을 지워버렸다.[fix]
[ru:]Эти изменения вытерли мою память
[zh:]我分不清幻觉和真实
[en:]I can't tell what's imagined from what's real.
[fre:]Je ne peux discerner ce qui est imaginaire de ce qui est réel.
[ar:]ولم أعد قادرا على تمييز الوهم من الحقيقة[fix]
[ko:]내가 상상했던 일들과 실제로 일어났던 일들을  난 구별하지 못한다.[fix]
[ru:]И я уже не могу отличить реальное от воображаемого.
[zh:]我的故事总是发生在夏天
[en:]My stories always take place in summer.
[fre:]Mes histoires se passent toujours durant l'été.
[ar:]قصصي دائما تحدث في الصيف[fix]
[ko:]내 이야기는 항상 여름에 일어난다.[fix]
[ru:]Мои истории всегда случались летом.
[zh:]炎热的气候使人们裸露得更多
[en:]People expose more of themselves in the heat.
[fre:]Les gens se dévoilent plus sous la chaleur,
[ar:]يكشف الناس عن أنفسهم بشكل أكثر أثناء الحر[fix]
[ko:]사람들은 햇빛에 몸을 드러내놓고,[fix]
[ru:]В жару люди раздеваются - и снаружи, и внутри.
[zh:]也更难以掩饰心中的欲望
[en:]and find it harder to control their desires.
[fre:]et ont plus de mal à contrôler leurs désirs.
[ar:]ويجدون أن التحكم برغباتهم أصعب[fix]
[ko:]그들의 욕망을 통제하기가  어렵다는 것을 깨닫는다.[fix]
[ru:]И им становится трудно сдерживать свои желания.
[zh:]那时候好象永远是夏天
[en:]It seemed like it was always summer then.
[fre:]On avait l'impression que c'était toujours l'été.
[ar:]، في ذلك الوقت كان الصيف يبدو أنه سيدوم للأبد[fix]
[ko:]그래서 이 이야기는  항상 여름에 일어났는지도 모르겠다.[fix]
[ru:]Кажется, в те годы все время было лето.
[zh:]太阳总是有空出来伴随着我
[en:]The sun always had time to come out and play with us.
[fre:]Le soleil avait toujours le temps de sortir, et jouer avec nous.
[ar:]دائما ما كان للشمس وقت لتطلع وترافقني[fix]
[ko:]태양은 항상 제 시간에 어김없이 나오고, 우리와 함께 어울린다.[fix]
[ru:]Солнце всегда находило время, чтобы выйти и играть с нами.
[zh:]阳光充足
[en:]The sunlight was so relentless,
[fre:]La lumière était si implacable,
[ar:]، من شدة أشعة الشمس[fix]
[ko:]햇빛은 아주 가차없었고,[fix]
[ru:]Солнечный свет был столь непрестанным,
[zh:]太亮
[en:]so bright,
[fre:]si claire,
[ar:]، وقوة ضياءها
[ru:]столь ярким
[zh:]使得眼前一阵阵发黑
[en:]that our eyes were washed in waves of blackness.
[fre:]que nos yeux étaient balayés par des vagues d'ombres.
[ar:]جُرفت أعيننا بموجات من السواد[fix]
[ko:]아주 밝았기 때문에[fix] 우리의 눈은 어둠의 물결속에서만  씻겨질 수 있었다.[fix]
[ru:]что у нас порой темнело в глазах.
[zh:]阳光灿烂的日子
[en:]In the Heat of the Sun.
[fre:]In the Heat of the Sun.
[ko:]햇빛 쏟아지던 날들.[fix]
[ru:]Под жарким солнцем
[zh:]革命风雷激荡
[en:]In the raging storms of Revolution.
[fre:]En pleine tempête de la Révolution,
[ar:]في العواصف الهائجة للثورة[fix]
[ko:]혁명의 성난 폭풍 속에서[fix]
[ru:]В яростных бурях революции
[zh:]战士胸有朝阳
[en:]The soldiers' hearts turn towards the sun.
[fre:]le cœur des soldats se tourne vers le soleil.
[ar:]شمس الصباح تعيش في قلوب الجنود[fix]
[ko:]군인들의 심장은 태양을 향했네.[fix]
[ru:]Сердца солдат поворачиваются к солнцу
[zh:]毛主席呀毛主席
[en:]Oh, Chairman Mao, Chairman Mao.
[fre:]Oh, Président Mao, Président Mao.
[ar:]!(الزعيم (ماو)! أوه، الزعيم (ماو[fix]
[ko:]오, 마오 주석, 마오 주석.[fix]
[ru:]О, Председатель Мао, Председатель Мао
[zh:]我们有多少知心的话儿要对你讲
[en:]We want to express our ardor to you.
[fre:]Nous voulons exprimer notre ferveur pour vous.
[ar:]كم من كلمات الإخلاص[fix]
[ko:]우리는 당신에게 충성을 맹세하고 싶습니다.[fix]
[ru:]Мы хотим, чтобы ты увидел наш пыл.
[zh:]您亲手发动的文化大革命
[en:]You launched the Cultural Revolution.
[fre:]Vous avez lancé la Révolution Culturelle,
[ar:]نود قولها لك[fix] أطلقتَ الثورة الثقافية الكبرى[fix]
[ko:]우리는 문화 혁명의 닻을 올렸고,[fix]
[ru:]Ты начал Культурную революцию,
[zh:]火一样的辉煌
[en:]and your military victories are stunning.
[fre:]et vos victoires militaires sont éclatantes.
[ar:]لهيبها كلهيب النار[fix]
[ko:]당신의 군대는 압도적으로  승리하고 있습니다.[fix]
[ru:]и твои военные победы ошеломляют.
[zh:]您的光辉思想象雨露阳光
[en:]Your brilliant thoughts are like dew and sunlight.
[fre:]Vos brillantes pensées sont telles la rosée et la lumière du soleil...
[ar:]فكرك المجيد كالندى بضياء الشمس[fix]
[ko:]당신의 찬란한 생각들은 이슬과 햇빛 같습니다.[fix]
[ru:]Твои идеи блестящие, как роса на солнце.
[zh:]哺育我们成长
[ar:]يغذي نمونا[fix]
[zh:]九大以后
[en:]After the 9th Party Congress in 1969.
[fre:]Après le 9ème Congrès du Parti en 1969,[fix]
[ru:]После IX партийного съезда в 1969 г.[fix]
[zh:]我爸爸他们部队接受了新任务
[en:]my father was sent to Guizhou as an army rep.
[fre:]mon père a été envoyé à Guizhou comme représentant de l'Armée,
[ar:]بعد المؤتمر التاسع للحزب عام 1969 تلقت وحدة أبي مهمة جديدة[fix]
[ko:]1969년 9차 당대회 후,[fix] 군인이었던 아버지는,  파벌 싸움을 막기 위해[fix]
[ru:]моего отца отправили в Гуйчжоу как представителя армии
[zh:]要去贵州进行三支两军工作
[en:]to stop factional battles taking place there.
[fre:]pour arrêter les batailles entre combats qui se déroulaient là-bas.
[ar:]حيث اُرسلوا إلى قويتشو لدعم الحشود وتأدية التدريب السياسي كوحدة عسكرية نموذجية[fix]
[ko:]귀주성으로 보내졌다.[fix]
[ru:]остановить межфракционные дискуссии, которые там происходили.
[zh:]当军代表
[zh:]我最大的幻想便是中苏开战
[en:]I longed for a Sino-Soviet war.
[fre:]J'espérais une guerre Sino-soviétique.
[ar:]كان أشد أمنياتي أن تقوم حرب بين الصين والاتحاد السوفياتي[fix]
[ko:]나는 중국 소비에트 전쟁이 일어나기를 오랫동안 바랬다.[fix]
[ru:]Я жаждал китайско-советской войны.
[zh:]因为我坚信
[en:]I was sure
[fre:]J'étais sûr
[ru:]Я был уверен
[zh:]在新的一场世界大战中
[en:]that in a new world war...
[fre:]que durant une nouvelle guerre mondiale
[ar:]لأنني كنت على يقين ...أن بحرب عالمية جديدة[fix]
[ru:]что в новой мировой войне...
[zh:]我军的铁拳定会把苏美两军的 战争机器砸得粉碎
[en:]...the PLA's iron fist would smash the Soviets and Americans.
[fre:]la main d'acier de l'ALP écraserait les Soviétiques et les Américains.[fix]
[ar:]ستسحق القبضة الحديدية لجيش التحرير الشعبي السوفييت والأمريكيين[fix]
[ko:]확신하건데,[fix] 새로운 전쟁에서...[fix] ...인민 해방군의 철의 주먹은 소련과 미국을 날려버릴 것이다.[fix]
[ru:]железный кулак НОАР разбил бы и Советы, и американцев.
[zh:]一位举世瞩目的战争 英雄将由此诞生
[en:]A new war hero would become a legend -
[fre:]Un nouveau héros de guerre deviendrait une légende...
[ar:]وأن بطل حرب شهير عالمي سيولد[fix]
[ko:]그리고 새로운 전쟁 영웅이  전설로 남게 될것이다.[fix]
[ru:]Новый герой войны стал бы легендой -
[zh:]那就是我
[en:]that's me, of course.
[fre:]et ce serait moi, bien sûr.
[ar:]وهو أنا[fix]
[ko:]그건 물론, 나였다.[fix]
[ru:]и это, конечно, был бы я.
[zh:]远飞的大雁
[en:]Hurry
[fre:]Dépêche-toi.
[ar:]أيتها الأوزة البرية المحلقة بعيدا[fix]
[ko:]서둘러라.[fix]
[ru:]Быстро
[zh:]请你快快飞
[en:]wild goose hurry on your way.
[fre:]Oie Sauvage, hâte-toi sur la route.[fix]
[ar:]رجاء عجلي في طريقك[fix]
[ko:]야생의 거위들아, 서둘러.[fix]
[ru:]летит дикий гусь к вам
[zh:]捎个信儿到北京
[en:]With a letter from the liberated serfs under your wing.
[fre:]Sous ton aile, apporte la lettre des paysans libérés[fix]
[ar:]وصلي الرسالة إلى بكين[fix]
[ko:]네 날개 밑에는  해방된 농노들의 편지가 있으니,[fix]
[ru:]с посланием от освобожденных рабов под крылом.
[zh:]翻身的农奴想念恩人毛主席
[en:]passing on love to Chairman Mao in Peking.
[fre:]à notre bien-aimé Président Mao.[fix]
[ar:]...العبيد المحررين مشتاقين[fix]
[ko:]베이징에 계신 마오 주석에게 우리의 사랑을 전해다오.[fix]
[ru:]отправленном любимому Председателю Мао в Пекин.
[zh:]爸爸走了
[en:]After Dad left
[fre:]Après que Papa fut parti,
[ar:]، بعد أن رحل أبي[fix]
[ru:]После отъезда отца
[zh:]我获得了空前的自由
[en:]I was freer than I'd ever been.
[fre:]j'étais vraiment fier.
[ar:]كنت حراً أكثر من أي وقت مضى[fix]
[ko:]아버지가 떠난 후,[fix] 나는 전보다 더 자유로워졌다.[fix]
[ru:]Я получил полную свободу.
[zh:]我特别羡慕父母都在 外地工作的那些孩子们
[en:]I always envied kids whose parents worked out of town.
[fre:]J'ai toujours envié les gamins dont les parents travaillent hors de la ville.
[ar:]كنت دائما أحسد الأطفال الذين يعمل آبائهم خارج المدينة[fix]
[ko:]나는 늘, 부모가 마을 밖에서 일하고 있는  아이들을 부러워했었다.[fix]
[ru:]Я всегда завидовал детям, родители которых работали за городом.
[zh:]如今我终于加入了他们的行列
[en:]Now I was one of them.
[fre:]Maintenant, j'étais un des leurs.
[ar:]واليوم، صرتُ أخيرا واحد منهم[fix]
[ko:]이제 나도 그런 아이들 중의 하나가 됐다.[fix]
[ru:]Теперь я стал одним из них.
[zh:]咱们打赌
[en:]Let's bet that
[fre:]On parie pour voir qui arrive
[ru:]Давай поспорим,
[zh:]看谁把书包扔得最高
[en:]who can toss their bag the highest.
[fre:]à lancer son sac le plus haut ?
[ar:]لنتراهن لنرى من يرمي حقيبته أعلى[fix]
[ru:]кто бросит сумку выше всех.
[zh:]赌什么呢？
[en:]What's the wager?
[fre:]C'est quoi le pari ?
[ar:]ما الرهان؟
[ko:]누가 자기 가방을[fix] 가장 높이 올릴 수 있는지 내기 하자.[fix] 뭘 걸까?[fix]
[ru:]На что спорим?
[zh:]冰棍
[en:]Icepops?
[fre:]Un bonbon ?
[ar:]!مثلجات - !بنكهة الزبدة -[fix]
[ko:]아이스캔디?[fix]
[ru:]Холодная шипучка?
[zh:]奶油的
[en:]Butter flavor.
[fre:]Au beurre.
[ru:]Персиковая.
[zh:]两个
[en:]Two.
[fre:]Deux.
[ar:]!الاثنان[fix] حسناً، لا مشكلة[fix]
[ru:]Две бутылки
[zh:]好好 没问题
[en:]Ok.
[fre:]OK.
[ar:]!أنا أول، أنا أول[fix]
[ru:]Хорошо.
[zh:]我先来我先来
[en:]let me go first!
[fre:]À moi en premier !
[ru:]Чур я первый!
[zh:]别急别急
[en:]No.
[fre:]Non.
[ar:]اهدأوا، اهدأوا[fix]
[ko:]버터맛.[fix] 두 개.[fix] 좋아.[fix] 내가 맨 먼저 할게![fix]
[ru:]Нет.
[zh:]从大蚂蚁这儿开始
[en:]We'll start with Big Ant.
[fre:]On commence par Big Ant.
[ar:](سنبدأ بـ(النملة الكبيرة - !حسنا -[fix]
[ru:]Начнем с Большого Муравья.
[zh:]咱们得把书包扔得跟楼那么高
[en:]See if you can get is as high as the roof.
[fre:]Essaye de l'envoyer aussi haut que le toit.
[ar:]يجب أن نرمي حقائبنا عاليا كالبيوت، حسنا؟[fix]
[ko:]안 돼.[fix] 왕개미(Big Ant)부터 하자.[fix] 지붕만큼 높이 올릴 수 있는지 보자.[fix]
[ru:]Посмотрим, добросит ли он хотя бы до крыши.
[zh:]行行
[en:]Ok,
[fre:]OK,
[ru:]Ладно.
[zh:]蚂蚁先来
[en:]go for it Big Ant.
[fre:]vas-y Big Ant.
[ar:]!حسنا، هيا أيها النملة الكبيرة[fix]
[ru:]Пусть будет Большой Муравей.
[zh:]一二三
[en:]1, 2, 3
[fre:]1, 2, 3...
[ar:]!واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة[fix]
[ko:]좋아.[fix] 왕개미, 해봐.[fix] 1, 2, 3[fix]
[ru:]Раз, два, три
[zh:]哎呀
[en:]No good.[fix]
[fre:]Nul.
[ar:]!لا يمكن
[ru:]Фигня![fix]
[zh:]该你了
[en:]Your turn Liu Sitian.
[fre:]À toi Liu Sitian.
[ar:](دورك، (ليو سيان
[ko:]에이... 별로네.[fix] 루시챤, 네 차례야.[fix]
[ru:]Теперь ты, Лю Сытиань
[zh:]一二三
[en:]1, 2, 3
[fre:]1, 2, 3...
[ar:]!واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة[fix]
[ko:]1, 2, 3[fix]
[ru:]Раз, два, три
[zh:]不行
[en:]No good, no good!
[fre:]Pas bon, pas bon !
[ar:]غير جيدة[fix] (دورك، (يانغ غاو[fix]
[ko:]별로야, 별로![fix]
[ru:]Фигня, фигня!
[zh:]羊搞，该你了
[en:]Yang Gao, your turn.[fix]
[fre:]Yang Gao, à ton tour.
[ru:]Ян Гао, твоя очередь![fix]
[zh:]一二三
[en:]1, 2, 3
[fre:]1, 2, 3...
[ar:]!واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة[fix]
[ko:]양가오, 네 차례.[fix] 1, 2, 3[fix]
[ru:]Раз, два, три
[zh:]你们玩意儿哎哟
[en:]Oh, look at that stupid thing!
[fre:]Oh, t'es vraiment nul !
[ar:]كلكم سيئون[fix]
[ru:]Блин, посмотрите на этого дурака.
[zh:]该你了
[en:]Your turn, Monkey.
[fre:]À toi, Monkey.
[ar:]حسنا، دورك يا قرد
[ko:]에고, 바보 같아![fix] 원숭이, 네 차례야.[fix]
[ru:]Теперь Обезьяна.
[zh:]一二三
[en:]1, 2, 3
[fre:]1, 2, 3...
[ar:]!واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة[fix]
[ko:]1, 2, 3[fix]
[ru:]Раз, два, три
[zh:]我操！
[ar:]!اللعنة
[zh:]你丫怎么这么懒呀？
[en:]You are such a lazy bastard...
[fre:]T'es vraiment qu'un gros flemmard...
[ar:]يا لك من وغد كسول
[ru:]Ты, блин, ленивая скотина...
[zh:]连书包都懒得拿
[en:]You even hold on to your bag yourself?
[fre:]Tu peux pas te porter ton sac ?
[ar:]!لا تستطيع حتى حمل حقيبتك بنفسك
[ko:]너 아주 게으른 놈이구나...[fix]
[ru:]уже сумку сам поймать не можешь?
[zh:]赶紧走
[en:]Come on!
[fre:]Allez !
[ar:]اسرع[fix]
[ru:]Поехали!
[zh:]大蚂蚁大蚂蚁
[en:]Big Ant! Big Ant!
[fre:]Big Ant ! Big Ant !
[ar:]!النملة الكبيرة - !النملة الكبيرة -
[ko:]아직도 가방만 붙잡고 있을거야?[fix] 간다![fix] 왕개미! 왕개미![fix]
[ru:]Большой Муравей! Большой Муравей!
[zh:]小学就这么毕业了
[en:]And so I graduated from primary school.
[fre:]Une fois le collège terminé,
[ar:]، وبعد تخرجي من المدرسة الابتدائية
[ko:]그렇게 나는 초등학교를 졸업했다.[fix]
[ru:]После начальной школы,
[zh:]大家升入了不同的中学
[en:]We were all sent to different high schools.
[fre:]on a tous été envoyés dans des lycées différents.
[ar:]اُرسلنا جميعا لمدارس ثانوية مختلفة[fix]
[ru:]Нас всех отправили в разные средние школы.
[zh:]这是校方为了 拆散象我们这样的小集体
[en:]This was a policy of the school...
[fre:]Il y avait une police à l'école
[ko:]우리 모두는 서로 다른 상급학교로  진학하게 되었다.[fix] 이것은 우리 작은 갱단을 떼어놓기 위해,[fix]
[ru:]Это было школьной политикой...
[zh:]而专门采取的措施
[en:]aimed at breaking up our little gangs.
[fre:]chargée de réprimer les petits gangs.
[ar:]كان هذا إجراء اعتمدته المدرسة بهدف تفريق عصابتنا الصغيرة[fix]
[ko:]학교에서 정한 방침이었다.[fix]
[ru:]Нацеленной на разбивание небольших банд.
[zh:]可是没过几年
[en:]But several years later...
[fre:]Mais quelques années plus tard,
[ar:]، ولكن بعد بضع سنوات
[ru:]Но несколько лет спустя...
[zh:]我们便随大人搬到了 东城的一个军队家属院
[en:]Our families all moved to the same army compound...
[fre:]nos familles ont toutes emménagé dans le même district,
[ar:]انتقلت كل عائلاتنا لنفس المجمع العسكري على الجانب الشرقي من المدينة[fix]
[ko:]몇 년이 지난 후...[fix] 우리는 모두 같이  부대 주둔지로 이사를 했다...[fix]
[ru:]наши семьи оказались в одном армейском соединении
[zh:]本来分开了的好哥们儿
[en:]and I was reunited with my mates.
[fre:]et j'ai retrouvé tous mes compagnons.
[ar:]والعصابة التي تفرقت لُم شملهم مرة أخرى[fix]
[ko:]그래서 나는 내 친구들과 다시 뭉쳤다.[fix]
[ru:]и я снова встретился со своими друзьями.
[zh:]又相聚了
[zh:]古伦木
[en:]Gooloomoo!
[fre:]Gooloomoo !
[ar:]!غلومو
[ru:]Гулуму![fix]
[zh:]古伦木
[en:]Gooloomoo!
[fre:]Gooloomoo !
[ar:]!اوبا[fix]
[zh:]古伦木欧巴
[en:]Oo-ba![fix]
[fre:]Oo-ba !
[ru:]Оо-ба![fix]
[zh:]古伦木
[en:]Gooloomoo![fix]
[fre:]Gooloomoo !
[ar:]!غلومو
[ko:]구루무![fix] 구루무![fix]
[ru:]Гулуму![fix]
[zh:]欧巴
[en:]Oo-ba!
[fre:]Oo-ba !
[ar:]!اوبا قلتُ: لا تحضري فتياناً للبيت[fix]
[ko:]오-바![fix] 구루무![fix] 오-바![fix]
[ru:]Оо-ба!
[zh:]七十年代中期
[en:]In the seventies.
[fre:]Dans les années 70,
[ar:]، بمنتصف السبعينات[fix]
[ru:]В семидесятых
[zh:]北京还没有那么多的汽车和豪华饭店
[en:]Beijing didn't have so many cars or luxury hotels.
[fre:]Pékin n'avait pas autant de voitures ou d'hôtels de luxe,[fix]
[ar:]لم يكن ببكين كثير من السيارات أو الفنادق الفاخرة[fix]
[ko:]70년대에,[fix] 베이징에는 차도 많지 않았고,  화려한 호텔도 없었다.[fix]
[ru:]В Пекине не было множества автомобилей и роскошных гостиниц.
[zh:]街上也没有那么多人
[en:]or even that many people on the street.
[fre:]ou même autant de gens dans les rues.
[ar:]أو حتى هذا العدد من الناس في الشوارع
[ru:]Не было даже толп людей на улицах.
[zh:]比我们大几岁的都去了农村和部队
[en:]The older kids were in the villages or army.
[fre:]Les aînés étaient au village ou à l'armée,
[ar:]الفتيان الأكبر سنا منّا ذهبوا جميعهم للريف أو إلى وحدات الجيش[fix]
[ko:]길거리에는 사람조차 많지 않았다.[fix] 나이든 사람들은 대부분  시골이나 군대에 있었다.[fix]
[ru:]Старшие были в деревнях или армии
[zh:]这座城市属于我们
[en:]and the town belonged to us.
[fre:]et la ville nous appartenait.
[ar:]والبلدة كانت لنا[fix]
[ko:]그래서 도회지에는  우리 같은 아이들만 있었다.[fix]
[ru:]и город принадлежал нам.
[zh:]上课 起立
[en:]Time for class. Attention!
[fre:]Votre attention !
[ar:]وقت الحصة - !انتباه -[fix]
[ko:]- 수업 시작. - 차렷![fix]
[ru:]Внимание, начинаем урок.
[zh:]同学们好
[en:]Hello students![fix]
[fre:]Bonjours les élèves !
[ar:]مرحبا يا طلاب
[ru:]Здравствуйте, товарищи школьники![fix]
[zh:]老师好
[en:]Hello teacher!
[fre:]Bonjour Professeur !
[ar:]مرحبا يا معلم[fix]
[ko:]안녕, 제군들![fix] 선생님, 안녕하세요![fix]
[ru:]Здравствуйте, товарищ учитель!
[zh:]不要笑
[en:]Don't laugh.
[fre:]Ne riez pas.
[ar:]بلا ضحك[fix]
[ko:]웃지 마라.[fix]
[ru:]Прекратите смех.
[zh:]很简单的一个物理现象
[en:]It's a simple principle of physics.
[fre:]C'est dû à un principe de physique très simple.
[ar:]هذه مجرد حالة فيزيائية بسيطة[fix]
[ru:]Это обычное физическое явление.
[zh:]坐下
[en:]Sit down.
[fre:]Assis.
[ar:]اجلسوا[fix]
[ko:]이건 단지 물리학의 원리일 뿐이야.[fix] 앉아.[fix]
[ru:]Садитесь.
[zh:]谁让你离开座位的
[en:]Who said you could get up?
[fre:]Qui a dit que tu pouvais te relever ?
[ar:]من سمح لك بالقيام؟
[ru:]Кто тебе разрешил вставать?
[zh:]无组织无纪律 回去
[en:]Take your seat!
[fre:]Va t'asseoir !
[ar:].جانح عنيد !اجلس[fix]
[ko:]누가 너한테 가져오라고 했어?[fix] 자리에 앉아![fix]
[ru:]Сядь!
[zh:]我让你把帽子给我放在这儿再回去懂吗
[en:]I mean, first put that hat back and take your seat.
[fre:]Je veux dire, d'abord ramène ce chapeau et va t'asseoir.
[ar:]أولا ضع القبعة هنا لي وبعد ذلك اجلس مكانك، فهمت؟[fix]
[ko:]내 모자는 제자리에 놓고, 자리에 돌아가 앉으란 말이야.[fix]
[ru:]Я имел в виду - положи шляпу и сядь.
[zh:]懂 胡老师
[en:]Yes, Mr. Hu.
[fre:]Oui, M. Hu.
[ar:](فهمت، معلم (هوو
[ko:]예, 후 선생님.[fix]
[ru:]Да, товарищ Ху.
[zh:]谁是班长？
[en:]Who's class monitor?
[fre:]Qui est le responsable de la classe ?
[ar:]من عريف الفصل؟
[ko:]반장은 누구냐?[fix]
[ru:]Кто староста класса?
[zh:]她
[en:]She is.
[fre:]C'est elle.
[ar:]هي
[ru:]Она!
[zh:]她是班长 给我回来
[en:]Get back here.
[fre:]Reviens ici !
[ar:]!ارجع مكانك[fix]
[ko:]얘에요.[fix] 자리로 돌아와.[fix]
[ru:]Вернись на место!
[zh:]谁问你啦？
[en:]Who's asking you?
[fre:]Qui t'a demandé de faire ça ?
[ar:]من سألك؟[fix]
[ko:]누가 너한테 물어봤어?[fix]
[ru:]Тебя кто-нибудь спрашивал?
[zh:]我问谁是班长的目的
[en:]I am asking class monitor to identify herself.
[fre:]Je demande ça à la responsable pour savoir qui c'est.[fix]
[ar:]الهدف من السؤال عن عريف الفصل[fix]
[ru:]Пусть староста сама откликается.
[zh:]是要让她自己站起来
[ar:]لكي يعرف العريف عن نفسه[fix]
[ko:]누군지 확인하려고 반장을 물어본거야.[fix]
[zh:]下课之后 把这堆煤球 都拖到外面去
[en:]After class, get rid of these coals.
[fre:]Après la classe, tu m'enlèveras ce charbon.
[ar:]بعد الحصة، خذوا هذا الفحم للخارج وتخلصوا منه[fix]
[ko:]수업 끝나고, 저 석탄 치워.[fix]
[ru:]После урока уберите этот уголь.
[zh:]大家把书翻到第35页
[en:]Open your books to page 35.
[fre:]Ouvrez vos livres page 35.
[ar:]افتحوا كتبكم صفحة 35
[ko:]책 35쪽 펴라.[fix]
[ru:]Откройте книги на странице 35.
[zh:]咱们讲讲中俄尼布楚条约
[en:]Let's look at the Sino-Russion Treaty of Nerchinsk.
[fre:]Regardez le Traité Sino-Russe de Nerchinsk.
[ar:]سنناقش اليوم معاهدة نيرتشينسك الصينية الروسية[fix]
[ko:]중국과 러시아 간에 체결한 네르친스크 조약에 대해 알아보자.[fix]
[ru:]Изучаем китайско-русский Нерчинский договор.
[zh:]中
[en:]"Sino"
[fre:]"Sino"
[ar:]"الصينية"[fix]
[ru:]"Китайско"
[zh:]清政府
[en:]refers to the Qing dynasty.
[fre:]se réfère à la dynastie Qing.
[ar:]يعني حكومة تشينغ
[ko:]"중국"[fix] 청왕조를 가리킨다.[fix]
[ru:]имеется в виду династия Цин.
[zh:]俄
[en:]"Russian"
[fre:]"Russe"
[ar:]"الروسية"[fix]
[ru:]"русский"
[zh:]沙俄政府
[en:]to czarist Russia.
[fre:]à la Russie tsariste.
[ar:]يعني روسيا القيصرية
[ko:]"러시아"[fix] 제정 러시아를 말한다.[fix]
[ru:]- царская Россия.
[zh:]啊 尼布楚
[en:]But Nerchinsk,
[fre:]Mais "Nerchinsk",
[ar:]"أما "نيرتشينسك[fix]
[ko:]그럼 네르친스크는,[fix]
[ru:]Но Нерчинский...
[zh:]何为尼布楚
[en:]what's Nerchinsk?
[fre:]qu'est-ce que Nerchinsk ?
[ar:]ما هي نيرتشينسك؟
[ko:]네르친스크는 뭐냐?[fix]
[ru:]что такое Нерчинск?
[zh:]贝加尔湖以东的地区
[en:]It's the region east of the Baykal Lake.
[fre:]C'est la région à l'Est du lac Baïkal.
[ar:]إنها المنطقة الشرقية من بحيرة بايكال[fix]
[ko:]그곳은 바이칼호의 동쪽에 있는 지역이다.[fix]
[ru:]Это город к востоку от озера Байкал.
[zh:]这是谁干的 谁干的
[en:]Who did this?
[fre:]Qui a fait ça ?
[ar:]من فعل هذا؟ من فعل هذا؟[fix]
[ko:]누가 그랬어?[fix]
[ru:]Кто это сделал?!
[zh:]这是什么意思
[en:]What's the meaning of this, huh?
[fre:]Ça veut dire quoi ça, hein ?
[ar:]ما المعنى من هذا؟[fix]
[ru:]Вы что творите?!
[zh:]谁
[en:]Who?
[fre:]Qui ?
[ar:]من؟
[ru:]Кто это сделал?
[zh:]不是我 不是我 你瞧我手干净的
[en:]It wasn't me. My hands are clean.
[fre:]C'est pas moi. Mes mains sont propres.
[ar:]ليس أنا انظر، يداي نظيفتان[fix]
[ko:]이게 도대체 뭐하는 짓이야?[fix] 누구야?[fix] 저 아니에요.  제 손 깨끗하잖아요.[fix]
[ru:]Это не я! Мои руки чистые.
[zh:]都把手伸出来
[en:]Hold up your hands, everyone.
[fre:]Levez tous les mains !
[ar:]الكل يرفع يديه[fix]
[ko:]모두, 손 올려.[fix]
[ru:]Все подняли руки.
[zh:]胡老师
[en:]Mr. Hu.
[fre:]M. Hu.
[ar:]معلم (هوو)؟
[ru:]Товарищ Ху.
[zh:]你说
[fre:]Parle !
[zh:]算了不说了
[en:]Speak up.[fix] Never mind.
[fre:]Non, rien.
[ar:]!تكلم - لا يهم -[fix]
[ko:]후 선생님.[fix] 말해봐.[fix] 아무 것도 아니에요.[fix]
[ru:]Говори.[fix] Да я просто...
[zh:]你说
[en:]Speak up,
[fre:]Parle.
[ar:]تكلم
[ru:]Говори, говори...
[zh:]不要怕
[en:]don't be afraid.
[fre:]N'aie pas peur.
[ar:]لا تخف[fix]
[ko:]말해봐라.[fix]
[ru:]Не бойся.
[zh:]我说那个他可能怕那帽子再给风吹走
[en:]Maybe it was to keep the hat from flying off again.
[fre:]C'était peut-être pour éviter que votre chapeau s'envole de nouveau.
[ar:]ربما أن الفاعل أراد منع القبعة من الطيران مجدداً[fix]
[ko:]무서워 말고.[fix] 아마 모자가 다시 날라가지  않도록 해놓은 것 같습니다.[fix]
[ru:]Может, это сделали, чтобы шляпа больше не улетала?
[zh:]我说这动机是好的
[en:]It was well-intentioned. So don't be angry.
[fre:]C'était bien intentionné. Alors ne vous énervez pas.
[ar:]لذا فنيته طيبة[fix]
[ko:]선의로 그런 것이니, 그렇게 화내지 마세요.[fix]
[ru:]Из самых добрых побуждений. Не сердитесь
[zh:]我问的你是谁
[en:]I'm asking who did it![fix]
[fre:]J'ai demandé qui a fait ça !
[ar:]!أنا اسأل من فعلها
[ru:]Я спрашиваю - кто это сделал?[fix]
[zh:]那我可不知道
[en:]Well I don't know.
[fre:]Ben, je ne sais pas.
[ar:]أوه، لا أعرف[fix]
[ko:]누가 했나고 물었어![fix] 그건 모릅니다.[fix]
[ru:]А я не знаю кто.
[zh:]坐下
[en:]Sit down.
[fre:]Assis !
[ar:]اجلس
[ru:]Садись.
[zh:]老师你千万别生气啊
[en:]Don't be angry. Mr. Hu.
[fre:]Ne vous énervez pas M. Hu.
[ar:]لا تغضب يا معلم، حسنا؟ - !لا تغضب يا معلم -[fix]
[ko:]앉아.[fix] 화내지 마세요, 후 선생님.[fix]
[ru:]Не сердитесь, товарищ Ху.
[zh:]这个课咱们不上了
[en:]Class is adjourned.
[fre:]Le cours est annulé.
[ar:]لا حصة اليوم
[ko:]수업은 그만한다.[fix]
[ru:]Урок не будет продолжен до тех пор...
[zh:]我 我跟你说 我要查清楚 我得查清楚
[en:]I shall get to that bottom of this!
[fre:]Je trouverai le responsable de tout ça !
[ar:]!أؤكد لكم أني سأكتشف ذلك[fix]
[ko:]누구짓인지 끝까지 알아내고 말거야![fix]
[ru:]пока я не узнаю, кто это сделал.
[zh:]胡老师 胡老师
[en:]Mr. Hu, Mr. Hu!
[fre:]M. Hu ! M. Hu !
[ar:]!(معلم (هوو)! معلم (هوو[fix]
[ko:]후 선생님, 후 선생님![fix]
[ru:]Товарищ Ху, товарищ Ху!
[zh:]把脚下鞋给我捡出来
[en:]Would you mind tossing me my shoe?
[fre:]Pourriez-vous me donner ma chaussure ?
[ar:]أيمكنك رمي حذائي؟[fix]
[ko:]내 신발 좀 던져 주세요.[fix]
[ru:]Дайте, пожалуйста, мой тапочек.
[zh:]你是不是上厕所也要老师给你擦屁股啊
[en:]Sure, and I'll wipe your ass in the toilet too!
[fre:]Bien sûr, et tu veux aussi que je te torche le cul ?
[ar:]بالتأكيد، أتريدني أيضا أن أمسح مؤخرتك بالحمام؟[fix]
[ko:]좋아, 화장실로 끌로가서  네 놈 엉덩이를 때려주겠다![fix]
[ru:]Конечно подам! И задницу в туалете тебе вытру.
[zh:]给你鞋 我给你穿上得了
[en:]Shall I help you put it on as well?
[fre:]Tu veux pas non plus que je t'aide à la mettre ?
[ar:]أتحتاج للمساعدة بارتداء الحذاء أيضا؟[fix]
[ko:]그래도 신발을 달라고 할거냐?[fix]
[ru:]А потом штаны надену.
[zh:]那倒不用
[en:]NO,
[ru:]Нет!
[zh:]你给我扔出来就行了
[en:]Just toss it out here, please.
[fre:]Non. Si vous pouviez juste me la rendre, s'il vous plaît.[fix]
[ar:]لا داعي لذلك فقط ارمه هنا، حسنا؟[fix]
[ru:]Просто бросьте его. Ну, пожалуйста.
[zh:]滚
[en:]Get out of here!
[fre:]Dégage de là !
[ar:]!اخرج
[ko:]안 돼.[fix] 이리로 신발 좀 주세요, 제발.[fix] 여기서 나가![fix]
[ru:]Убирайся отсюда!
[zh:]你这些害群之马
[en:]You rotten apple![fix]
[ru:]Засранец![fix]
[zh:]不学无术
[fre:]Espèce de fruit pourri ![fix]
[ar:]هذا الأحمق اللعين !الجاهل عديم الفائدة[fix]
[zh:]焦师傅 焦师傅
[en:]Mr. Jiao!
[fre:]M. Jiao !
[ar:]!(سيد (جياو)! سيد (جياو
[ko:]썩어빠진 놈![fix] 지아오씨![fix]
[ru:]Товарищ Цзяо!
[zh:]哪位同学啊
[en:]Someone[fix]
[fre:]Que quelqu'un aille chercher
[ar:]...أيوجد طالب هنا[fix]
[ru:]Кто-нибудь,[fix]
[zh:]赶紧去把咱们工宣队的焦师傅 给请到教室这儿来
[en:]get Mr. Jiao of the Workers Propaganda Team here right now!
[fre:]M. Jiao de l'Équipe de Propagande des Travailleurs !
[ar:](يستطيع الذهاب لإحضار السيد (جياو من (فريق دعاية العمال)؟[fix]
[ko:]누구[fix] 노동자 선전팀의 지아오씨를  이곳으로 당장 모셔와![fix]
[ru:]немедленно позовите сюда товарища Цзяо из "группы пропаганды среди рабочих".
[zh:]嘿 姓胡的
[en:]Jeez, Hu.
[fre:]Du calme, Hu !
[ar:]يا (هوو)، أأنت وقح لدرجة عدم المبالاة بحفظ كرامتك؟[fix]
[ru:]Ладно, Ху.
[zh:]你别给脸不要脸
[en:]give me a bit of face, OK?[fix]
[fre:]Fous-moi un peu la paix !
[ru:]Хочешь, что мне досталось по морде, да?[fix]
[zh:]求你这么点儿事你都不给我办
[en:]I'm not asking for much.
[fre:]Je demande pas grand-chose.
[ar:]ترفض أن تقدم لي هذه الخدمة الصغيرة حتى؟ !حسنا، سترى[fix]
[ko:]이런... 후 선생님.[fix] 체면 좀 세워주세요, 예?[fix] 대단한걸 부탁한 것도 아니잖아요.[fix]
[ru:]Я не многого просил.
[zh:]行 你等着
[en:]OK, just you wait![fix]
[fre:]Vous allez voir !
[ru:]Ладно, теперь жди.[fix]
[zh:]嘿 笑话
[en:]Wait for what?[fix]
[fre:]Voir quoi ?
[ar:]!أنت تمزح
[ru:]Чего "жди"?[fix]
[zh:]我等什么啊
[en:]What a joke?
[fre:]C'est une blague ?
[ar:]ماذا سأرى؟[fix]
[ko:]좋아요, 두고보세요![fix] 뭘 두고 봐?[fix] 지금 농담하냐?[fix]
[ru:]Ты шутишь?
[zh:]你还能把我怎么样
[en:]What are you going to do?
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que tu vas faire ?
[ar:]ماذا يمكنك فعله بي؟
[ru:]Что ты собираешься сделать?
[zh:]你不要来这套恐吓讹诈
[en:]don't threaten me.
[fre:]On ne me parle pas comme ça !
[ar:]لا تأتي هنا وتهددني بوعيدك التافه
[ru:]Не угрожай мне.
[zh:]行 行 你等着 我还不要了
[en:]Fine. I don't need that stupid show.
[fre:]Très bien. Je n'ai pas besoin de cette stupide chaussure.
[ar:]حسنا، سترى لا أريد الحذاء
[ko:]뭘 어쩌겠다는거야?[fix] 협박하지 마.[fix] 좋아요. 이제 그만 하세요.[fix]
[ru:]Да ладно, Ху. Некогда мне тут с тобой базарить.
[zh:]你回来 你回来
[en:]come back here!
[fre:]Reviens ici !
[ar:]!ارجع! تعال[fix]
[ru:]А ну-ка вернись!
[zh:]难道你会叫人打我吗
[en:]Going to have someone beat me?
[fre:]Tu es parti chercher quelqu'un pour me frapper ?
[ar:]ماذا، ستأتي بأحد يضربني؟[fix]
[ru:]Ты собираешься избить меня?
[zh:]你会扎我的车胎不成吗
[en:]Puncture my bicycle tires? Stab me in the back?
[fre:]Crever les pneus de ma bicyclette ? Me planter un couteau dans le dos ?
[ar:]تجد دراجتي وتثقب عجلاتها؟  هاه؟[fix]
[ko:]이리로 들어와![fix] 나를 패라고, 사람이라도 보낼래?[fix] 내 자전거 타이어에 구멍을 뚫을거야?  내 등을 찌를거야?[fix]
[ru:]Проколоть мне шины на велосипеде? Пырнуть ножом сзади?
[zh:]我没人希罕你这个破鞋
[en:]No one wants your filthy shoe.
[fre:]Personne ne veut ta chaussure dégueulasse.
[ar:]لا أحد يريد حذائك القذر
[ko:]니 더러운 신발은 아무에게도 쓸모가 없어.[fix]
[ru:]Да кому нужен твой грязный тапок?
[zh:]敬礼 齐步走
[en:]Attention! March in time!
[fre:]Attention ! En marche !
[ar:]!انتباه! إلى الأمام، سر[fix]
[ko:]차렷! 앞으로~ 가![fix]
[ru:]Смирно! К торжественному маршу!
[zh:]请首长放心 我们保证完成任务
[en:]Our leaders should rest assured, we will complete our mission.
[fre:]Que nos leaders se rassurent, nous accomplirons notre mission.
[ar:]ليطمئن قادتنا نحن نضمن إتمام مهمتنا[fix]
[ko:]임무를 완수할 것이니, 지도자 동지들은 안심하십시오.[fix]
[ru:]Наши лидеры могут быть уверены - мы выполним свою задачу!
[zh:]851 851 我是延安 我是延安
[en:]8-5-1, 8-5-1, this is Yan'an, this is Yan'an.[fix]
[fre:]8-5-1, 8-5-1, ici Yan'an, ici Yan'an.
[ar:]8-5-1، 8-5-1 (معك (يانان)، معك (يانان[fix]
[ru:]851, 851, это Яньань, это Яньань.[fix]
[zh:]向我开炮 向我开炮
[en:]Fire in my direction! Fire in my direction!
[fre:]Je suis sous les feux ! Je suis sous les feux !
[ar:]!أطلق النار باتجاهي !أطلق النار باتجاهي[fix]
[ko:]8-5-1, 8-5-1, 여기는 양안, 여기는 양안.[fix] 지시한 방향으로 쏴라! 지시한 방향으로 쏴라![fix]
[ru:]Вызываю огонь на себя, вызываю огонь на себя!
[zh:]我迷恋上了钥匙
[en:]I loved keys.
[fre:]J'ai toujours aimé les clés.
[ar:]كنت مجنوناً بالمفاتيح[fix]
[ru:]Я любил ключи.
[zh:]并开始制造它们
[en:]I learned how to make them.
[fre:]J'ai appris à les fabriquer.
[ar:]وبدأت حتى بصنعها بنفسي[fix]
[ko:]나는 열쇠를 좋아했다.[fix] 나는 열쇠 만드는 법을 익혔다.[fix]
[ru:]И узнал, как их делать.
[zh:]先是把自己家的各种锁一一打开
[en:]I practiced on all the locks at home.
[fre:]Je m'entraînais sur toutes les serrures de la maison,
[ar:]في البداية تدربت على جميع الأقفال في المنزل[fix]
[ko:]그리고 집에 있는 모든 자물쇠를  가지고 연습했다.[fix]
[ru:]Я напрактиковался на всех замках дома.
[zh:]偷看大人的秘密
[en:]peering into my parents' secrets.
[fre:]fouillant dans les affaires de mes parents.
[ar:].متجسسا على أسرار والداي
[ru:]Подсмотрел все родительские секреты.
[zh:]后来就发展到未经邀请就去开别人家的锁
[en:]Then I began going into other people's homes.
[fre:]Ensuite, j'allais chez les autres.
[ar:]ثم بدأت اقتحام منازل الناس الآخرين[fix]
[ko:]부모님의 비밀을 엿보기 위해.[fix] 그런 다음 나는  다른 사람들 집에도 들어갔다.[fix]
[ru:]Затем начал проникать в чужие дома.
[zh:]每当锁舌铛的一声跳开
[en:]The "click" of a lock popping open.
[fre:]Le "click" d'une serrure qui s'ouvre
[ar:]، بكل مرة أسمع صوت فتح القفل[fix]
[ru:]Щелчок, с которым замок открывался
[zh:]我便陷入无限的欣喜之中
[en:]propelled me into a realm of sheer bliss.
[fre:]m'a toujours procuré énormément de bonheur.
[ar:]أدخل في عالم من النعيم المطلق
[ko:]자물쇠가 열릴 때 나는 "찰칵"하는 소리는[fix] 나를 아주 행복하게 만들었다.[fix]
[ru:]отправлял меня в царство полного счастья.
[zh:]这种感觉
[en:]This feeling
[fre:]Cette impression...
[ar:]...هذا الشعور[fix]
[ru:]Это чувство...
[zh:]这种感觉只有二战中攻克柏林的 苏联红军才能体会得到
[en:]This feeling, only the Soviet army attacking Berlin in WWII could have felt what I feel.
[fre:]Cette impression, seule l'armée soviétique attaquant Berlin,  pendant la seconde Guerre Mondiale, a pu la ressentir.[fix]
[ar:]هذا الشعور كان لا يمكن أن يعرفه أحد إلا السوفييت أثناء مهاجمة برلين في الحرب العالمية الثانية[fix]
[ko:]이 기분,[fix] 2차세계대전에서 베를린을 공격했던 소련만이 내가 느낀 이 기분을 알 수 있을것이다.[fix]
[ru:]Я чувствовал себя, как Советская армия при взятии Берлина во Второй мировой.
[zh:]不瞒你说
[en:]I can't hid it.
[fre:]Je ne peux pas le nier,
[ar:]، لأقول الحقيقة[fix]
[ru:]Я не мог скрывать его.
[zh:]我的才华是来自爸爸的遗传
[en:]I got my talent from my father.
[fre:]j'ai reçu ce talent de mon père.
[ar:]حصلت على موهبتي من أبي[fix]
[ko:]나는 숨길 수 없다.[fix] 내 재능은 나의 아버지에게서 물려받은 것이다.[fix]
[ru:]Я унаследовал свой талант от отца.
[zh:]抗美援朝战争中
[en:]In the Korean War.
[fre:]Pendant la guerre de Corée,
[ar:]...خلال الحرب الكورية[fix]
[ru:]В Корейской войне
[zh:]他曾无师自通地撤除了无数 美国兵投下的定时炸弹上的引信
[en:]he worked out how to countless American bombs.
[fre:]il travaillait comme démineur pour désamorcer les bombes américaines.[fix]
[ar:]تعلّم بنفسه كيفية نزع فتيل قنابل أمريكية لا تحصى[fix]
[ko:]한국 전쟁에서,[fix] 아버지는 미국의 수많은  폭탄 세례하에서 복무했다.[fix]
[ru:]он занимался обезвреживанием бесчисленных американских бомб.
[zh:]很多人为此壮烈牺牲了
[en:]Lots of people lost their lives that way.
[fre:]Beaucoup de personnes sont mortes en faisant ça,
[ar:]الكثير ضحوا بشجاعة بأنفسهم بالقيام بذلك[fix]
[ru:]Много людей погибло на этой работе
[zh:]可他却安然无恙
[en:]but he came out of it without a scratch...
[fre:]mais il en est revenu sans une égratignure,
[ar:]أما هو فخرج منها سالما تماما
[ko:]많은 사람들이 그 와중에 목숨을 잃었다.[fix]
[ru:]но он вернулся оттуда без единой царапины
[zh:]以至于妈妈一直怀疑他在朝鲜那几年
[en:]which is why Mom suspects that all his time in Korea
[fre:]ce qui fait que maman pense que pendant tout ce temps
[ar:]ولهذا شكّت أمي ...أن كل تلك السنوات بوجوده في كوريا[fix]
[ko:]그러나 아버지는 긁힌 상처하나 없이 돌아왔다.[fix] 그것 때문에 어머니는, 아버지가  한국 전쟁 기간 내내,[fix]
[ru:]из-за чего мама до сих пор подозревает, что все время в Корее
[zh:]一直是躲在山洞里
[en:]was spent hiding out in the mountains.
[fre:]il restait caché dans les montagnes.
[ar:]كان يقضيها مختبئا في الجبال[fix]
[ko:]산속에 숨어지내지 않았을까 의심했다.[fix]
[ru:]он провел, прячась в горах.
[zh:]我进行了仔细的侦察
[en:]I'd check carefully for any cash.
[fre:]Je regardais scrupuleusement s'il n'y avait pas d'argent.[fix]
[ru:]Я тщательно осматривал все в поисках денег
[zh:]发现人们都没什么钱
[ar:]كنت أجري عمليات تفتيش دقيقة وأكتشف أن لا أحد لديه أي أموال[fix]
[ko:]나는 어떤 자물쇠도 조심스럽게 다뤘다.[fix]
[zh:]那些现在被认为是必不可少的 家用电器当时闻所未闻
[en:]The machines everyone demands today were unknown then.
[fre:]Les machines que tout le monde veut aujourd'hui étaient inconnues à l'époque,
[ar:]الآلات التي تعتبر اليوم ضرورية جدا لم تكن تُعرف في ذلك الوقت[fix]
[ko:]오늘날 모든 사람의 필수품이 된  기계 장치들이 당시에는 없었다.[fix]
[ru:]Домашняя техника, без которой не обходятся сейчас, тогда была неизвестна.
[zh:]房里多是单位发的家俱
[en:]Work units provided most of the furniture.
[fre:]les unités de travail fournissant à peu près tout le matériel.
[ar:]معظم الأثاث كان مقدما (من (وحدات العمل[fix] ...يمكنني أن أشهد أن[fix]
[ko:]작업 대상은 대부분 자물쇠들이었다.[fix]
[ru:]то же самое касалось и большей части мебели.
[zh:]我也可以作证
[en:]I can testify that at the time...
[fre:]Je pourrais parier qu'à l'époque,
[ru:]Я могу свидетельствовать, что в то время...[fix]
[zh:]那时候除了一些政治品质可疑的干部
[en:]expect for a very few politically suspect cadres.
[fre:]à part quelques politiciens suspects,
[ar:]باستثناء قليل من ، الكوادر المشبوهة سياسيا[fix]
[ko:]당시에는, 극소수의[fix] 정치적으로 부패한 간부들을 제외하고는,[fix]
[ru:]за исключением очень немногих политически подозрительных кадров
[zh:]贪官污吏凤毛麟角
[en:]there was virtually no corruption at all.
[fre:]il n'y avait quasiment pas de corruption.
[ar:]لم يكن هناك فساد في ذلك الوقت تقريبا[fix]
[ko:]썩은 인간들이 전혀 없었다는 것을  나는 증명할 수 있다.[fix]
[ru:]коррупции в стране не было. Вообще.
[zh:]在我的溜撬生涯中
[en:]In all my exploits...
[fre:]Durant tous mes exploits,
[ar:]...في كل مغامراتي[fix]
[ru:]За все время своих подвигов
[zh:]只见过一台苏联产的老式黑白电视机
[en:]I only spotted one old Soviet black-n-white TV.
[fre:]je n'ai flashé que sur une vielle télé noir et blanc soviétique.
[ar:]لم أرى إلا تلفاز سوفياتي واحد أبيض وأسود قديم[fix]
[ko:]내가 찾은 것이라곤...[fix] 낡고 오래된 흑백 TV뿐이었다.[fix]
[ru:]я обнаружил только один старый советский черно-белый телевизор.
[zh:]我的确想把它搬走
[en:]I considered stealing it,[fix]
[fre:]Je voulais la voler,
[ar:]فكرت فعلا بسرقته
[ru:]Я подумывал спереть его[fix]
[zh:]可是太沉
[en:]but it was too heavy.
[fre:]mais elle était bien trop lourde.
[ar:]لكنه كان ثقيلا جدا[fix]
[ko:]나는 그것을 훔칠까도 생각했지만,[fix] 너무 무거웠다.[fix]
[ru:]но он был слишком тяжелым.
[zh:]我发誓
[en:]Besides,
[fre:]D'ailleurs,
[ru:]Кроме того,
[zh:]我仅仅是开锁
[en:]I vowed I'd only break in,[fix]
[fre:]je m'étais juré de juste pénétrer,
[ar:]، تعهدت أن أقتحم فقط ألا أكون لصاً[fix]
[ru:]я поклялся, что буду только вскрывать замки[fix]
[zh:]不是作贼
[en:]I wouldn't be a thief.
[fre:]pas de voler.
[ko:]게다가,[fix] 나는 다른 사람의 집에 들어갈 뿐,[fix]
[ru:]Я не был вором.
[zh:]玩累了
[en:]When I tired myself out...[fix]
[fre:]Quand j'étais fatigué,
[ru:]Когда я уставал...[fix]
[zh:]就躺在陌生人的床上睡会
[en:]I'd take a nap on the bed.
[fre:]je faisais la sieste sur le lit,
[ar:]عندما أتعب آخذ غفوة على سرير شخص غريب[fix]
[ko:]도둑이 되지는 않기로 맹세했다.[fix]
[ru:]я мог вздремнуть прямо там, на кровати
[zh:]想象着它的主人可能在床上 可能干过的一些事
[en:]imagining what might have happened there.
[fre:]imaginant ce qui avait pu se passer dedans.
[ar:]متخيلاً ما كان قد يفعله هناك[fix]
[ko:]피곤해지면...[fix] 나는 침대에서 잠깐 눈을 부쳤다.[fix] 그곳에서 일어날지도 모르는 일을  상상하면서 말이다.[fix]
[ru:]ничуть не беспокоясь о том, что что-то случится.
[zh:]放心 我绝对有把握不会被人擒住
[en:]I knew I'd never be caught.
[fre:]Je savais que je ne me ferais jamais attraper
[ar:]، لا تقلقوا[fix] لن يُكشف أمري أبدا[fix]
[ko:]나는 절대로 붙잡히지  않으리라는 것을 알았다.[fix]
[ru:]Я знал, что никогда не попадусь
[zh:]那时候人们上班是从来不溜号的
[en:]'cause no one ever snuck out of their office then.
[fre:]parce que personne ne rentre jamais aussi tôt de son bureau.
[ar:].لم يكن أحد يخرج من عمله آنذاك[fix]
[ko:]사무실을 배회하는 사람은  아무도 없었고,[fix]
[ru:]потому что в те времена никто не уходил с работы пораньше.
[zh:]而且因为没丢失任何东西
[en:]And I never stole anything,
[fre:]En plus, je n'ai jamais rien volé,
[ar:]، ولأني لم أكن أسرق شيئا[fix]
[ru:]И я никогда не говорил ничего,
[zh:]也从未引起任何的警惕
[en:]so I didn't arouse any suspicion.
[fre:]donc je ne laissais aucuns soupçons.
[ar:]لم أثر أي شبهات[fix]
[ko:]나는 절대 아무 것도  훔치지 않았기 때문이다.[fix] 그래서 나는 어떤 의심도  불러일으키지 않았다.[fix]
[ru:]что могло бы вызвать подозрения.
[zh:]当然 偶尔也会碰到点小麻烦
[en:]Of course, I ran into trouble from time to time.
[fre:]Bien sûr, de temps en temps, c'était limite.
[ar:]، بطبيعة الحال[fix]  واجهت قليلا من المتاعب من وقت لآخر[fix]
[ko:]물론, 때때로  곤란할 경우도 있었다.[fix]
[ru:]Конечно, время от времени случались неожиданности
[zh:]这点小事 不会让我丧失勇气
[en:]But this didn't dampen my courage.
[fre:]Mais ça ne refroidissait pas mon courage,
[ar:]لكن هذه المناسبات لم تقلل من شجاعتي[fix]
[ko:]그렇지만 그것도  나의 용기를 꺽지는 못했고,[fix]
[ru:]Но это не влияло на мою храбрость
[zh:]只能使我从中体会到更多的刺激
[en:]it only increased the thrill.
[fre:]au contraire, ça m'apportait des émotions.
[ar:]بل زادت التشويق[fix]
[ko:]오직 스릴만을 높일 뿐이었다.[fix]
[ru:]это только усиливало острые ощущения.
[zh:]我向来只开明锁 因为安全
[en:]Usually, I only went for padlocks, they were safe.
[fre:]D'habitude, je ne faisais ça que sur les cadenas, c'était plus sûr.
[ar:]عادة، اختار فقط الأقفال الخارجية لأنها كانت آمنة[fix]
[ko:]대개 나는 맹꽁이 자물쇠가 달린 곳을 들어갔다. 그런 곳은 안전했다.[fix]
[ru:]Обычно я работал с висячими замками, это было безопасней.
[zh:]但我却鬼使神差的打开了一个暗锁
[en:]But that day, something moved me to pick a built-in one.
[fre:]Mais ce jour-là, quelque chose m'a poussé à crocheter cette serrure.
[ar:]لكن في ذلك اليوم، صادف أني اخترت قفلاً مدمجاً[fix]
[ko:]그러나 그날, 나는 무언가에 이끌려 붙박이 문을 열고 들어갔다.[fix]
[ru:]Но в тот день что-то толкнуло меня выбрать врезной замок.
[zh:]我操
[en:]I'll be damned.
[fre:]Ola...
[ar:]!اللعنة[fix]
[ko:]놀랍군.[fix]
[ru:]Оп-па!
[zh:]哇
[ar:]!اللعنة[fix]
[zh:]我操
[en:]I'll be damned.
[fre:]Ola...
[ar:]!اللعنة[fix]
[ko:]놀라워.[fix]
[ru:]Ни фига себе!
[zh:]我操
[en:]I'll be damned.
[fre:]Ola...[fix]
[ar:]!اللعنة[fix]
[ko:]놀라워.[fix]
[ru:]Во дает!
[zh:]姓胡的 你也有今天啦
[en:]Well, Hu, you've fallen low!
[fre:]Hé bien, Hu, tu es tombé bien bas !
[ar:](حسنا، (هوو لقد نلتُ منك الآن[fix]
[ko:]후선생, 당신은 썩었어![fix]
[ru:]Да, Ху, вот это ты обоссался...
[zh:]这是余北蓓
[en:]This is Yu Beipei,
[fre:]Voilà Yu Beipei,
[ar:](هذه (يو بـيـپـي
[ko:]얘는 유베이페이야.[fix]
[ru:]Это Юй Бэйпэй.[fix]
[zh:]外交部大院的
[en:]from the Foreign Ministry compound.
[fre:]du Ministère des Affaires étrangères.
[ar:]من مجمع وزارة الخارجية
[ru:]У нее родители из МИДа.[fix]
[zh:]这是马小军 哥们儿
[en:]This is our mate, Ma Xiaojun.
[fre:]Lui c'est notre ami, Ma Xiaojun.
[ar:](هذا صديقنا، (ماشياو جون
[ko:]외무부 거리에 살아.[fix] 얘는 내 친구, 마샤오준.[fix]
[ru:]Это наш друг, Ма Сяоцзюнь
[zh:]上来吧
[en:]Come on up!
[fre:]Montez donc !
[ar:]تعالوا هنا[fix]
[ko:]올라와![fix]
[ru:]Поднимайтесь!
[zh:]他叫刘忆苦
[en:]That's Liu Yiku.
[fre:]Lui c'est Liu Yiku.
[ar:](هذا (ليو إيكو[fix]
[ru:]Это Лю Еку
[zh:]是刘思甜同父异母的哥哥
[en:]Liu Sitian's stepbrother...
[fre:]Le demi-frère de Liu Sitian...
[ar:]أخو (ليو سيان) من أبيه[fix]
[ru:]Сводный брат Сытианя
[zh:]刚当兵复员回来
[en:]just out of the army.
[fre:]Il revient juste de l'armée.
[ar:]خرج لتوه من الجيش[fix]
[ko:]쟤는 류이쿠이다.[fix] 류시챤의 이복형제인데...[fix]
[ru:]только что вернувшийся из армии
[zh:]人长得精神
[fre:]Il était génial,
[zh:]打起架来手特黑
[en:]He was handsome.[fix] and fought dirty.
[fre:]et se battait bien.
[ar:]كان وسيما وكان يقاتل بغش[fix]
[ko:]군에서 막 제대했다.[fix] 그는 잘 생겼고,[fix] 난폭하게 싸웠다.[fix]
[ru:]Он был красив[fix] и знал грязные приемы в драке.
[zh:]我们都很佩服他 你好
[en:]We thought he was terrific,
[fre:]On le trouvait super,
[ar:]كنا ننظر إليه باعجاب
[ru:]Мы считали его неотразимым
[zh:]因为他经常带些外院的女孩来玩
[en:]'cause he always brought home girls.
[fre:]parce qu'il ramenait toujours des filles à la maison.
[ar:]لأنه كان دائما يحضر الفتيات من أجل الاستمتاع قليلا
[ko:]우리는 그를 대단하다고 여겼다.[fix] 왜냐하면 그는 항상 집으로  여자들을 불러들였기 때문이었다.[fix]
[ru:]потому что он частенько приводил домой девчонок
[zh:]玩了半天了 都在等你
[ar:]كنا نتسكع طوال اليوم بانتظارك أين كنت؟[fix]
[zh:]上哪儿去了
[zh:]那女孩叫余北蓓
[en:]She was called Yu Beipei.
[fre:]Elle s'appelait Yu Beipei.
[ar:](هذه الفتاة اسمها (يو بـيـپـي
[ko:]그녀는 '유베이페이'로 불렸다.[fix]
[ru:]Ее звали Юй Бэйпэй.
[zh:]蓓蕾的蓓
[en:]That "pei" is usually pronounced "bei".
[fre:]Ce "pei" se prononce normalement "bei",
[ar:]الـ پـي عادةً تنطق بي
[ru:]Это "пэй" обычно произносится как "бэй".
[zh:]可我们一直叫她余北蓓(PEI)
[en:]But we called her Yu Beipei...
[fre:]mais nous on l'appelait Yu Beipei,
[ar:](ولكن كنا دائما نناديها (يو بيـپـي
[ko:]"페이"는 대개 '베이'로 발음된다.[fix]
[ru:]Но мы звали ее Юй Бэйпэй...
[zh:]其实连她自己也不清楚 自己的名字是PEI还是BEI
[en:]and even she didn't know which was correct.
[fre:]et ça n'avait pas l'air de la déranger.
[ar:]في الواقع، حتى هي لم تعرف ما الصح، پـي أو بي[fix]
[ko:]그렇지만 우리는 그녀를 유베이페이라고 불렀다.[fix] 그리고 그녀조차도 그게 맞는 건지 알지 못했다.[fix]
[ru:]и даже она сама не знала, какой вариант правильнее.
[zh:]谁让你们在这儿等我呀
[en:]I didn't know you were waiting?
[fre:]Je ne savais pas que tu attendais ?
[ar:]!لم أكن أعرف أنكم كنتم تنتظرون
[ko:]너희들이 기다리고 있는지 몰랐어.[fix]
[ru:]Ой, а я и не знал, что вы здесь.
[zh:]也没人告诉我
[en:]No one told me anything.
[fre:]Personne ne m'avait rien dit.
[ar:]...لم يخبرني أحد
[ru:]Мне никто не сказал.
[zh:]约会去了
[zh:]去你妈的
[en:]Had a date, did you?[fix] Fuck you! No way!
[fre:]- T'avais un rencard, pas vrai ? - Va te faire voir ! N'importe quoi ![fix]
[ar:]كان عندك موعد؟ - !اللعنة على أمك -[fix]
[ko:]아무도 말 안해줬거든.[fix] 너 데이트했지?[fix] 엿 먹어라! 아냐![fix]
[ru:]А ты типа на свидание шел, жених?[fix] Заткнись, мать твою!
[zh:]别不好意思 马猴
[en:]Don't be embarrassed, Monkey!
[fre:]Ne sois pas si embarrassé, Monkey !
[ar:]!لا تخجل يا قرد
[ko:]이러지 마, 원숭아![fix]
[ru:]Да ладно, Обезьяна, не смущайся!
[zh:]说谁约我了
[en:]Say it! Who had the date.
[fre:]Dis-le ! Qui avait rencard ?
[ar:]قلها! من الذي عنده موعد؟ أنا[fix]
[ko:]말해 봐! 누가 데이트 했다고?[fix]
[ru:]А ну повтори! Кто тут на свидание пришел?
[zh:]得了 得了
[en:]Enough, enough.
[fre:]Assez, assez.
[ar:]حسنا، يكفي، يكفي
[ko:]그만 해, 그만 해.[fix]
[ru:]Ладно, хватит.
[zh:]脸皮还挺薄
[en:]what thin skin!
[fre:]C'est quoi le problème ?
[ar:]!يا لك من حسّاس
[ko:]예민하네![fix]
[ru:]Ишь, какие мы нежные...
[zh:]约会怕什么的
[en:]What's so bad about having a date?
[fre:]Qu'est-ce qu'il y a de mal à avoir un rencard ?
[ar:]ما المشكلة إذا عندك موعد؟
[ko:]데이트 했다는걸 왜 그렇게 싫어하니?[fix]
[ru:]А что такого страшного в свидании?
[zh:]我不是上这儿约会来了吗
[en:]Wasn't it a date that brought me here today?
[fre:]Je ne suis pas venu ici pour un rencard ?
[ar:]أليس موعداً الذي أحضرني اليوم هنا؟
[ru:]Может, мне кто-нибудь назначит свидание?
[zh:]是谁啊
[en:]Who with?
[fre:]Avec qui ?
[ar:]نعم، مع من؟[fix]
[ko:]오늘 여기로 날 불러낸 것도  데이트 하자는거 아니야?[fix] 누구랑?[fix]
[ru:]И кто?
[zh:]他
[en:]Him.
[fre:]Lui.
[ar:]معه[fix]
[ko:]쟤.[fix]
[ru:]Он.
[zh:]坐我这儿
[en:]Come, sit over here.
[fre:]Vas-y, assieds-toi là-bas.
[ar:]تعال اجلس هنا[fix]
[ko:]가. 저리 가 앉아.[fix]
[ru:]Давай, садись здесь.
[zh:]甭理他们
[en:]Just ignore them,
[fre:]Ignore-les,
[ar:]تجاهلهم وحسب
[ru:]Да ты плюнь на них.
[zh:]思想太复杂了 他们
[en:]they've got dirty minds.
[fre:]ils ont des idées pas nettes.
[ar:]عقولهم قذرة
[ko:]쟤들은 신경쓰지 마.[fix] 마음씨가 못된 애들이야.[fix]
[ru:]Они все извращенцы.
[zh:]对 大蚂蚁 说你呐
[en:]She's talking about you, Ant.[fix]
[fre:]Elle parle de toi, Ant.
[ar:]صحيح، إنها تتحدث عنك يا النملة الكبيرة
[ru:]Муравей, это она про тебя говорит![fix]
[zh:]不学无术 思想肮脏
[en:]Ignorant fool! Filthy mind!
[fre:]Ignorant ! Pervers !
[ar:]!أحمق جاهل! عقل قذر
[ko:]니 얘기하고 있는거야, 개미야.[fix] 멍청한 바보! 마음씨 못된 놈![fix]
[ru:]Невоспитанный дурак с грязными желаниями.
[zh:]你前功尽弃了 你
[en:]I'm wasting my breath on you!
[fre:]Je perds mon temps avec toi !
[ar:]!تضيع حياتك
[ru:]И что я на вас свою жизнь трачу?
[zh:]哟 来劲儿
[en:]Now he's talking!
[fre:]Maintenant, il l'ouvre !
[ar:]!صار يشتم[fix]
[ko:]너에 대해 함부로 지껄이고 있는 중이야![fix] 쟤 말하는 것 좀 봐![fix]
[ru:]Ты смотри, как заговорил.
[zh:]先抽颗烟吧
[en:]Forget it, have a cigarette.
[fre:]Laisse tomber, prend une cigarette.
[ar:]هيا، خذ سيجارة
[ko:]신경 끄고, 담배나 펴.[fix]
[ru:]Да забудь, дай лучше закурить.
[zh:]哎 余北蓓
[en:]Yu Beipei...
[fre:]Yu Beipei,
[ar:](يو بيـپـي)[fix]
[ko:]유베이페이...[fix]
[ru:]Юй Бэйпэй...
[zh:]下回把那个米兰也带来
[en:]next time bring Mi Lan with you.
[fre:]la prochaine fois emmène Mi Lan avec toi.
[ar:]عندما تأتين مرة أخرى أحضري (مي لان) تلك معك
[ko:]다음엔 미란이를 데려와.[fix]
[ru:]следующий раз возьми с собой Ми Лань.
[zh:]让咱也认识认识
[en:]We want to meet her.
[fre:]On veut la rencontrer.
[ar:]ودعينا نقابلها
[ru:]Мы хотели бы с ней увидеться.
[zh:]我不管
[en:]You want to chat here up?
[fre:]Tu veux bavarder avec elle ?
[ar:]...لا أظن ذلك
[ko:]그 여자애를 만나보고 싶으니까.[fix] 수작을 걸어보시겠다?[fix]
[ru:]Ты же с ней хочешь пообщаться?
[zh:]看上她 你自个儿拍呀
[en:]Find her yourself.
[fre:]Trouve-la toi-même.
[ar:]ألا تستطيع التعرف على الفتيات بنفسك؟
[ru:]Вот сам ее и приведи.
[zh:]你不号称没有你拍不上的吗
[en:]Haven't you said no girl can resist your charms?
[fre:]Tu n'avais pas dit qu'aucune fille ne pouvait résister à tes charmes ?[fix]
[ar:]ألم تقل أنك لا تخاف من شيء؟[fix]
[ko:]네가 알아서 해.[fix] 어떤 여자도 네 매력에는  저항할 수 없다고 네가 그랬잖아?[fix]
[ru:]Не ты ли рассказывал, что перед тобой ни одна девчонка не устоит?
[zh:]说真格的
[en:]Seriously.
[fre:]Sérieusement,
[ru:]Да я серьезно.
[zh:]老听人提起她
[en:]we hear so much about her.
[fre:]on a tant entendu parler d'elle.
[ar:]أنا جاد، سمعنا الكثير عنها[fix]
[ko:]심각하군.[fix] 그 여자애 얘기를 많이 들었어.[fix]
[ru:]Мы столько слышали о ней.
[zh:]倍儿传奇
[en:]She's a legend.
[fre:]C'est une vraie légende.
[ru:]Она уже легенда какая-то.
[zh:]好多人为她打架
[en:]Guys have fought over her...
[fre:]Des mecs se sont battus,
[ru:]Пацаны постоянно цапаются из-за нее
[zh:]连哥们儿都掰了 有人还出人命了
[en:]friendships have ended and some have died.
[fre:]des amitiés se sont arrêtées et même certains sont morts pour elle.
[ar:]إنها أسطورة. تقاتل عليها رجال وصداقات انهيت. والبعض مات حتى[fix]
[ko:]그 여자애는 하나의 전설이야.[fix] 사내들이 그 여자를 차지하려고 싸웠고...[fix] 우정은 끝나버렸고,  몇 명은 죽었다더군.[fix]
[ru:]Дружба трещит по швам, а у кого-то и умерла уже.
[zh:]就不可以帮个忙 认识一下还不行吗
[en:]All we ask is that you introduce us.
[fre:]Tout ce qu'on te demande, c'est de nous la présenter.
[ar:]ألا يمكنك أن تعرفينا ببعض فقط؟
[ko:]우리가 부탁하는건,  네가 우리를 소개시켜 달라는거야.[fix]
[ru:]Все, что мы просим - чтобы ты нас познакомила.
[zh:]得了吧 其实米兰挺正经的
[en:]Forget it, she's a proper sort.
[fre:]Laisse tomber, elle a un style particulier.
[ar:]مستحيل إنها من النوع المحترم[fix]
[ko:]잊어버려, 걔는 조신한 여자야.[fix]
[ru:]Забудь об этом, она другой породы
[zh:]我也没说她不正经啊
[en:]I didn't say she wasn't.
[fre:]J'ai jamais dit le contraire.
[ar:]لم أقل أنها ليست كذلك
[ru:]Да тебе что - спросить трудно?
[zh:]我跟她提过
[en:]Anyway, I've asked her.[fix]
[fre:]D'ailleurs, je lui ai demandée
[ru:]Я уже спрашивала,[fix]
[zh:]她根本不想上这儿来
[en:]and she said no.
[fre:]et elle a dit non.
[ar:]وأصلاً لقد سألتُها من قبل وقالت لا[fix]
[ko:]걔가 안 그렇다고 말 안했어.[fix] 어쨌든, 전에 그애한테 물어봤는데,[fix] 싫대.[fix]
[ru:]и она отказалась.
[zh:]下午发现的那张照片 把我弄的恍恍惚惚
[en:]The photo I discovered that day put me in a daze.
[fre:]La photo que j'ai vue ce jour-là m'a mis en état second.
[ar:]الصورة التي اكتشفتُها ذلك اليوم جعلتني في حالة ذهول[fix]
[ko:]그날 내가 발견한 그 사진은 나를 눈부시게 했다.[fix]
[ru:]Фотография, которую я увидел в тот день, изумила меня.
[zh:]视野有多大，她的形象便有多大
[en:]She filled my entire field of vision.
[fre:]Elle remplissait toutes mes pensées.
[ar:]صورتها ملأت مجال رؤيتي بالكامل[fix]
[ko:]내 눈앞에는 온통 그녀 뿐이었다.[fix]
[ru:]Я думал только об этой девушке
[zh:]想象力有多丰富
[en:]The implications of her gaze...
[fre:]Son regard qui me fixait
[ru:]А буйное воображение
[zh:]她的神情里便有多少种暗示
[en:]were bounded only by my imagination.
[fre:]troublait complètement mon imagination.
[ar:]وإيحاءات نظراتها لم يحددها إلا مخيلتي[fix]
[ko:]그녀의 시선이 함축하는 의미는...[fix] 오로지 나의 상상력과 맞닿아 있었다.[fix]
[ru:]вкладывало все новые смыслы в ее пристальный взгляд.
[zh:]当时我并不觉得他们所议论的米兰
[en:]I had no idea she was the Mi Lan everyone talked about.
[fre:]J'avais aucune idée que c'était LA Mi Lan dont tout le monde parlait.[fix]
[ar:]في ذلك الوقت لم أكن أعرف من تكون مي لان) هذه التي يتحدث الجميع عنها)[fix]
[ko:]나는 모든 애들이 말하고 있는 미란이라는 여자가 사진 속의 그 여자인 줄 몰랐다.[fix]
[ru:]И я понятия не имел, что это и была Ми Лань, о которой все говорили.[fix]
[zh:]与那张照片有什么联系
[ar:].أو ما هي علاقتها بتلك الصورة[fix]
[zh:]古伦木
[en:]Gooloomoo![fix]
[fre:]Gooloomoo !
[ar:]!غلومو
[ru:]Гулуму![fix]
[zh:]欧巴
[en:]Oo-ba!
[fre:]Oo-ba !
[ar:]!اوبا
[ko:]구루무![fix] 오-바![fix]
[ru:]Оо-ба!
[zh:]吻一下  再吻一下
[en:]Kiss, and one more.
[fre:]Embrasse-le encore une fois !
[ar:]!قبليه - !قبليه ثانية -[fix]
[ko:]한 번 더 키스 해.[fix]
[ru:]Нет-нет-нет, ты проиграла три поцелуя!
[zh:]抓住啊
[en:]Catch him!
[fre:]Attrapez-le !
[ar:]!امسكوه[fix]
[ko:]잡아![fix]
[ru:]Держите его!
[zh:]没事吧
[en:]You OK, Yu Beipei?
[fre:]Ça va, Yu Beipei ?
[ar:]أأنت بخير؟ - أين أصبتِ؟ -[fix]
[ko:]유베이페이, 괜찮아?[fix]
[ru:]Юй Бэйпэй, ты в порядке?
[zh:]碰哪儿了
[zh:]我咬死你
[en:]I'll bite you to death.
[fre:]Je vais te mordre à mort !
[ar:]!سأعضك بقوة[fix]
[ko:]널 물어 죽일테야.[fix]
[ru:]Я тебя до смерти зацелую!
[zh:]松开 松开
[en:]Let go, let go!
[fre:]Laisse-moi, laisse-moi !
[ar:]!اتركني، اتركني
[ko:]놔, 놔![fix]
[ru:]Отпусти, отпусти!
[zh:]快松开 我抽你了
[en:]Let me go![fix]
[fre:]Laisse-moi partir !
[ar:]!اتركني! سأصفعك[fix]
[zh:]快松开 放手
[en:]Let me go!
[fre:]Laisse-moi partir !
[ar:]!اتركني! الآن
[ko:]놓으란 말야![fix] 놔![fix]
[ru:]Отпусти сейчас же![fix]
[zh:]我操你丫
[en:]I'll get you, you little bastard!
[fre:]Je vais t'avoir, petit con !
[ar:]!سأبرحك ضربا[fix]
[ko:]널 갖고 말거야, 이 자식아![fix]
[ru:]Я тебя убью, мелкий ублюдок!
[zh:]算了 余北蓓 得得得
[en:]Forget it, leave him alone, Yu Beipei.
[fre:]Laisse tomber. Fous-lui la paix, Yu Beipei.
[ar:](انسي، (يو بيـپـي - يكفي، يكفي -[fix] من الأفضل أن تبقى هناك يا قرد[fix]
[ko:]그만 하고, 내버려 둬, 유베이페이.[fix]
[ru:]Да забудь, оставь его в покое, Юй Бэйпэй!
[zh:]美丽的鲜花在开放 在开放
[en:]Beautiful flowers blossom across the land.
[fre:]De jolies fleurs s'épanouissent à travers le pays.
[ar:]الزهور الجميلة تزهر، تزهر[fix]
[ko:]아름다운 꽃들이 온 산천에 피었네[fix]
[ru:]Красивые цветы пробиваются через землю.
[zh:]贵宾客人来自远方 来自远方
[en:]Friends are coming from distant places.
[fre:]Des amis arrivent d'endroits éloignés.
[ar:]الضيوف الكرام قادمين من بعيد، من بعيد[fix]
[ko:]친구들은 멀리서 찾아오고 있다네[fix]
[ru:]Друзья приезжают из отдаленных мест.
[zh:]欢乐的歌儿高声唱 高声唱
[ar:]نغني هذه الأغنية السعيدة بابتهاج، بابتهاج[fix]
[zh:]友谊的花开万里香 万里香
[en:]Flowers of friendship blossom across the land.
[fre:]Les fleurs de l'amitié s'épanouissent à travers le pays.
[ar:]عبير الصداقة ينتشر عبر الأرض، عبر الأرض
[ko:]우정의 꽃들이 온 산천에 피었네[fix]
[ru:]Цветы дружбы пробиваются через землю.
[zh:]欢迎 欢迎 热烈欢迎
[en:]Welcome! Welcome! Warmly welcome!
[fre:]Bienvenu ! Bienvenu ! Soyez le bienvenu !
[ar:]!أهلاً! أهلاً" "!نرحب بكم بحرارة[fix]
[ko:]환영합니다! 환영합니다! 뜨겁게 환영합니다![fix]
[ru:]Добро пожаловать! Добро пожаловать! Сердечно приветствуем!
[zh:]欢迎 欢迎 热烈欢迎
[en:]Welcome! Welcome! Warmly welcome!
[fre:]Bienvenu ! Bienvenu ! Soyez le bienvenu !
[ko:]환영합니다! 환영합니다! 뜨겁게 환영합니다![fix]
[ru:]Добро пожаловать! Добро пожаловать! Сердечно приветствуем![fix]
[zh:]欢迎 欢迎 热烈欢迎
[en:]Welcome! Welcome! Warmly welcome!
[fre:]Bienvenu ! Bienvenu ! Soyez le bienvenu !
[ko:]환영합니다! 환영합니다! 뜨겁게 환영합니다![fix]
[zh:]我终日游荡在这栋楼的周围
[en:]I was always hanging out there...
[fre:]Je rôdais toujours ici,
[ar:]قضيتُ فترات النهار متسكعا فوق ذلك المبنى[fix]
[ko:]뜨거운 양철 지붕위의 고양이처럼,[fix]
[ru:]Я каждый день лазил как кошка
[zh:]像只热铁皮屋顶上的猫
[en:]like a cat on a hot tin roof.[fix]
[fre:]comme un chat sur un toit brûlant,
[ar:]مثل قطة على سطح صفيح ساخن[fix]
[ru:]по этим раскаленным крышам.[fix]
[zh:]焦躁不安的守候着画中人的出现
[en:]frantic for the girl in the picture to appear.
[fre:]espérant que la fille sur la photo apparaisse tout à coup.
[ar:]انتظرتُ بلا راحة ظهور الفتاة التي بالصورة[fix]
[ko:]나는 늘 그곳을 서성거렸다.[fix] 사진 속의 그녀가 나타나리라 기대하며...[fix]
[ru:]И все из-за девушки с фотографии.
[zh:]她像一个幽灵
[en:]Like a ghost...
[fre:]Comme un fantôme,
[ar:]كانت مثل الشبح
[ru:]Она была призраком.
[zh:]来无踪 去无影
[en:]she came and went without a trace.
[fre:]elle passait et repartait sans laisser de traces.
[ar:]لا تترك ظل ولا أثر .بمجيئها وذهابها
[ko:]유령처럼...[fix] 그녀는 왔다가 흔적없이 사라졌다.[fix]
[ru:]появившимся и растаявшим без следа.
[zh:]只有我的感觉和嗅觉里 留下了一些痕迹和芳香
[en:]Only my intuition and a lingering fragrance...
[fre:]Seule mon intuition et une légère fragrance
[ar:]ومع ذلك، كنت أشعر ببقايا أثرها أثر من عبيرها[fix]
[ko:]그곳을 떠날 수 없었던 유일한 이유는...[fix]
[ru:]Только мое вообращение и запах, оставляемый ею,
[zh:]能证实她的存在
[en:]could verify her existence.
[fre:]témoignaient de son existence.
[ar:]الذي يؤكد وجودها
[ko:]그녀의 존재를 확인하기 위해서였을 것이다.[fix]
[ru:]свидетельствовали о ее реальности.
[zh:]我延长了守候的时间
[en:]I'd wait till the stars were high in the sky,
[fre:]J'attendais ici jusqu'à ce que les étoiles soient hautes dans le ciel,[fix]
[ru:]Я смотрел с крыши на ее окна до темноты
[zh:]甚至披星戴月
[ar:]انتظرتُ حتى صارت النجوم عالية في السماء[fix]
[ko:]나는 별이 하늘 높이 뜰 때까지 계속 기다렸지만,[fix]
[zh:]终究一无所获
[en:]and still nothing.
[fre:]mais toujours rien.
[ar:]ولكن في النهاية دون جدوى[fix]
[ko:]여전히 그녀를 보지 못했다.[fix]
[ru:]но она ни разу не появилась
[zh:]那是大使
[en:]the ambassador.
[fre:]Voilà l'ambassadeur.
[ar:]انظروا! الكوريون الشماليون - يبدو أن ذلك هو السفير -[fix]
[ko:]대사(大使)야.[fix]
[ru:]Это посол.
[zh:]朝鲜人吧
[en:]It's Koreans.[fix]
[fre:]C'est celui de Corée.
[ru:]Корейский.[fix]
[zh:]哪有那么多大使
[en:]How would you know?
[fre:]Comment tu le saurais ?
[ar:]ما أدراك عن السفراء؟ - إنه هو، ذراعه بذراع زوجته -[fix]
[ru:]А ты откуда знаешь?
[zh:]真的
[en:]It's true.
[fre:]C'est vrai.
[ko:]조선인이야.[fix]
[ru:]Да говорю тебе - точно!
[zh:]昨天不是有一个朝鲜大使吗
[en:]But didn't the ambassador come last night?
[fre:]Mais il n'est pas déjà venu hier soir ?
[ar:]!ليست بذراعه ألم نرى رجل آخر بمراسم الأمس؟[fix] أكان شكله هكذا؟ - ألا يفترض أنه وصل سابقا؟ -[fix]
[ko:]네가 어떻게 알아?[fix] 진짜야.[fix] 그렇지만 저 대사는  어젯밤에는 오지 않았잖아?[fix]
[ru:]Да мы же вчера другого видели?
[zh:]恁没知识 朝鲜大使就一个人
[en:]What would you know? There's no just on, you know.
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que t'en sais ? Il n'y en a pas qu'un, tu sais.
[ar:]لم يكن شكله كهذا الأحمق[fix] كيف تكون جاهلا هكذا؟ السفير ليس شخصا واحدا[fix]
[ko:]네가 그걸 어떻게 알아?  그렇지 않아.[fix]
[ru:]Да что ты гонишь! Что бы ты в этом понимал.
[zh:]得有两三个吧
[en:]There's gotta be two or there at least.
[fre:]Il doit y en avoir au moins deux ou trois.
[ar:]يجب أن يكونوا اثنين أو ثلاثة على الأقل[fix]
[ko:]적어도 두,세명 정도는 왔었어.[fix]
[ru:]Может, их там двое, или еще какая фигня.
[zh:]不是还有南朝鲜的吗
[en:]Maybe this one's from South Korea?
[fre:]C'est peut-être celui de Corée du Sud ?
[ar:]ربما أن هذا من كوريا الجنوبية؟[fix]
[ko:]저 사람들 남한 사람들인가?[fix]
[ru:]Слушай, а может он из Южной Кореи?
[zh:]操你大爷 南朝鲜
[en:]What the fuck would you know?
[fre:]Putain, comment tu pourrais le savoir ?
[ar:]كوريا الجنوبية؟ ماذا تقول؟
[ko:]바보 같은 소리 하고 있네.[fix]
[ru:]Сказал, как в лужу пернул.
[zh:]南朝鲜那是美国的
[en:]South Korea is America's.
[fre:]C'est l'Amérique qui a la Corée du Sud.
[ar:]كوريا الجنوبية تابعة لأمريكا
[ko:]남한은 미국꺼야.[fix]
[ru:]Южная Корея - это Америка.
[zh:]咱们能让他到这儿来
[en:]We wouldn't even let him in.
[fre:]On ne l'aurait pas laissé venir.
[ar:]أتظن أننا سنسمح له بالمجيء؟[fix]
[ru:]Мы бы его не впустили даже.
[zh:]走狗 丫一走狗
[en:]Running dog!
[fre:]Chien galeux !
[ar:]!خادم !خادم لعين[fix]
[ko:]그랬으면 들어오지도 못했을거야.[fix]
[ru:]Голова с отрубями.
[zh:]谁走狗呀
[en:]Who's a running dog?
[fre:]C'est qui le chien galeux ?
[ar:]من الخادم؟[fix]
[ko:]주구((走狗)라고![fix] 누가 주구야?[fix]
[ru:]У кого голова с отрубями?!
[zh:]那是哪国大使啊
[en:]Hey, which country is she ambassador for?
[fre:]Et elle, elle représente quel pays ?
[ar:]تلك، سفيرة أي بلد؟[fix] تلك التي هناك[fix]
[ko:]야, 저 여자는 어느 나라 대표냐?[fix]
[ru:]Эй, а это из какой страны посол?
[zh:]你过去 叫她过来
[en:]Yu Beipei, go get her to come talk to us.
[fre:]Yu Beipei, va lui dire de venir nous parler.
[ar:](اذهبي واقنعيها أن تأتي هنا، (يو بـيـپـي[fix]
[ko:]유베이페이, 우리랑 이야기 좀 하게 가서 데리고 와.[fix]
[ru:]Юй Бэйпэй, пожалуйста, сходи, попроси ее поговорить с нами
[zh:]喝水
[en:]Have some soda.
[fre:]Tiens, prends du soda.
[ar:]تناول الصودا[fix]
[ko:]소다 좀 마셔.[fix]
[ru:]Хочешь лимонада?
[zh:]跟她说什么来着
[en:]What'd you say to her?
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que tu lui as dit ?
[ar:]ماذا قلتِ لها؟[fix] لا شأن لك
[ko:]쟤한테 뭐하고 한거야?[fix]
[ru:]Что ты ей сказала?
[zh:]你是跳舞的吧
[en:]Are you a dancer?
[fre:]Tu es danseuse ?
[ar:]أأنت راقصة؟ - أجل -[fix]
[ru:]А ты будешь танцевать, да?
[zh:]嗯
[en:]yes.
[fre:]Oui.
[ru:]Да.
[zh:]在少年宫 对啊
[en:]At Youth Palace?
[fre:]- Au Palais de la Jeunesse ? - Oui.
[ar:]في (قصر الشباب)؟ - صحيح -[fix]
[ko:]너 댄서야?[fix]
[ru:]Во Дворце молодежи?
[zh:]哎 你叫什么 能告诉我吗
[en:]Can you tell me your name?
[fre:]Tu peux me dire ton nom ?
[ar:]أوه، ممكن أعرف اسمك؟
[ko:]응.[fix] 청년 궁전에서?[fix] 이름이 뭐야?[fix]
[ru:]А как тебя зовут?
[zh:]我叫马小军
[en:]I'm Ma Xiaojun.
[fre:]Moi, c'est Ma Xiaojun.
[ar:](اسمي (ماشياو جون
[ko:]난 마샤오준이야.[fix]
[ru:]Меня Ма Сяоцзюнь
[zh:]我叫张晓梅 拂晓的晓
[en:]I'm Zhang Xiaomei. "Xiao" as in "dawn".[fix]
[fre:]Je m'appelle Zhang Xiaomei. "Xiao" comme dans "aurore".
[ar:](اسمي (جانغ شياومي (شياو) كما في (فجر)[fix]
[ru:]А меня Чжан Сяомэй. "Сяо" - тот же иероглиф, что и "рассвет".[fix]
[zh:]哎 那我是大小的小
[en:]The "Xiao" in my name means "small".
[fre:]Le "Xiao" dans mon nom, c'est pour "petit".
[ar:](أوه، (شياو) في اسمي تعني (صغير[fix]
[ko:]나는 장샤오메이,  "샤오"는 "새벽"이란 뜻이고.[fix] 내 이름에서 "샤오"는 "작은"이란 뜻인데.[fix]
[ru:]А в моем имени "сяо" - это "маленький".
[zh:]这帮人真闹
[en:]These guys really are a pain.
[fre:]Ils sont vraiment pénibles.
[ar:]هؤلاء الشباب مزعجون[fix]
[ko:]얘들은 정말 골치 아픈 놈들이야.[fix]
[ru:]Эти парни реальная чума.
[zh:]往哪儿跑
[en:]Where do you think you're going?[fix]
[fre:]Où est-ce que tu te crois ?[fix]
[ko:]어딜 들어오는거야?[fix]
[ru:]Ты вообще думал, куда шел?[fix]
[zh:]往哪儿跑
[en:]Where do you think you're going?
[ar:]أين تظن أنك ذاهب؟
[zh:]我就是爱好音乐
[en:]I love music,
[fre:]J'adore la musique,
[ar:]أنا عاشق للموسيقى
[ru:]Я люблю музыку,
[zh:]我就想看看演出
[en:]just wanted to see the concert.
[fre:]je voulais juste voir le concert.
[ar:]أردتُ حضور الحفل فقط هذا كل شيء[fix]
[ru:]но только я должен видеть концерт.
[zh:]没别的意思
[zh:]爱好音乐还冒充外国人
[en:]Just because you're a music lover you pretend to be a foreigner.
[fre:]Juste parce que tu aimes la musique, tu te fais passer pour un étranger ?
[ar:]إذن لأنك عاشق للموسيقى تنكرت كأجنبي؟[fix]
[ko:]어딜 들어오는거냐고?[fix] 난 음악을 사랑합니다.[fix] 단지 콘서트가 보고 싶을 뿐입니다.[fix] 음악을 사랑하기 때문에,  외국인인 척 했다는거야?[fix]
[ru:]Только потому, что ты любишь музыку, надо выдавать себя за иностранца, да?
[zh:]冒充朝鲜大使
[en:]And the Korean ambassador at that.
[fre:]Et en plus, pour l'ambassadeur coréen ?
[ru:]Да еще и за корейского посла!
[zh:]这
[ar:]!و السفير الكوري أيضاً[fix]
[ko:]그래서 조선인 대사처럼 굴었군.[fix]
[zh:]什么这个
[en:]What's the real story?
[fre:]C'est quoi ça ?
[ar:]ما...ما هذا؟[fix]
[ko:]사실대로 말해.[fix]
[ru:]Ты вообще в своем уме?
[zh:]什么呀
[zh:]叫什么
[en:]What are you doing?
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que tu fais ?
[ar:]أنت، ماذا تفعل؟[fix]
[ko:]너 뭐하는거야?[fix]
[ru:]Ты что делаешь?
[zh:]怎么了
[en:]What's wrong?
[fre:]Qu'est-ce qu'il y a ?
[ar:]ما الأمر؟
[ru:]А что такое?
[zh:]什么怎么了
[en:]What d'ya mean, what's wrong?
[fre:]Comment ça, "qu'est-ce qu'il y a" ?
[ar:]ماذا تعني بهذا؟ - ...ماذا هناك -[fix]
[ko:]문제 있어요?[fix] 너 지금 문제 있냐고 물었냐?[fix]
[ru:]Я тебя сейчас покажу, что такое.
[zh:]干嘛
[en:]What the hell...
[fre:]Putain...
[ru:]Да что за херня?
[zh:]干嘛啦
[en:]"what the hell"?!
[fre:]"Putain" ?
[ar:]ماذا هناك" ؟" - لا شيء يحدث هنا -[fix]
[ru:]Ах, "что за херня"?!
[zh:]这儿没我事儿
[en:]I didn't do anything.
[fre:]J'ai rien fait.
[ru:]Я ничего не делал!
[zh:]怎没你事儿
[en:]Right.
[fre:]C'est ça !
[ar:]ماذا تعني لا شيء؟ !كنت أراقبك اليوم كله. هيا[fix]
[ru:]Правда.
[zh:]看你半天了 快走
[en:]I've had my eye on you. Come on!
[fre:]Je te regardais. Suis-moi !
[ko:]도대체 무슨 일로..[fix] "도대체"?![fix] 난 아무 짓도 안했어요.[fix] 좋다.[fix] 널 눈여겨보고 있었다. 가자![fix]
[ru:]Я за тобой следил. Вперед!
[zh:]我怎么了
[en:]What'd I do? I didn't do anything.
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que j'ai fait ? J'ai rien fait !
[ar:]ماذا فعلتُ؟ لم افعل شيئا[fix]
[ru:]За что? Я ничего не делал!
[zh:]那女孩子 你也走快点
[en:]And the girl there, you're coming in as well.
[fre:]Et la fille là, tu viens aussi.
[ar:]وأنت يا فتاة !ستأتين أيضا. هيا[fix] ...لم افعل شيئا - !هيا -[fix]
[ko:]내가 뭘 어쨌다는거에요?  난 아무 짓도 안했어요.[fix] 거기있는 너 여자애.  너도 역시 따라 와.[fix]
[ru:]И девушка тоже, вперед, за мной!
[zh:]你爸叫什么
[en:]Your father's name?
[fre:]Le nom de ton père ?
[ar:]اسم أبوك؟ - (ما وينجونغ) -[fix]
[ru:]Фамилия отца?
[zh:]马文中
[en:]Ma Wenzhong.
[fre:]Ma Wenzhong.
[ru:]Ма Вэньчжун.
[zh:]你妈呢
[en:]Your mother?
[fre:]Celui de ta mère ?
[ar:]أمك؟ - (جاي رو) -[fix]
[ru:]Матери?
[zh:]翟茹
[en:]Zhai Ru.
[fre:]Zhai Ru.
[ru:]Чжай Жу.
[zh:]你们家住哪儿
[en:]Where do you live?
[fre:]Tu habites où ?
[ar:]أين تسكن؟ - شارع وزارة الشؤون الداخلية 11 -[fix]
[ko:]아버지 이름?[fix] 마웬홍.[fix] 엄마는?[fix]
[ru:]Где живешь?
[zh:]内务府街11号
[en:]No.11 Internal Affairs Department Street.
[fre:]11 rue du Département des Affaires Internes.
[ko:]자이루.[fix] 너 어디 살아?[fix] 내무부 거리 11번지.[fix]
[ru:]Улица Министерства внутренних дел, 11.
[zh:]看什么看
[en:]What are you looking at?
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que tu regardes ?
[ar:]ما الذي تنظر إليه؟ !التفت[fix]
[ko:]뭘 보고 있는거야?[fix]
[ru:]Ты куда уставился?
[zh:]刚搜出来 多悬
[en:]Just found this. What a menace!
[fre:]Je viens de trouver ça. Un vrai danger public !
[ar:]وجدتُ هذه للتو !كان هذا وشيكا[fix]
[ru:]Смотри, что у него нашли. Опасный человек.
[zh:]以后你们仔细点儿
[en:]Don't let that sort of thing slip by next time.
[fre:]Ne laissez plus ce genre de chose se reproduire.
[ar:]لا تغفل عن هذه الأشياء بالمرة القادمة
[ko:]이것만 찾았어. 골치 아픈 놈들![fix] 앞으로는 저런 놈들 풀어주지 마.[fix]
[ru:]Выбросить не успел, да?
[zh:]那外面那堆人走不了
[en:]That gang's not going anywhere.
[fre:]Ce gang n'ira pas plus loin.
[ar:]لن تذهب تلك العصابة لأي مكان[fix]
[ko:]저 갱들은 이제 아무데도 못 가.[fix]
[ru:]Его банда успела удрать.
[zh:]身上还带着凶器
[en:]Carrying arms!
[fre:]Port d'armes !
[ar:]!يحملون أسلحة[fix] كانوا سيتمردون، صحيح؟[fix]
[ko:]흉기들 치워![fix]
[ru:]Так, незаконное ношение оружия.
[zh:]反了他们了
[en:]Gonna rebel, were they?
[fre:]Ils vont se rebeller, pas vrai ?
[ru:]Теракт что ли готовили?
[zh:]晚上把他们都带走
[en:]We'll take 'em to lockup this evening.
[fre:]On va les mettre en cellule pour la nuit.
[ar:]سنأخذهم للسجن هذا المساء[fix]
[ru:]В общем, в карцер его, там разберемся.
[zh:]国庆
[en:]Guoqing![fix]
[ru:]Гоцин![fix]
[zh:]听见了吗
[en:]Hear that?
[fre:]Guoqing ! T'as entendu ça ?[fix]
[ar:]غو تشينغ)! سمعتَ ذلك؟) - !أجل -[fix] ...يا عم[fix]
[ko:]저것들 반란을 일으킬 생각이었나?[fix] 오늘밤 저놈들 수감할거야.[fix]
[ru:]Что, оглох что ли?
[zh:]叔叔 你放了我得了
[en:]Uncle, Uncle, please let me go.
[fre:]Mon oncle, s'il vous plaît, laissez-moi partir.
[ar:]يا عم، دعني اذهب أرجوك - لماذا تبكي؟ -
[ko:]구오큉![fix] 들었어?[fix] 아저씨, 아저씨, 보내 주세요.[fix]
[ru:]Дяденька, дяденька, пожалуйста, отпустите меня.
[zh:]哭什么
[en:]What are you crying about? What's his story?
[fre:]Pourquoi tu pleures ? Qu'est-ce qu'il s'est passé ?
[ar:]لماذا تبكي؟ لماذا جئنا بك إلى هنا إذن؟
[ko:]왜 우는거냐?  하고 싶은 말이 뭐야?[fix]
[ru:]Ну и что ты там гундишь? Как дело было?
[zh:]其实没我事 我跟那儿等退票来着
[en:]I was waiting for tickets,
[fre:]J'attendais pour avoir des tickets,
[ar:]لم افعل شيئا، حقا كنت انتظر لإعادة بعض التذاكر[fix]
[ko:]저는 표를 사려고 기다리고 있었는데.[fix]
[ru:]Я просто ждал билеты,
[zh:]就跟我带进来了
[en:]and they hauled me in.[fix]
[fre:]et ils m'ont embarqué.
[ar:]وأخذوني إلى هنا بالقوة[fix]
[ru:]а меня забрали.[fix]
[zh:]德性 还镇王府井 镇动物园 镇地安门
[en:]Look at you, you think half of Peking is your turf.
[fre:]Regarde-toi ! Tu penses posséder la moitié de Pékin ?
[ar:]!انظر لحالك البائس تعتقد أن نصف بكين منطقة خاصة لك[fix]
[ko:]그 아저씨들이 끌고 온거에요.[fix] 잘 들어, 넌 베이징의 절반이 네 구역이라고 생각할거야.[fix]
[ru:]А что ты вел себя так, будто пол-Пекина под тобой ходит?
[zh:]我告诉你 公安局全镇
[en:]If it's anyone's turf, it's ours.
[fre:]Même si elle n'appartient à personne, on doit quand même la surveiller.
[ar:]إن كانت خاصة لأحد فهي لنا، فهمت؟
[ru:]Если это и чья-то территория, то наша.
[zh:]知道吗 知道
[en:]Get that? yes.
[fre:]- Compris ? - Oui.
[ar:]فهمت
[ko:]그게 누군가의 구역이라면,  그건 우리들 구역이야.[fix] - 무슨 말인지 알아? - 예.[fix]
[ru:]Конечно, ваша.
[zh:]擦鼻子 滚蛋
[en:]Wipe the snot off your nose...
[fre:]Essuie-moi ce nez qui coule
[ar:]...امسح المخاط من أنفك !والآن اغرب[fix]
[ko:]코나 닦아라...[fix]
[ru:]Сопли, блин, вытри, герой.
[zh:]以后少来展览馆一带胡混
[en:]and don't show you face round here again.
[fre:]et que je ne te revoies plus dans les environs.
[ar:]ولا ترينا وجهك هنا مجددا يا تافه[fix]
[ru:]И больше у нас своей рожей не отсвечивай
[zh:]听见没有去
[en:]Get that?
[fre:]Reprends ça ! File !
[ar:]فهمت؟[fix] !اذهب
[ko:]그리고 다시는 이 근처에 코빼기도 보이지 마.[fix] 알아들어?[fix]
[ru:]Забирай и проваливай.
[zh:]这根不是我的
[en:]This isn't mine, that is.
[fre:]Ce n'est pas la mienne, c'est celle-là.
[ar:]هذا ليس لي، ذلك هو[fix]
[ru:]Это не мое, мой вот этот.
[zh:]那
[en:]that.
[fre:]Là.
[ko:]제건 이게 아니라, 저건데요.[fix] 저기.[fix]
[ru:]Вот.
[zh:]要不要 要不要
[en:]You taking it or what?
[fre:]Tu la prends oui ou non ?
[ar:]تريده أم لا؟ - أريده، أريده -[fix]
[ru:]Так ты берешь или нет?
[zh:]要 要 要
[en:]yes.
[fre:]Oui.
[ar:]لو كنت لا تريده فيمكنك قضاء الليلة هنا[fix]
[ru:]Да.
[zh:]不要跟我在这儿多住两天
[en:]If not, you're welcome to spend the night here.
[fre:]Sinon, tu es le bienvenu pour passer la nuit ici.[fix]
[ru:]Если нет - я тебя закрою на ночь.
[zh:]要 要 就这根吧
[en:]I'm taking it! This one is fine!
[fre:]Je prends celle-là ! Elle va très bien !
[ar:]!سآخذه !لا بأس بهذا[fix]
[ko:]가저 갈래, 말래?[fix] 예.[fix] 가지고 가기 싫다면,  여기서 하룻밤 더 보내게 해주지.[fix] 가져 갈게요! 이게 좋아요![fix]
[ru:]Я беру! Все хорошо!
[zh:]你把我那根腰带给我拿过来
[en:]Go fetch my belt.
[fre:]Va me chercher ma ceinture !
[ar:]اذهب إلى هناك وأحضر حزامي[fix]
[ko:]가서 내 벨트 가져와.[fix]
[ru:]Быстро принес мой ремень!
[zh:]我那根 找去
[en:]My belt! Go get it!
[fre:]Ma ceinture ! Ramène-la !
[ar:]!حزامي! أحضره[fix]
[ru:]Мой ремень! Бегом!
[zh:]你不牛逼吗 你不是横吗
[en:]Don't you think you're Mr. Tough?
[fre:]Tu te prends pour un dur ?
[ar:]ألستَ رجلا قويا؟ ألستَ صلبا؟
[ko:]내 벨트! 가서 가져 와![fix] 네가 '미스터 터프'라고 생각하는건 아니겠지?[fix]
[ru:]Ты думаешь, твоя фамилия Крутой?
[zh:]你现在怎么熊了
[en:]Lose your nerve, have you?
[fre:]Tu craques, c'est ça ?
[ar:]فقدتَ جرأتك، هاه؟[fix]
[ko:]눈깔에 힘 빼.[fix]
[ru:]Нервишки побереги, успокойся.
[zh:]你还甭跟这儿求我
[en:]Get up off your knees...[fix]
[fre:]Lève-toi
[ar:]كف عن الترجي والبكاء[fix]
[ru:]Встань с колен...[fix]
[zh:]甭流眼泪
[en:]and stop crying.
[fre:]et arrête de chialer.
[ru:]и хватит плакать.
[zh:]我就不吃那套
[en:]I don't buy that crap.
[fre:]Je n'ai pas acheté cette merde.
[ar:]لا يقنعني هذا الهراء
[ko:]무릎 꿇어.[fix] 그리고 울지마.[fix] 난 그런 수작엔 안 넘어가.[fix]
[ru:]Я не возьму это говно, дай мой.
[zh:]我哭什么
[en:]When I cry,
[fre:]Moi quand je pleure,
[ar:]لماذا كنت ابكي؟[fix]
[ru:]Я то я такое сделаю,
[zh:]我那是迷惑你们的 孙子
[en:]it's just to confuse you wimps.
[fre:]c'est juste pour vous tromper, mauviettes.
[ar:]ذلك لكي أثير حيرتكم يا أوغاد[fix]
[ko:]내가 운건,[fix] 너 같은 바보들을 속이려고 그랬던거야.[fix]
[ru:]что ты обосрешься от страха.
[zh:]我拍婆子 你管得着吗
[en:]What's if your business if I pick up chicks?
[fre:]En quoi ça vous regarde que je ramène des poulettes ?
[ar:]، لو تعرفتُ على الفتيات[fix] فما شأنكم؟ لست أسعى لأمهاتكم[fix]
[ko:]내가 여자를 꼬시던 말던,  니가 무슨 상관이야?[fix]
[ru:]Какое вам дело, если я клеил телку?
[zh:]我又没拍你妈
[en:]I'm not after your mother.
[fre:]Je ne vais pas draguer vos mères.
[ru:]Я что - твою маму клеил?
[zh:]我还明告诉你了
[ar:]، و أقول لكم الآن
[zh:]我明儿还跟那儿拍
[en:]I'm coming back to do it again tomorrow.
[fre:]Je repasserai dès demain.
[ar:]سأعود هنا لفعل ذلك غداً
[ko:]내가 니 엄마를 쫓아다닌것도 아닌데.[fix]
[ru:]Я завтра вернусь, и буду делать то же самое
[zh:]我就一个人去
[en:]I'll be alone.
[fre:]Je serai seul,
[ar:]سآتي وحدي
[ru:]И я буду один.
[zh:]你要不去逮我你孙子
[en:]If you don't arrest me you can kiss my ass.
[fre:]et si vous ne m'arrêtez pas, alors allez vous faire foutre.
[ar:]والأفضل لكم ألا تحاولوا إيقافي يا داعرين
[ko:]난 내일 다시 여자를 꼬시러 돌아 갈거야.[fix] 혼자 갈거야.[fix] 니가 만약 나를 체포하지 못하면,  넌 엿같은 새끼가 되는거야.[fix]
[ru:]Если ты ко мне подойдешь, то поцелуешь меня в жопу.
[zh:]我镇东单 镇西单
[en:]I'm the king of half of Peking...
[fre:]Je suis le Roi de la moitié de Pékin
[ar:]أنا ملك الجانب الغربي والشرقي
[ru:]Я король половины Пекина.[fix]
[zh:]我还镇你们炮局呢
[en:]and of your station as well.
[fre:]ainsi que de votre commissariat.
[ar:]وملك مركزكم أيضا[fix]
[ko:]나는 베이징 절반을 지배하는 왕이고...[fix] 또한 니네 경찰서도 마찬가지야.[fix]
[ru:]и вашей станции тоже.
[zh:]行 行 行 擦鼻子 滚蛋
[en:]OK, Get outta here.
[fre:]OK, dégagez de là.
[ar:]حسنا، حسنا، امسح أنفك واغرب[fix]
[ko:]좋아, 여기서 꺼져.[fix]
[ru:]Ладно, вали отсюда.
[zh:]滚不滚 你不愿滚就跟这儿多呆两天
[en:]If you don't move it, you're welcome to spend the night.
[fre:]Si vous ne dégagez pas, vous serez les bienvenus pour passer la nuit en cellule.[fix]
[ar:]ستذهب أم لا؟ إن كنتَ لا تريد الذهاب فيمكنك قضاء الليلة هنا[fix]
[ko:]안 꺼지면, 기꺼이  하룻밤을 지내도록 해주지.[fix]
[ru:]Если ты сейчас не исчезнешь, я тебя закрою на ночь.
[zh:]谁呀
[en:]Who's there?
[fre:]Qui est là ?
[ar:]من هناك؟[fix]
[ko:]누구야?[fix]
[ru:]Кто там?
[zh:]羊搞给人划了
[en:]Someone's bashed Yang Gao.
[fre:]Quelqu'un a frappé Yang Gao.
[ar:]تعرض (يانغ غاو) للضرب[fix]
[ko:]양가오가 폭행당했다.[fix]
[ru:]Ян Гао отпрессовали.
[zh:]我操
[en:]Fuck!
[fre:]Putain !
[ar:]!اللعنة[fix]
[ko:]우라질![fix]
[ru:]Как?
[zh:]今天羊搞回家的时候
[en:]On his way home...
[fre:]Sur le retour de l'école, il a vu des gamins de Liutiao
[ar:]، بطريقه للمنزل[fix]
[ru:]По пути домой...
[zh:]看见六条的几个孩子欺负傻子
[en:]he saw some kids from Liutiao bullying the retarded boy.
[fre:]en train de faire chier le petit attardé.
[ar:]رأى فتيان من الحارة السادسة يضايقون الفتى المعاق[fix]
[ko:]집으로 가는 길에...[fix] 양가오는 류샤오 거리에서 몇 명의 애들이  지진아를 놀리고 있는 것을 봤어.[fix]
[ru:]он увидел несколько парней Лютяо, опускавших запоздавшего пацана.
[zh:]他们逼傻子吃猫屎
[en:]They were making him eat catshit...[fix]
[fre:]Ils lui faisaient bouffer de la merde de chat,
[ar:]كانوا يجبروه على أكل براز القطط
[ru:]Они заставляли его жрать кошачье дерьмо.[fix]
[zh:]还要抢走傻子骑了好几年的棍子
[en:]and trying to take away his pole.
[fre:]et ont essayé de lui piquer sa canne.
[ar:]ويحاولون أخذ العمود الذي يمتطيه منذ سنوات
[ko:]고양이 똥을 먹이고 있었던거야...[fix] 그 아이의 낚싯대를 뺏으려고 했고.[fix]
[ru:]и пытались отобрать его палку.
[zh:]羊搞上去帮忙
[en:]Yang Gao went to his rescue...[fix]
[fre:]Yang Gao s'est interposé
[ru:]Ян Гао впрягся за него[fix]
[zh:]结果让他们给打了
[en:]and they bashed him up.
[fre:]et ils l'ont frappé.
[ar:]ذهب (يانغ غاو) لمساعدته وضربوه[fix]
[ru:]и они вломили ему.
[zh:]眼睛给封了 棍子给打成了两半
[en:]He can't open his eyes. They broke the pole in half.
[fre:]Il ne peut plus ouvrir l'œil et ils ont cassé la canne en deux.
[ar:]عينه أغلقت من التورم وكسروا العمود لنصفين[fix]
[ko:]양가오가 그 아이를 구하러 나섰다가...[fix] 그 놈들한테 폭행당한거야.[fix] 양가오는 눈을 못 떠.  그 놈들은 그 낚싯대를 절단 냈고.[fix]
[ru:]Он не может глаз открыть. Они сломали его палку.
[zh:]走
[en:]Let's go.
[fre:]On y va.
[ar:]لنذهب[fix]
[ko:]가자.[fix]
[ru:]Пошли.
[zh:]那我怎么办
[en:]What about me?[fix]
[fre:]Et moi ?
[ar:]ماذا عني؟[fix]
[ru:]А я?[fix]
[zh:]你留这儿吧
[en:]Girls stay behind.
[fre:]Les filles restent en arrière.
[ar:]ابقي هنا[fix]
[ko:]나는 어떻게 해?[fix] 여자들은 그냥 남아있는거야.[fix]
[ru:]Девчонки остаются.
[zh:]大哥 没我事
[en:]I wasn't involved, mate!
[fre:]J'ai rien fait, les mecs !
[ar:]!لم أكن معهم يا أخي[fix]
[ko:]난 그 일과 상관없어, 친구들![fix]
[ru:]Я его не бил, клянусь.
[zh:]躲开
[en:]Out of my way!
[fre:]Dégage de là !
[ar:]!ابتعدوا[fix]
[ko:]모두 비켜![fix]
[ru:]С дороги!
[zh:]羊搞 有他没有
[en:]Yang Gao, was he involved?
[fre:]Yang Gao, il y était ?
[ar:]يانغ غاو)، هل كان معهم؟)[fix]
[ko:]양가오, 이 새끼 맞지?[fix]
[ru:]Ян Гао, он там был?
[zh:]撤
[en:]Let's go.
[fre:]On se casse.
[ar:]لنذهب[fix]
[ko:]Let's go. 가자.[fix]
[ru:]Сваливаем.
[zh:]马猴
[en:]Monkey...
[fre:]Monkey...
[ar:]يا قرد - هاه؟ -
[ko:]원숭아...[fix]
[ru:]Обезьяна...
[zh:]你丫的手怎么那么黑呀
[en:]when'd you get to be such a thug.
[fre:]Depuis quand tu es devenu un vrai gangster ?
[ar:]متى صرتَ مجرما هكذا؟[fix]
[ko:]너 언제 그렇게 흉악범이 됐냐?[fix]
[ru:]когда это ты стал таким кровожадным?
[zh:]怎么了
[en:]What do you mean?
[fre:]De quoi tu parles ?
[ar:]ماذا تقصد؟[fix]
[ru:]Ты о чем?
[zh:]那板砖拍得 连我都怕
[en:]What you did with that brick?
[fre:]Ce que tu as fait avec cette brique.
[ar:]...ما فعلتَه بذلك الطوب حتى أنا خفت
[ko:]What do you mean? 무슨 소리야?[fix] 그 벽돌로 한 거 말이야?[fix]
[ru:]А что делал тот кирпич у тебя в руке?
[zh:]天太黑 看不清楚
[en:]It was dark. I couldn't see.
[fre:]Il faisait sombre. Je n'y voyais rien.
[ar:]كان ظلاما. لم أرى[fix]
[ko:]어두워서, 잘 보이지 않았어.[fix]
[ru:]Там было темно, я ни хрена не видел.
[zh:]要不然 非废了丫挺的
[en:]Otherwise I'd really have wasted him.
[fre:]Autrement, je l'aurai complètement fracassé.
[ar:]وإلا لكنتُ قتلته بحق[fix]
[ko:]그렇지 않았다면,  실제로 그 새끼를 죽였을거야.[fix]
[ru:]Вот и побоялся впустую потратить.
[zh:]哟 哟 哟
[zh:]说你胖吧 你还喘了 你
[en:]If you told Monkey he was fat he'd loosen his belt. He's really full of himself now!
[fre:]Monkey, il a vraiment changé. Il y va à fond maintenant.
[ar:]لو دعوتُك بالسمين لضربتَني أنا أيضا[fix] إنه متفاخر بنفسه الآن[fix]
[ko:]쟤는 지금 실제로 자기가 최고인 줄 알고 있어![fix]
[ru:]Обезьяне надо ремень ослабить - настолько он раздулся от гордости!
[zh:]其实
[en:]Actually...
[fre:]Au fait...
[ar:]...في الواقع
[ko:]사실은...[fix]
[ru:]На самом деле...
[zh:]说什么呀
[en:]Actually what?
[fre:]Au fait quoi ?
[ar:]في الواقع ماذا؟
[ru:]Что на самом деле?
[zh:]其实可能没那孩子
[en:]I don't think that kid was involved.
[fre:]Je ne crois pas que ce gamin était impliqué.
[ar:]لا أعتقد أن ذلك الفتى كان معهم[fix]
[ko:]사실은 뭐?[fix] 아까 걔는 상관없는 애야.[fix]
[ru:]На самом деле я не уверен, что этот пацан там был.
[zh:]去你妈的
[en:]Fuck you!
[fre:]Quel con !
[ar:]كفاك سخفا[fix]
[ru:]Твою мать!
[zh:]孙子 你丫早干嘛来的
[en:]Asshole! Why didn't you say so earlier?
[fre:]Abruti ! Pourquoi tu ne l'as pas dit plus tôt ?
[ar:]!يا غبي لماذا لم تقل هذا من قبل؟
[ko:]야, 이 새끼야![fix] 새끼야! 그걸 왜 이제 말해?[fix]
[ru:]Дырка в жопе! Ты раньше мог сказать?
[zh:]不是 我还没看清楚
[en:]It all happened...
[fre:]Tout s'est passé si vite,
[ar:]لم أرى جيدا[fix]
[ru:]Да все случилось...
[zh:]丫一板砖就拍下去了
[en:]before I got a good look.
[fre:]et je n'y voyais pas grand-chose.
[ar:].إلى أن ضربه القرد بذلك الطوب عموما هو فرد من تلك العصابة ولقد ضربناه[fix]
[ko:]내가 제대로 살펴보기도 전에...[fix] 일이 벌어져버린거야.[fix]
[ru:]раньше, чем я его рассмотрел.
[zh:]反正都他们的人
[en:]He's part of that gang.[fix]
[fre:]Il faisait partie du gang.
[ru:]Да ладно, он все равно из той банды.[fix]
[zh:]打都打了
[en:]What the hell!
[fre:]Ça change quoi ?
[ru:]Что за хрень!
[zh:]你走 你走
[en:]Get out of my sight.
[fre:]Sors de ma vue !
[ar:]اذهب. اخرج من هنا[fix]
[ko:]그래도 그애는 그 패거리 중의 한 명이야.[fix] 당해도 싸![fix] 내 눈앞에서 꺼져.[fix]
[zh:]谁呀
[en:]Who's there?
[fre:]Qui est là ?
[ar:]...ما الذي - من هناك؟ -[fix]
[ko:]거기 누구야?[fix]
[ru:]Кто это?
[zh:]余北蓓
[en:]Yu Beipei.
[fre:]Yu Beipei.
[ar:]...(إنها (يو بـيـپـي - !(يو بـيـپـي) -[fix]
[ko:]유베이페이.[fix]
[ru:]Юй Бэйпэй
[zh:]马猴
[en:]Monkey.
[fre:]Monkey.
[ar:]يا قرد[fix]
[ru:]Обезьяна.
[zh:]你可真过分
[en:]You asshole.
[fre:]Abruti !
[ar:]!لقد تماديتَ
[ko:]원숭아.[fix] 야 이 새끼야.[fix]
[ru:]Ты дырка в жопе!
[zh:]等会非抽你不可
[en:]I'm going to get you.
[fre:]Je vais te choper !
[ar:]!سأبرحك ضربا[fix]
[ko:]널 잡고 말거야.[fix]
[ru:]Я тебя еще поймаю!
[zh:]来啊 现在就来吧
[en:]Come on out, then.
[fre:]Sors de là !
[ar:]!تعالي إذن[fix]
[ru:]Сваливаем отсюда!
[zh:]来啊
[en:]come on, get a move on.
[fre:]Allez, sors de là !
[ar:]!هيا - أجل، تعالي -[fix]
[ko:]그럼 이리로 나와.[fix] 이리 와, 이리 와 보라고.[fix]
[ru:]Давай, пока ей не до нас.
[zh:]讨厌
[en:]You jerks.
[fre:]Pauvres nuls !
[ar:]!أيها الأغبياء[fix]
[ko:]머저리들.[fix]
[ru:]Ты, сопляк!
[zh:]往这瞧瞧 衣服全给弄湿了
[en:]Look at this. My clothes are soaking.
[fre:]Regardez ! Mes vêtements sont trempés,
[ar:]!انظروا إلي !ملابسي غرقانة[fix]
[ko:]이것 봐.  내 옷이 다 젖었잖아.[fix]
[ru:]Посмотри, что ты натворил! Я вся мокрая.
[zh:]胳膊都摔破了
[en:]And you've torn the sleeve.
[fre:]et vous avez déchiré ma manche.
[ar:]!والأكمام مزقتوها[fix]
[ko:]소매도 찢어졌어.[fix]
[ru:]Еще и рукав из-за тебя порвала.
[zh:]这么讨厌呀
[en:]Jeez, you're a pain.
[fre:]Mon Dieu, qu'ils sont pénibles !
[ar:]يا لكم من أغبياء
[ko:]너 짜증나.[fix]
[ru:]Мне больно, между прочим.
[zh:]余北蓓 先出去
[en:]Yu Beipei, you've got to leave. Go away!
[fre:]Yu Beipei, sors de là ! Dégage !
[ar:]يو بـيـپـي)، عليك الخروج من هنا)[fix]
[ko:]유베이페이, 여기서 나가. 나가라고![fix]
[ru:]Юй Бэйпэй, выйди! Убирайся!
[zh:]不
[en:]No
[fre:]Non.
[ar:]!كلا[fix]
[ru:]Нет.
[zh:]我就不
[en:]I won't.
[fre:]Je ne bougerai pas d'ici.
[ar:]مستحيل
[ru:]Я не выйду.
[zh:]我跟你说 出去啊
[en:]I said, get out!
[fre:]J'ai dit, dégage !
[ar:]أقول لك، اخرجي
[ko:]싫어.[fix] I won't. 안 나가.[fix] 나가라고 했잖아![fix]
[ru:]Я сказал - исчезни.
[zh:]真没劲
[en:]You bore me!
[fre:]Vous me faites rire !
[ar:]يا للوضع الكريه[fix]
[ru:]Вы меня достали.
[zh:]还藏起来了
[en:]Hiding like that...
[fre:]Se cacher comme ça...
[ar:]...تختبئون هكذا[fix]
[ko:]따분한 소리 그만 해![fix] 누가 꼭 너네들...[fix]
[ru:]Было бы что прятать.
[zh:]我多想看你们似的
[en:]as if anyone wanted to look at you guys.
[fre:]comme si quelqu'un voulait vous voir nus.
[ar:]كما لو أني أريد رؤيتكم[fix]
[ko:]거시기를 보고 싶어하기나 하는 것처럼,  감추고 있군.[fix]
[ru:]Как будто бы все только и мечтают на вас посмотреть.
[zh:]余北蓓 那是我的衣服
[en:]Oh no! Those are my clothes!
[fre:]Oh non ! Ce sont mes fringues !
[ar:]يو بـيـپـي)!هذه ملابسي)[fix]
[ko:]안돼! 그거 내 옷이야![fix]
[ru:]Ой, нет! Это моя одежда!
[zh:]我才不管谁的衣服呢
[en:]I don't care whose they are.[fix]
[fre:]Je me fiche à qui elles sont.
[ar:]لا يهمني لمن هي[fix]
[ko:]누구꺼라도 상관없어.[fix]
[ru:]Буду я разбираться - чья она.[fix]
[zh:]马猴 马猴
[en:]Monkey.
[fre:]Monkey,
[ar:]يا قرد[fix]
[ru:]Обезьяна...
[zh:]找上你了
[en:]this all your fault.
[fre:]c'est de ta faute.
[ar:]كل هذا ذنبك[fix]
[ko:]원숭아.[fix] 다 너 때문이야.[fix]
[ru:]это все из-за тебя!
[zh:]直了
[en:]He's erect![fix]
[fre:]Il bande !
[ar:]إنه منتصب[fix]
[zh:]直了
[en:]He's erect!
[fre:]Il bande !
[ar:]!إنه منتصب[fix]
[ko:]얘 섰다![fix] 얘 섰어![fix]
[ru:]У него встал![fix]
[zh:]这丫直了
[en:]The bastard's got an erection!
[fre:]Ce bâtard a une érection !
[ar:]!انظروا، إنه منتصب[fix]
[ru:]Глянь, у этого ублюдка стояк!
[zh:]丫直了
[en:]He's erect!
[fre:]Il bande !
[ko:]이 자식 섰어![fix] He's erect! 섰어![fix]
[ru:]У него встал!
[zh:]丫怎那么流氓啊
[fre:]Espèce d'ordure !
[ar:]!أيها الوضيع[fix]
[zh:]我 我是尿憋的
[en:]You scumbag![fix] I have to pee.[fix]
[fre:]J'ai vraiment envie de pisser.
[ar:]أريد...أريد التبول
[ko:]더러운 놈![fix] 오줌 마려워서 그러는거야.[fix]
[ru:]Ты мешок с дерьмом.[fix] Да я не поэтому, я ссать захотел.[fix]
[zh:]滚蛋
[en:]Get outta here.
[fre:]Casse-toi de là !
[ar:]ابتعد من هنا[fix]
[ko:]저리 가.[fix]
[ru:]А ну вали отсюда!
[zh:]哎 哎
[en:]Hei.
[fre:]Hé.
[ko:]저기...[fix]
[ru:]Эй!
[zh:]你叫我吗
[en:]Talking to me?
[fre:]C'est à moi que tu parles ?
[ar:]تكلمني؟[fix]
[ko:]나한테 말한거니?[fix]
[ru:]Это ты мне?
[zh:]咱们好像在哪儿见过吧
[en:]Haven't we met somewhere before?
[fre:]On ne s'est pas déjà vu quelque part ?
[ar:]نعم...ألم نلتقي من قبل؟[fix]
[ko:]우리 전에 어디서 만난적 있지 않나?[fix]
[ru:]Мы никогда раньше не встречались?
[zh:]得了吧 小毛孩
[en:]Forget it, kid.
[fre:]Laisse tomber, gamin.
[ar:]مستحيل يا فتى
[ru:]О боже! Забудь об этом, мальчик!
[zh:]你才多大就干这个了
[en:]You're not old enough for this.
[fre:]Tu es trop jeune pour ça.
[ar:].لست كبيرا بما يكفي لهذا
[ko:]신경꺼라, 꼬마야.[fix] 넌 아직 이런 수작 걸리엔 어려.[fix]
[ru:]Ты слишком маленький для меня.
[zh:]等等 别走啊
[en:]Wait, don't go!
[fre:]Attends, ne pars pas !
[ar:]انتظري، لا تذهبي[fix]
[ko:]잠깐만, 가지 마![fix]
[ru:]Подожди, не уходи!
[zh:]哎 你是不是就住前面楼啊
[en:]Don't you live in that building?
[fre:]Tu n'habites pas dans cet immeuble ?
[ar:]هل تسكنين بذلك المبنى؟[fix]
[ko:]너 그 건물에서 안 살지?[fix]
[ru:]А ты не в этом доме живешь?
[zh:]你是那中学的学生吧 是啊
[en:]Do you go to school down the street?
[fre:]Tu vas à l'école en bas de la rue ?
[ar:]ألست طالبا بالثانوية؟ - بلى -[fix] .رأيتك من قبل[fix]
[ko:]학교 갈 때 그 길로 가니?[fix]
[ru:]Тебе в школу пора.
[zh:]我见过你
[en:]Yes, I've seen you.
[ru:]Точно, я тебя видел!
[zh:]有一天在派出所门口
[en:]at the door of the police station.
[fre:]Oui, je t'ai déjà vu devant le commissariat de police.[fix]
[ru:]В полицейском участке
[zh:]你跟一个女警察一块儿出来
[en:]You were with a policewoman.
[fre:]Tu étais avec une flic.
[ar:]ذات يوم عند مدخل مركز الشرطة كنتِ خارجة مع شرطية[fix]
[ko:]그래, 너 본적 있어.[fix] 경찰서 문에서.[fix] 여자 경찰관과 함께 있었잖아.[fix]
[ru:]Ты там с толстой полицейской теткой была
[zh:]咱们认识认识吧
[en:]Can we be friends?[fix]
[fre:]On ne pourrait pas être amis ?
[ar:]ممكن نتعرف؟[fix]
[ru:]Давай дружить.[fix]
[zh:]有必要吗 有
[en:]Is that necessary?
[fre:]Il le faut ?
[ar:]ضروري؟ - أجل -[fix] لا أعتقد ذلك[fix]
[ko:]우리 친구할까?[fix]
[ru:]А надо?
[zh:]我觉着没必要
[en:]I don't think so.[fix]
[fre:]Je ne pense pas moi.
[ru:]- Да. - А я думаю - нет.[fix]
[zh:]那咱们交个朋友吧
[en:]Why not be friends?
[fre:]Pourquoi on ne serait pas amis ?
[ar:]لمَ لا نكون صديقين؟
[ko:]그럴 필요가 있을까?[fix] 난 그렇게 생각 안 해.[fix] 왜 친구가 못 되는데?[fix]
[ru:]А почему?
[zh:]一看你就是一坏孩子
[en:]You're obviously a very bad boy.
[fre:]Tu es assurément un très mauvais garçon.
[ar:]على الفور أرى أنك بذرة سيئة[fix]
[ko:]넌 분명히 아주 못된 녀석일거야.[fix]
[ru:]Потому что ты мелкий уличный пацан.
[zh:]就认识认识 有什么
[en:]Can't we just get to know each other?
[fre:]On ne pourrait pas au moins faire connaissance ?
[ar:]ما المشكلة لو تعارفنا؟[fix]
[ko:]그냥 서로에 대해 알아보자는 건데도 안 돼?[fix]
[ru:]Ну, я же не замуж тебя зову. Просто познакомимся.
[zh:]要不你可以当我姐嘛
[en:]Be an elder sister to me.
[fre:]Tu pourrais être ma sœur aînée.
[ar:]يمكنك أن تكوني أخت كبرى لي[fix]
[ru:]Будешь мне как старшая сестра.
[zh:]你呀 上别处认姐姐去吧
[en:]Find your elder sisters elsewhere.
[fre:]Trouve-toi des sœurs aînées ailleurs.
[ar:]لمَ لا تجد أختك الكبرى بمكان آخر هاه؟[fix]
[ko:]내 누나가 돼 줘.[fix] 니 누나는 다른데가서 찾아 봐.[fix]
[ru:]Ищи себе сестру в другом месте.
[zh:]你要不跟我认识 我可
[en:]If you won't be friends, I'll...
[fre:]Si tu ne veux pas devenir mon amie, je vais...
[ar:]إن لم تكوني صديقتي ...سوف
[ko:]친구가 못 되겠다면, 나는...[fix]
[ru:]Смотри, не рискуй. Ты сама сказала, что я уличный.
[zh:]你想怎么着
[en:]You'll what?
[fre:]Tu vas quoi ?
[ar:]سوف ماذا؟[fix] تضربني؟[fix]
[ko:]어쩔건데?[fix]
[ru:]И что ты сделаешь?
[zh:]打我
[en:]Beat me up?[fix]
[fre:]Me taper ?
[ar:]أجل
[ru:]Ударишь меня?[fix]
[zh:]啊
[fre:]Ouais.
[zh:]是吗
[en:]Yeah.[fix] Really?
[fre:]Vraiment ?
[ar:]حقا؟[fix]
[ko:]때릴거야?[fix] 그래.[fix] 진짜?[fix]
[ru:]Хотя бы.[fix] Да ты что?
[zh:]你打得过我吗
[en:]You really think if we fought you'd win?
[fre:]Tu crois vraiment que tu gagneras ?
[ar:]أحقا تعتقد أنك تستطيع ضربي؟[fix]
[ko:]우리가 싸우면, 네가 이길거라고 생각하니?[fix]
[ru:]А ты уверен, что справишься со мной?
[zh:]哎 那小孩
[en:]Kid,
[fre:]Hé gamin,
[ar:]يا فتى[fix] تعال[fix]
[ko:]꼬마야,[fix]
[ru:]Эй, пацан,
[zh:]过来
[en:]come over here.
[fre:]viens par là.[fix]
[ko:]이리 와 봐.[fix]
[ru:]подойди-ка сюда.
[zh:]你多大了
[en:]How old are you?
[fre:]Tu as quel âge ?
[ru:]Тебе сколько лет?
[zh:]十六
[en:]sixteen.
[fre:]Seize ans.
[ar:]كم عمرك؟ - 16 -[fix]
[ko:]너 몇 살이니?[fix] 16.[fix]
[ru:]Шестнадцать.
[zh:]让我看看
[en:]Let me look at you.
[fre:]Laisse-moi te regarder.
[ar:]دعني أرى[fix]
[ko:]한 번 보자.[fix]
[ru:]Дай-ка я не тебя посмотрю.
[zh:]你哪有十六啊 骗我
[en:]No way you're sixteen, liar!
[fre:]Tu n'as pas seize ans, menteur !
[ar:]مستحيل 16، كاذب[fix]
[ko:]넌 16살이 아니야, 거짓말쟁이![fix]
[ru:]Врешь, нет тебе 16-ти.
[zh:]那你呢 你多大
[en:]And you? How old are you?[fix]
[fre:]Et toi ? Tu as quel âge ?
[ar:]وأنت؟ كم عمرك؟[fix]
[ru:]А ты? Тебе сколько лет?[fix]
[zh:]反正比你大
[en:]Older than you.
[fre:]Plus que toi.
[ar:]أكبر منك على أي حال
[ru:]Больше чем тебе.
[zh:]你想认我当姐姐
[en:]Still want me to be your elder sister?
[fre:]Tu veux toujours que je devienne ta sœur aînée ?
[ar:]أحقا تريدني كأخت كبرى لك؟ - حقا -
[ko:]그럼 넌? 넌 몇 살인데?[fix] 너보다는 많아.[fix] 너 아직도 내가 니 누나가 됐으면 좋겠냐?[fix]
[ru:]Ты все еще хочешь, чтобы я была твоей старшей сестрой?
[zh:]一见你 怎么说
[en:]Yes! How can I put it...
[fre:]Oui ! Je n'y peux rien...
[ar:]أول ما رأيتك ...شعرتُ...كيف أقولها
[ko:]응! 여동생 해달라고...[fix]
[ru:]Конечно! Тем более что ты
[zh:]就觉得你特像我姐
[en:]you're just like my sister.[fix]
[fre:]Tu es comme ma sœur.
[ar:]أنت تماما كأختي[fix]
[ko:]할수는 없잖아.[fix]
[ru:]и впрямь как моя старшая сестра.[fix]
[zh:]有姐姐吗
[en:]You have a sister?
[fre:]Tu as une sœur ?
[ru:]А у тебя есть сестра?
[zh:]没有
[en:]No.
[fre:]Non.
[ar:]لديك أخت؟ - لا -[fix]
[ko:]너 여동생 있니?[fix] No. 없어.[fix]
[ru:]Нет.
[zh:]叫什么
[en:]What's your name?
[fre:]Comment tu t'appelles ?
[ru:]Как тебя зовут?
[zh:]马小军
[en:]Ma Xiaojun.
[fre:]Ma Xiaojun.
[ar:]ما اسمك؟ - (ماشياو جون) -[fix]
[ko:]이름이 뭐야?[fix]
[ru:]Ма Сяоцзюнь
[zh:]真的
[en:]Really.[fix]
[fre:]C'est vrai !
[ar:]حقا[fix]
[ru:]Честно.[fix]
[zh:]我书包 马小军
[en:]It's here on my book bag.
[fre:]C'est écrit sur mon sac.
[ar:]مكتوب هنا على حقيبتي (ماشياو جون)
[ko:]마샤오준.[fix] 정말이야.[fix] 여기 책가방에 써 있잖아.[fix]
[ru:]Вот, могу дневник показать.
[zh:]我不骗你 你呢
[en:]I'm not lying, and you?[fix]
[fre:]Je ne mens pas. Et toi ?
[ar:]لست أكذب. واسمك؟
[ko:]난 거짓말 안 해.  네 이름은?[fix]
[ru:]Я не вру. А тебя как?[fix]
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan.
[fre:]Mi Lan.
[ar:](مي لان)
[ko:]미란.[fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань.
[zh:]你叫米兰
[en:]You're Mi Lan?
[fre:]Tu es Mi Lan ?
[ar:]...(أنت (مي لان[fix]
[ru:]Та самая?
[zh:]怎么了 没什么
[en:]So?
[fre:]Et alors ?
[ar:]وإن أكن؟ - ...لا شيء -[fix]
[ko:]네가 미란이야?[fix] 왜?[fix]
[ru:]Что?
[zh:]哎 你不是老在家住吧
[en:]Nothing. Uh, you don't spend much time at home?
[fre:]Non, rien. Tu n'es pas souvent chez toi, hein ?[fix]
[ar:]أنت لا تقضين وقتا كثيرا بالبيت
[ru:]Нет, ничего. Ты постоянно дома сидишь, да?
[zh:]你怎么知道
[en:]How do you know?
[ar:]كيف تعرف؟
[ru:]Откуда ты знаешь?
[zh:]你们家住5号楼 我去过你们家楼
[en:]You live at No.5. I've been to you building.
[fre:]- Comment tu le sais ? - Tu habites au numéro 5.[fix] Je suis déjà allé dans ton immeuble.[fix]
[ar:]أنت تسكنين في المبنى رقم 5 ذهبتُ إليه من قبل
[ko:]아니야. 그런데 넌 집에서는 별로 지내지 않나보지?[fix] 네가 그걸 어떻게 알아?[fix] 넌 5번지에 살잖아. 그 건물에 가본적이 있어.[fix]
[ru:]Ты живешь в пятом доме. Я в вашем доме бывал.
[zh:]好了你该回家了
[en:]Go home...
[fre:]Rentre chez toi
[ar:]حسنا، عليك العودة للبيت
[ko:]집에 가라...[fix]
[ru:]Иди домой...
[zh:]要不你家长该打你了
[en:]before you get into trouble with your parents.
[fre:]avant que tes parents te grondent.
[ar:]قبل أن يقرر والديك ضربك
[ru:]пока тебя родители не ищут.
[zh:]回去吧
[en:]Go home.
[fre:]Allez, rentre.
[ar:]هيا[fix]
[ko:]네 부모님한테 혼나기 전에,[fix] 집에 가.[fix]
[ru:]Иди домой.
[zh:]哎 哎 我还没说完了
[en:]But I've still got something to say.
[fre:]Mais je dois te dire quelque chose.
[ar:]مهلا، لايزال لدي شيء أخبرك به[fix]
[ko:]아직 할 말 남았어.[fix]
[ru:]Погоди, я еще не все сказал.
[zh:]我忘了一件事
[en:]There's something I forgot.
[fre:]J'ai oublié de te demander...
[ar:]...لقد نسيتُ شيئا[fix]
[ko:]깜박한게 있어.[fix]
[ru:]Я еще спросить хотел...
[zh:]你去过北海吗
[en:]Uh, have you been to Beihai Park?
[fre:]Euh, tu es déjà allée...
[ar:]...هل سبق أن ذهبتِ إلى[fix]
[ko:]음...너 바이하이 공원에 가본적 있어?[fix]
[ru:]Ты еще не была в парке Бэйхай?
[zh:]算了吧你
[en:]Nice try but forget it...
[fre:]Bien essayé, mais laisse tomber, gamin.[fix]
[ar:]بجد، انسى
[ru:]Хорошая попытка, но не забывай...
[zh:]什么北海不北海的
[en:]kid.
[ar:]ماذا تعني بذلك؟[fix]
[ko:]시도는 좋지만, 신경 꺼...[fix] 꼬마야.[fix]
[ru:]что ты еще ребенок.
[zh:]行了 小毛孩回家吧
[en:]Time to little children to go home.
[fre:]C'est l'heure de rentrer pour les petits enfants.
[ar:]حسنا، عد للبيت يا صغير[fix]
[ko:]애들은 집에 갈 시간이야.[fix]
[ru:]В это время маленькие дети должны бежать домой.
[zh:]哎 哎
[en:]So...
[fre:]Alors...
[ar:]...إذن[fix]
[ru:]Так...
[zh:]那你当我姐吗
[en:]you will be my elder sister?
[fre:]tu veux bien être ma grande sœur ?
[ar:]ستكونين أختي الكبرى؟
[ko:]그런데...[fix] you will be my elder sister? 내 누나 해줄거야?[fix]
[ru:]ты будешь моей старшей сестрой?
[zh:]你得听话
[en:]Only if you do as I say.
[fre:]Que si tu m'obéis.
[ar:]ستنفذ ما أقول؟
[ru:]Только если ты будешь делать то, что я говорю.[fix]
[zh:]保证听
[en:]I promise.
[fre:]Promis.
[ar:]أقسم
[ru:]Договорились.
[zh:]赶紧回家
[en:]Ok, then run off home now.
[fre:]OK, alors rentre chez toi.
[ru:]Ладно, а теперь беги домой.
[zh:]成
[en:]OK!
[fre:]OK !
[ar:]إذن عد للبيت بسرعة - حسنا -[fix]
[ko:]내가 하라는대로만 하면.[fix] 그럴게.[fix]
[ru:]Бегу.
[zh:]以后不准再到街上追女孩了
[en:]And no more picking up girls on the street!
[fre:]Et arrête de draguer les filles dans la rue ![fix]
[ar:]لا تتعرف على الفتيات في الشارع !بعد الآن[fix]
[ko:]좋아, 그럼 이제 집으로 뛰어가.[fix] 알았어![fix] 그리고 더 이상 길거리에서 여자애들 꼬시지 마![fix]
[ru:]И больше никаких приставаний к девушкам на улице!
[zh:]我向毛主席保证 我这头一回
[en:]I swear before Chairman Mao this was my first time.
[fre:]Je jure devant le Président Mao que c'était la première fois.
[ar:](أقسم بالزعيم (ماو تلك كانت أول مرة[fix]
[ko:]마오 주석 앞에서 맹세컨데,  이번이 처음이야.[fix]
[ru:]Клянусь Председателем Мао, это было в первый раз!
[zh:]再见 再见
[en:]Bye!
[fre:]Bye !
[ar:]مع السلامة - مع السلامة -
[ru:]Пока!
[zh:]哎 我可真来找你啊
[en:]Uh, can I really come visit you?
[fre:]Euh, je pourrais vraiment venir te voir ?
[ar:]سآتي لزيارتك حقا
[ko:]Bye! 잘 가![fix] 정말로 너 만나러 와도 되는거지?[fix]
[ru:]Ой, забыл. Я правда могу к тебе прийти?
[zh:]真是你爸的好儿子
[en:]You really are your father's son, you!
[fre:]T'es vraiment le fils de ton père, toi !
[ar:]!أنت فعلا ولد أبوك
[ko:]너 정말로 니 아빠랑 똑같구나.[fix]
[ru:]Вот уж действительно - весь в папашу!
[zh:]他是年年不回家
[en:]He's never at home...[fix]
[fre:]Il n'est jamais à la maison
[ru:]Того никогда дома нет...[fix]
[zh:]你是天天不回家
[en:]and neither are you.
[fre:]et toi non plus.
[ar:]لا يعود للبيت لسنوات ولا أراك لأيام[fix]
[ko:]니 아빠는 집에 안 붙어있지...[fix] 너도 마찬가지고.[fix]
[ru:]и этого не дождешься!
[zh:]真把这家当旅馆了
[en:]You treat this place like a hotel...
[fre:]Tu te crois à l'hôtel ici ?
[ar:]تعتبر هذا البيت فندقاً !وأنا خادمة[fix]
[ko:]여기가 호텔인줄 알아...?[fix]
[ru:]Живут как в гостинице,
[zh:]把我当老妈子
[en:]and me like a maid.
[fre:]Tu me prends pour une bonne ?
[ru:]а я здесь прислуга.
[zh:]美得你
[en:]Aren't you something else!
[fre:]Tu es incorrigible !
[ar:]عجيب أنت
[ko:]난 하녀고?[fix] 지 아빠랑 똑같아![fix]
[ru:]А чем ты лучше меня?!
[zh:]给我弄点水
[en:]Get me some water.
[fre:]Donne-moi de l'eau.
[ar:]أحضر لي ماء[fix]
[ko:]물이나 떠 와.[fix]
[ru:]Принеси мне воды.
[zh:]拿碗
[en:]And a bowl!
[fre:]Et un bol !
[ar:]في وعاء
[ko:]접시에![fix]
[ru:]В миске!
[zh:]烫死我 你
[en:]Trying to scald me to death?!
[fre:]Tu cherches à m'ébouillanter ?
[ar:]تحاول تحرقني؟
[ko:]화상 입혀서 죽게 하려는거야?![fix]
[ru:]Ты что - обварить меня хотел?
[zh:]妈 我不
[en:]No.
[fre:]Non.
[ar:]لم افعل يا أمي
[ru:]Нет.
[zh:]气死我了 你 你
[en:]You make me so angry.
[fre:]Tu me mets vraiment en colère.
[ar:]اللعنة، أنت تثير غضبي
[ko:]그러지 마요.[fix] 니가 날 화나게 만들잖아.[fix]
[ru:]Ты меня достал сегодня.
[zh:]我不了 妈
[en:]No, Mom.
[fre:]Non, maman.
[ar:]لم افعل يا أمي[fix]
[ru:]Нет, мам.
[zh:]你 你
[zh:]我 我打死你
[en:]I'll kill you.
[fre:]Je vais te tuer !
[ar:]...سـ...سـ[fix] !سأضربك
[ko:]그만, 엄마.[fix] 이 죽일 놈아.[fix]
[ru:]Я тебя убью!
[zh:]我打死你
[en:]I'm going to give you a beating!
[fre:]Je vais te passer à tabac !
[ru:]Сейчас ты у меня получишь!
[zh:]妈 我不了
[en:]No, Mom.[fix]
[fre:]Non, maman.
[ru:]Мама, не надо![fix]
[zh:]我 我
[en:]Don't, Ma.
[fre:]Non, 'man.
[ar:]!سأضربك !لم افعل يا أمي -[fix]
[ko:]흠씬 패줄거다.[fix] 그만, 엄마.[fix] 엄마, 이러지 마.[fix]
[ru:]Не надо!
[zh:]打死你
[ar:]!سـ...سأضربك حتى الموت[fix]
[en:]No, don't hit me.
[fre:]Non, ne me frappe pas.
[ar:]!لا تضربيني يا أمي
[ru:]Не бей меня!
[zh:]天天不着家
[en:]You're never here.[fix]
[fre:]Tu n'es jamais là !
[ar:]...كل يوم
[ru:]Тебя никогда нет![fix]
[zh:]你天天不着家
[en:]You're never home, you little son of a bitch.
[fre:]Tu n'es jamais à la maison, espèce de vaurien !
[ar:]بعيد عن البيت كل يوم غبي[fix]
[ko:]때리지 마요.[fix] 왜 집에 안 붙어 있어?[fix] 왜 안 붙어 있어, 이 썩을 놈아.[fix]
[ru:]Никогда нет дома, маленький сукин сын!
[zh:]你成天成天等现成的
[ar:]طوال اليوم انتظر مجيئك
[zh:]你小王八犊子 你
[en:]You little son of a bitch.
[fre:]Vaurien !
[ar:]يا ابن العاهرة[fix]
[ko:]썩을 놈.[fix]
[ru:]Ты маленький сукин сын!
[zh:]你就 你就跟那些坏孩子去混去吧
[en:]You hang out with those bad kids.
[fre:]Tu traînes avec ces voyous.
[ar:]دائما تتسكع مع أولئك الفتيان الفاسدين[fix]
[ko:]못된 놈들하고 어울려 다니기나 하고.[fix]
[ru:]Постоянно болтаешься со всякой шпаной.
[zh:]你早晚 你就上公安局去作客
[en:]One day I know you'll end up in jail.
[fre:]Un jour, je suis sûre que tu finiras en prison,
[ar:]مآلك السجن عاجلا أم آجلا[fix]
[ko:]나중에 넌 감옥 갈거야, 이 놈아.[fix]
[ru:]Вот увидишь, однажды это кончится тюрьмой,
[zh:]没人心疼
[en:]and no one will sympathize.
[fre:]et personne ne t'apportera à manger.
[ar:]ولن يبالي أحد[fix]
[ko:]그래도 아무도 동정 안해.[fix]
[ru:]и я тебе передачи носить не буду!
[zh:]你看 你老师留了信
[en:]This is a letter from your teacher.
[fre:]C'est une lettre de ton professeur.
[ar:]هذه رسالة من معلمك
[ko:]네 선생님한테 편지 왔다.[fix]
[ru:]Вот записка от твоего учителя.
[zh:]你看看 哪 你看看
[en:]Read it. Read it!
[fre:]Lis-la ! Vas-y, lis-la !
[ar:]!اقرأها. اقرأها[fix]
[ko:]읽어 봐. 읽어 봐![fix]
[ru:]Почитай. Почитай!
[zh:]人家别人家的孩子
[en:]Other children...
[fre:]Les autres enfants
[ar:]...أولاد الناس[fix]
[ru:]Другие дети
[zh:]人家一放学就回去做功课
[en:]come home to do their homework after school.
[fre:]rentrent chez eux pour faire leurs devoirs après l'école.
[ar:]يعودون للبيت مباشرة بعد المدرسة ويقومون بواجباتهم المنزلية[fix]
[ko:]다른 애들은...[fix] 학교 끝나면 숙제 하려고 집에 오는데,[fix]
[ru:]идут после школы домой, домашнее задание делать.
[zh:]你呢
[en:]But you?
[fre:]Mais toi ?
[ar:]أما أنت؟[fix]
[ru:]А ты?
[zh:]天不黑你就不回来
[en:]It's dark and you're still not home!
[fre:]Il fait nuit, et tu es toujours dehors !
[ar:]لا تعود إلا بالليل
[ru:]На улице темнота, а его и в помине нет!
[zh:]你干啥去了 你
[en:]What's going on, huh?!
[fre:]Qu'est-ce qu'il ne va pas, hein ?
[ar:]ماذا تفعل  بحق الجحيم حتى ذلك الوقت؟[fix]
[ko:]넌 뭐야?[fix] 어두워져도, 집구석에 들어오질 않아![fix] 뭐 하고 다니는거야, 응?![fix]
[ru:]Это как называется?!
[zh:]干脆
[en:]Why don't you...
[fre:]Pourquoi tu...
[ru:]Почему ты...
[zh:]就跟你爸一样
[en:]be exactly like your father...
[fre:]ne ferais pas comme ton père...
[ar:]...لمَ لا تكن مثل أبيك[fix]
[ko:]왜...[fix] 니 아빠랑 하는 짓이 똑같아...?[fix]
[ru:]ведешь себя как твой отец
[zh:]都别回家
[en:]and never come home?
[ar:].ولا تعد أبدا
[ru:]и носа домой не кажешь?
[zh:]滚蛋
[en:]Get out, go!
[fre:]et ne plus jamais revenir à la maison ? Dégage ![fix]
[ar:]!اغرب! اخرج من هنا[fix]
[ru:]Убирайся отсюда!
[zh:]走
[en:]Go!
[fre:]Pars !
[ko:]집에도 안 들어오고.[fix] 나가![fix] 나가![fix]
[ru:]Иди, гуляй!
[zh:]自由吧 你们
[en:]You're free.
[fre:]Tu es libre.
[ar:]أنت حر الآن[fix]
[ru:]Ты свободен!
[zh:]你上公安局去做客去吧 你
[en:]Go visit the police whenever.
[fre:]Va rendre visite à la police.
[ar:]فاذهب لزيارة الشرطة متى شئتَ[fix]
[ko:]니 맘대로 해.[fix] 아무 때나 경찰서로 가버려.[fix]
[ru:]Иди, пусть тебя полиция заберет.
[zh:]你搬到公安局去吧 你
[en:]Why don't you just move directly to jail?!
[fre:]Pourquoi tu ne vas pas directement en prison ?
[ar:]!اسكن عندهم إن أردتَ[fix]
[ko:]왜 경찰서 갈 짓만 골라 하는거야?![fix]
[ru:]А можешь прямо в тюрьму топать.
[zh:]哎呀
[zh:]你妈妈 我呀
[en:]I'm an educated women...
[fre:]Je suis une femme qui a de l'éducation...
[ar:]...أتعلم أن أمك[fix]
[ko:]난 배운 여자야...[fix]
[ru:]Я же образованная женщина,
[zh:]是一个有文化有教养的人
[en:]with a proper upbringing.
[fre:]avec de l'amour propre.
[ar:]امرأة متعلمة ذات تربية سليمة[fix]
[ko:]가정 교육도 잘 받고 자랐고.[fix]
[ru:]с хорошим воспитанием
[zh:]跟你爸随军以后
[en:]but I've been a "dependent"...
[fre:]Mais je suis devenue "dépendante"
[ar:]...ولكن منذ أن انضم والدك للجيش
[ko:]그런데 네 아버지가 군대에 간 뒤로,[fix]
[ru:]но мой статус - "иждивенка".
[zh:]当了家属
[en:]since your dad joined the army.[fix]
[fre:]depuis que ton père s'est engagé dans l'armée.
[ar:]لم أكن إلا مجرد ربة منزل[fix]
[ru:]И все потому, что твой отец пошел служить в армию.[fix]
[zh:]我是家属的料吗 我
[en:]Is that all I deserve? Me?
[fre:]C'est tout ce que je mérite ? Hein ?
[ar:]أنا هكذا فقط؟[fix]
[ko:]난 '하인'이 다 됐어.[fix] 내가 왜 이런 대접을 받아야 해? 내가?[fix]
[ru:]И это все, что я заслужила? И ничего больше?
[zh:]气急了我把这房子都给烧了 我
[en:]I'm so furious... I'd like to burn down the house.
[fre:]Je suis si en colère... Je voudrais foutre le feu à cette maison.
[ar:]أريد حرق البيت من شدة غضبي[fix]
[ko:]아주 화가 나... 이 집에 불을 지르고 싶어.[fix]
[ru:]Сил моих больше нет... Так бы и подпалила этот дом!
[zh:]你们马家没一个好种
[en:]I can see your father in you and you in him.
[fre:]Je peux voir ton père en toi, et toi en lui.
[ar:]عائلة (ما) لم يسبق أن قاموا بتربية ولد مهذب
[ko:]널 보면 네 아버지를 보는 듯 하고,  네 아버지를 보면 널 보는 듯해.[fix]
[ru:]А теперь еще один такой же растет.
[zh:]从小看到大
[ar:]...وكنت أرى منذ صغرك
[zh:]你就跟你那贼爸爸是一路货色呀 你
[en:]Peas out of the same rotten pod you are.
[fre:]Vous êtes bien des fruits pourris du même arbre.
[ar:]أنك أنت وأبوك الغبي كالطيور على أشكالها تقع[fix]
[ko:]둘 다 썩은 꼬투리 속에 있는 콩 같아.[fix]
[ru:]Горошина из того же гнилого стручка.
[zh:]你要是一只小鸡
[en:]If you were a chicken,
[fre:]Si tu avais été un poulet,
[ar:]لو كنتَ دجاجة لذبحتُك[fix]
[ko:]네가 닭이라면,[fix]
[ru:]Если бы ты был цыпленком,
[zh:]我把你杀了
[zh:]我也不吃那肉
[en:]I wouldn't even eat your meat.
[fre:]je ne voudrai même pas de ta viande.
[ar:].ولن آكل لحمك حتى[fix]
[ru:]я бы тебя съесть побрезговала.
[zh:]恨死我了
[en:]I hate you that much.
[fre:]Je te déteste à ce point.
[ar:]!أكرهك[fix]
[ko:]네 놈을 잡아먹었을 거야.[fix] 네가 아주 지긋지긋해.[fix]
[ru:]Ненавижу, ненавижу вас!
[zh:]恨死我了 你
[en:]You hate me too, don't you...
[fre:]Et toi aussi tu me détestes, pas vrai ?
[ar:]وأنت تكرهني أيضا
[ko:]너도 내가 밉지, 그렇지...?[fix]
[ru:]И вы меня ненавидите точно так же.
[zh:]你咋就不跟你妈妈争口气呢
[en:]When have you ever done anything to make me proud?
[fre:]C'était quand la dernière fois que tu m'as rendu fière ?
[ar:]متى فعلتَ شيئا يجعلني فخورة؟[fix]
[ko:]내가 자랑스러워할 만한 일을 언제 네가 한 적이 있어?[fix]
[ru:]Ты когда-нибудь сделал что-нибудь, чтобы я тобой гордилась?
[zh:]真是让我太失望了
[en:]You disappoint me.
[fre:]Tu m'as déçu.
[ar:]لم تفعل إلا تخييب ظني[fix]
[ru:]Ты никчемный сын!
[zh:]太让我后悔了 你
[en:]I regret ever having had you.
[fre:]Je regrette même de t'avoir mise au monde.
[ar:].وجعلي أكرهك
[ko:]넌 날 실망만시켰어.[fix] 네 놈을 낳은 것도 후회되.[fix]
[ru:]Я жалею, что родила тебя.
[zh:]王八犊子
[en:]You bastard.
[fre:]Sale bâtard !
[ar:]أيها النذل
[ko:]이 썩을 놈아.[fix]
[ru:]Ублюдок.
[zh:]你妈我呀
[ar:]لم يسبق لي أن لعنت أحد[fix]
[zh:]从来都不会骂人
[en:]I never hit or cursed anyone...
[fre:]Je n'avais jamais tapé ou maudit quelqu'un
[ru:]Я никого пальцем не трогала и не проклинала
[zh:]更不会打人
[ar:]ناهيك عن ضرب أحد
[ko:]네 아빠랑 너와 같이 살기 전에는[fix]
[zh:]都是让你们这姓马的给我逼出来的
[en:]before your father and you came along.
[fre:]depuis que ton père et toi êtes arrivés.
[ar:]!إلى أن جئت أنت ووالدك[fix]
[ko:]난 누구를 때려보지도 않았고,  누구에게 싫은 소리 한 적도 없어.[fix]
[ru:]пока вы в моей жизни не появились.
[zh:]你王八犊子
[en:]Turtle spawn!
[fre:]Petit démon !
[ar:]!وغدان
[ru:]Икра черепахи!
[zh:]你给我滚
[en:]Get out of here! Oh! Aaah!
[fre:]Dégage de là !
[ar:]!اخرج[fix]
[ko:]이 미련한 놈아![fix] 여기서 나가!.... 아!...아..아![fix]
[ru:]Убирайся отсюда! Ой... Аааа!!!
[zh:]我妈妈一怒之下生下了她的第二个儿子
[en:]In a fit of anger, my mother gave birth to my brother.
[fre:]Dans un moment de colère, ma mère a donné naissance à mon petit frère.
[ar:]بنوبة غضب، ولدت أمي ابنها الثاني[fix]
[ko:]너무 화를 내신 나머지, 어머니는 내 동생을 낳았다.[fix]
[ru:]Вот так, в приступе гнева моя мать и родила моего брата.
[zh:]哥儿几个是用食堂买菜的平板车
[en:]My mates took her to the army hospital...
[fre:]Mes amis l'ont amenée à l'hôpital de l'armée
[ar:]أخذوها أصدقائي لمستشفى الجيش على ظهر عربة[fix]
[ko:]내 친구들이 어머니를  자전거 짐받이에 싣고...[fix]
[ru:]Мои друзья отвезли ее в армейский госпиталь
[zh:]把妈妈送进了陆军总医院
[en:]on the back of a bicycle cart.
[fre:]sur un rickshaw,
[ru:]на багажнике велосипеда.
[zh:]因为司机班的那辆吉普
[en:]'cause the driver...
[fre:]parce que le chauffeur
[ar:]لأن السائق المداوم بذلك الوقت لم يستطع تشغيل السيارة[fix]
[ko:]군 병원으로 모시고 갔다.[fix] 왜냐하면 친구들 중에는...[fix]
[ru:]Потому что водитель
[zh:]怎么也打不着火
[en:]couldn't get the jeep started.
[fre:]n'arrivait pas à démarrer la jeep.
[ko:]지프를 운전할 수 있는 사람이  없었기 때문이었다.[fix]
[ru:]не смог завести свою машину
[zh:]我当时想
[en:]I thought.
[fre:]Je pensais,
[ar:]...قلتُ ببالي[fix] أي استعداد للحرب هذا؟[fix]
[ru:]Я тогда подумал
[zh:]这种战备观念
[en:]what sort of war-preparedness is this?
[fre:]quel genre de préparatifs de guerre est ce ?
[ru:]что же это за военная промышленность такая?
[zh:]要是帝国主义发动突然袭击
[en:]An attack by the imperialists...
[fre:]Une attaque des impérialistes
[ar:]...لو شن الامبرياليون هجوم مفاجيء
[ko:]나는 생각했다.[fix] 전시에 대한 대비가 이랬다면?[fix] 제국주의자들이 공격 했을 때...[fix]
[ru:]Если бы на нас напали империалисты
[zh:]还不全他妈完蛋
[en:]and we'd be dead meat.
[fre:]et on est de la viande froide.
[ar:]لكنا أُبدنا[fix]
[ko:]우리는 죽게 될 것이다.[fix]
[ru:]мы были бы мертвым мясом.
[zh:]妈妈每次打我总要骂上爸爸
[en:]Ma always cursed Dad when she was beating me.
[fre:]Maman maudissait toujours papa quand elle me battait,
[ar:]كلما ضربتني أمي تلعن أبي
[ko:]엄마는 나를 때릴 때마다, 아빠를 저주했다.[fix]
[ru:]Мама всегда проклинала отца, когда била меня,
[zh:]这回爸爸真让她给骂回来了
[en:]but her curses brought him home this time.
[fre:]mais ses malédictions l'ont ramenée à la maison.
[ar:]لكن لعناتها هذه المرة أعادته للبيت فعلا[fix]
[ko:]그러나 이번에 한 저주는 아빠를 집으로 오게 했다.[fix]
[ru:]но на сей раз ее проклятия вернули его в семью.
[zh:]长大懂事后我才恍然大悟
[en:]When I got older I realized my brother's birth...[fix]
[fre:]Quand je fus plus grand, j'ai réalisé que la naissance de mon frère
[ar:]...عندما كبرتُ، أدركتُ[fix]
[ru:]Когда я стал старше, я понял, что рождение моего брата[fix]
[zh:]弟弟的出生与我偷开爸爸的 抽屉玩那只大气球有关系
[en:]had to do with my breaking into Dad's drawer...
[fre:]avait un rapport avec ma fouille dans le tiroir de papa
[ar:]أن لولادة أخي علاقة باقتحامي لدرج أبي[fix]
[ko:]내가 나이가 더 들었을 때,  나는 내 동생의 출생이...[fix] 내가 아빠의 책상 서랍을 열어 그 큰 풍선(주: 콘돔)을 터뜨렸던 일과[fix]
[ru:]устроил я, пошарив в запертом отцовском ящике.
[zh:]因为气球被扎漏了
[en:]and puncturing that big balloon.
[fre:]et la crevaison de ce gros ballon.
[ar:].وبثقب ذاك البالون[fix]
[ko:]관련되어 있었음을 깨달았다.[fix]
[ru:]и проколов тот большой воздушный шарик.
[zh:]六条的那孩子被我们 打成重伤住了一个月的院
[en:]That kid from Liutiao was in hospital for a month.
[fre:]Le gamin de Liutiao a été à l'hôpital pendant un mois.[fix]
[ar:]فتى الحارة السادسة الذي ضربته ظل بالمستشفى لشهر[fix]
[ko:]류차오 거리에서 다친 그 아이는  한달 동안 병원 신세를 졌다.[fix]
[ru:]Тот парень из банды Лютяо лежал в больнице больше месяца.
[zh:]但他们不服
[en:]His mates sent word...
[fre:]Ses amis nous ont envoyé un mot
[ar:]لكنهم لازالوا لم يحترمونا بما يكفي[fix]
[ko:]그의 패거리들이 전갈을 보냈다.[fix]
[ru:]Его друзья сообщили нам
[zh:]找人带话来要跟我们打架
[en:]that...
[fre:]comme quoi
[ar:]أرسلوا أحدا يبلغنا أنهم يريدون قتالنا[fix]
[ko:]월요일날...[fix]
[ru:]что забивают нам стрелку
[zh:]时间是礼拜一
[en:]there'd be a rumble on Monday...
[fre:]il y aurait un règlement de compte lundi,[fix]
[ar:]الوقت: يوم الأثنين[fix]
[ru:]в понедельник
[zh:]地点约在芦沟桥
[en:]at the Marco Polo Bridge.
[fre:]sous le pont Marco Polo.
[ar:]المكان: جسر ماركو بولو
[ru:]на мосту Марко Поло.
[zh:]可带上百人
[en:]We could each take 100 people.
[fre:]On pouvait emmener chacun 100 personnes.
[ar:]يمكن لكلا الطرفين الذهاب بـ 100 فرد[fix]
[ko:]마르코 폴로 다리에서[fix] 패싸움을 열자는 것이었다.[fix] 각각 100명씩 참가할 수 있다고 했다.[fix]
[ru:]Каждая сторона имела право выставить до сотни человек.
[zh:]我不由得紧张起来
[en:]I couldn't help feeling nervous...[fix]
[fre:]Je ne pouvais m'empêcher d'être nerveux,
[ar:]لم أستطع منع نفسي من التوتر[fix]
[ru:]Я сильно нервничал,[fix]
[zh:]后悔不该逞英雄拍那孩子一砖头
[en:]and regretted trying so much to be a hero with that brick.
[fre:]et de regretter d'avoir essayé de passer pour un héros avec cette brique.
[ar:]وندمتُ على محاولتي الجادة لأكون بطلا بتلك الطوبة[fix]
[ko:]난 초조하지 않을 수 없었고...[fix] 벽돌을 가지고 영웅이 되려고 했던 일이  무척 후회스러웠다.[fix]
[ru:]потому что они потребовали,
[zh:]因为对方点头非我参加不可
[en:]They demanded my participation.
[fre:]Ils m'ont demandé d'y participer.
[ar:]لأن العصابة الأخرى الآن تصر على وجودي[fix]
[ko:]그들은 내가 꼭 나올 것을 요구했다.[fix]
[ru:]чтобы "герой с кирпичом" обязательно  был там.
[zh:]我想到米兰
[en:]My thoughts turned to Mi Lan.[fix]
[fre:]Mes pensées se sont tournées vers Mi Lan.
[ar:](تحولت أفكاري إلى (مي لان[fix]
[ru:]И я сразу подумал о Ми Лань.[fix]
[zh:]想马上见到她
[en:]I had to see her immediately.[fix]
[fre:]Je devais la voir immédiatement.
[ar:]أردت الذهاب لرؤيتها فوراً[fix]
[ru:]Мне хотелось увидеть ее немедленно.[fix]
[zh:]说不定这就是生离死别
[en:]Maybe it would be the last time.
[fre:]Ce serait peut-être la dernière fois.
[ar:]لأني لم أكن متأكدا .أذلك سيكون وداعي الأخير أم لا[fix]
[ko:]미란만이 생각났다.[fix] 그녀를 즉시 만나봐야만 한다.[fix] 어쩌면 이번이 마지막이 될지도 모르니까.[fix]
[ru:]Потому что это могло быть в последний раз.
[zh:]那头让我过去
[en:]The bastard's here. Let me go see him.
[fre:]Le bâtard est là. Laisse-moi aller le voir.[fix]
[ar:]يريدوني أن اذهب إلى هناك[fix]
[ru:]Очкастый ублюдок уже здесь. Мне надо с ним поговорить.
[zh:]那过去干嘛呀
[en:]What for?
[fre:]Pourquoi ?
[ar:]لماذا؟
[ko:]저 새끼들 왔군.  내가 갔다 올게.[fix] 뭐하러?[fix]
[ru:]Зачем?
[zh:]机灵点
[en:]Act smart...[fix]
[fre:]Agissez prudemment,
[ar:]كونوا أذكياء وانتبهوا لإشارتي[fix]
[ru:]Попросили большие люди.[fix]
[zh:]看一下我手势
[en:]and watch for my signal.
[fre:]et attendez mon signal.
[ko:]Act smart... 깨끗하게 하자고...[fix] 내 신호 기다려.[fix]
[ru:]Ждите моего сигнала.
[zh:]你是马小军
[en:]Are you Ma Xiaojun?
[fre:]C'est toi Ma Xiaojun ?
[ar:]أأنت (ماشياو جون)؟ - أجل -
[ko:]네가 마샤오준이냐?[fix]
[ru:]Это ты Ма Сяоцзюнь?
[zh:]啊
[en:]Yeah!
[fre:]Ouais !
[ru:]Да.
[zh:]那板砖是你拍的
[en:]Was it you who hit him with a brick?
[fre:]C'est toi qui l'as frappé avec une brique ?
[ar:]أنت صاحب الطوبة؟[fix]
[ru:]Это ты его кирпичом приложил?
[zh:]是 是我
[en:]yes.
[fre:]Oui.
[ar:]أجل[fix]
[ko:]응.[fix] 벽돌로 깠다는게 너야?[fix] 응.[fix]
[ru:]Ага.
[zh:]和了
[ar:]!سلام[fix]
[zh:]这场颇费苦心安排的架
[en:]The rumble never got underway...
[fre:]La bataille n'a jamais eu lieu,
[ko:]모든 계획에도 불구하고...[fix]
[ru:]Разборки всегда проходят совсем не так
[zh:]就这么没打起来
[en:]despite all the planning.
[fre:]malgré le plan préparé.
[ar:]بالرغم من التخطيط السابق المجهد لم يحدث القتال[fix]
[ru:]как планировалось.
[zh:]我们拥进了老莫
[en:]We went to the old Moscow Restaurant.
[ar:](ذهبنا لمحل العجوز (موو
[ru:]Мы отправились в старый ресторан "Москва"
[zh:]就是现在的莫斯科餐厅
[fre:]On est tous allés au vieux restaurant moscovite.[fix]
[ar:](يعرف اليوم باسم (مطعم موسكو
[ko:]패싸움은 일어나지 않았다.[fix] 우리는 오래된 모스크바 식당으로 갔다.[fix]
[zh:]四海之内皆兄弟
[en:]Brothers of the 4 Seas & 5 Continents...
[fre:]Frères des 4 Mers et des 5 Continents,
[ar:]الكل إخوة في البحار الأربعة "
[ko:]4해(海)와 5대륙의 형제들이여...[fix]
[ru:]Братья четырех морей и пяти континентов,
[zh:]五洲震荡和为贵
[en:]the supreme virtue is - unity!
[fre:]la vertu suprême est : L'Unité !
[ar:]وعند اضطراب العالم "يكون السلام الفضيلة الأسمى
[ko:]- 최고의 덕(德)은?...단결![fix]
[ru:]высшее достоинство - это единство!
[zh:]喝
[fre:]Santé !
[ar:]!اشربوا[fix]
[zh:]喝
[en:]Cheers![fix] Cheers!
[fre:]Santé !
[ko:]건배![fix] 건배![fix]
[ru:]Ваше здоровье![fix]
[zh:]正当梨花开遍了天涯
[ar:]عندما تتفتح أزهار الكمثرى بالأرض[fix]
[zh:]河上飘着柔漫的轻纱
[ar:]وضباب خفيف يهب ببطء فوق النهر[fix]
[zh:]喀秋莎站在峻峭的岸上
[ar:]...تقف كاتيوشا على قمة ضفة النهر المرتفعة[fix]
[zh:]我发现了一个规律
[en:]I discovered a rule.[fix]
[fre:]J'ai appris quelque chose...
[ar:]اكتشفتُ قاعدة
[ru:]В тот день я понял одну вещь.[fix]
[zh:]几个人十几个人的遭遇战打得最狠
[en:]With a dozen people...
[fre:]Avec une douzaine de personnes,
[ar:]أشد القتال عنفاً عندما يشارك به العشرات[fix]
[ko:]나는 규칙을 발견했다.[fix] 12명이 싸울때는...[fix]
[ru:]Если вас десяток -
[zh:]也常出人命
[en:]you can fight to death.[fix]
[fre:]tu peux te battre à mort.
[ar:]وسيفقد البعض حياتهم[fix]
[ru:]вы можете поубивать друг друга до смерти[fix]
[zh:]几十人上百人的架却往往打不起来
[en:]With hundreds involved, the fight never gets going.
[fre:]Avec des centaines, la bataille n'a jamais lieu.
[ar:]لكن عندما يشارك المئات لا يبدأ القتال أبدا[fix]
[ko:]죽을 때까지 싸울 수 있다.[fix] 백명이 관련되었을 경우엔, 절대로 싸움이 이루어지지 않는다.[fix]
[ru:]Но если собрались сотни, все спустят на тормозах.
[zh:]因为人勾来的越多
[en:]'Cause the more you drag in...
[ru:]Причем чем вас больше,
[zh:]就越容易勾来熟人
[en:]the more likely it is...
[fre:]Parce que plus tu en ramènes, plus tu as de chances[fix]
[ar:]بزيادة العدد يزيد احتمال أن يعرف البعض أشخاص من الطرف الآخر[fix]
[ko:]왜냐하면, 시간을 끌면 끌수록...[fix] 서로 간에...[fix]
[ru:]тем более вероятно,
[zh:]甚至两拔儿都去勾了同一拔儿人
[en:]that the same people will be friendly with both sides.
[fre:]que ces personnes deviennent amies avec ceux d'en face.
[ar:]أو يحاولوا إقناع نفس الأشخاص بالقتال معهم[fix]
[ru:]что в конце концов побратаетесь.
[zh:]这次就是
[en:]So it was this time.
[fre:]À ce moment-là,
[ar:]هذا ما حصل هذه المرة[fix]
[ru:]Так случилось и на этот раз.
[zh:]两边都去找了当时威震北京的小坏蛋
[en:]We'd both gone for the most fared bully in Peking.
[fre:]le tyran le plus juste de Pékin a vu le jour.
[ar:]ذهبنا كلانا إلى أكثر المجرمين مهابة في بكين[fix]
[ko:]더 친하게 되기 때문이다.[fix] 그 때가 바로 그랬다.[fix] 우리는 서로가 베이징에서  가장 잘나가는 깡패들이라고 여겼다.[fix]
[ru:]Нас примирил самый известный хулиган Пекина.
[zh:]他的确是鼎鼎大名
[en:]He had an awesome reputation.
[fre:]Il avait une réputation exceptionnelle,
[ar:]كان له سمعة رائعة
[ru:]У него была приводящая в трепет репутация.
[zh:]人人都知道几个关于他胆大手黑的传说
[en:]and everyone talked about his underhanded ways.
[fre:]et tout le monde parlait de ses actes sournois.
[ar:]والكل كان يعلم قصص أساليبه الجريئة والقاسية[fix]
[ko:]그는 위엄있는 명성을 갖고 있었다.[fix] 그리고 그의 비밀스런 일처리  방식에 대해 말들이 많았다.[fix]
[ru:]Все только и говорили о его коварстве и хитроумии.
[zh:]这是我第一次
[en:]This was my first...
[fre:]C'était ma première
[ru:]Это была моя первая...
[zh:]也是唯一次见到他
[en:]and last encounter with him.
[fre:]et dernière rencontre avec lui.
[ar:]كان هذا لقائي الأول والوحيد معه[fix]
[ko:]그를 만난 건 그 때가...[fix] 처음이자 마지막이었다.[fix]
[ru:]и последняя встреча с ним.
[zh:]这事儿过后不久
[en:]He was later...
[fre:]Plus tard, il a été tué
[ar:]، بعد ذلك بوقت قريب[fix]
[ru:]Вскоре его убили
[zh:]他就被几个十五六岁 想取代他的孩子扎死
[en:]killed by teenage punks who wanted to take his place.
[fre:]par des adolescents rebelles qui voulaient sa place.
[ar:]قُتل على يد مراهقين أرادوا أخذ مكانه[fix]
[ko:]얼마 뒤, 그는...[fix] 그의 자리를 탐낸  10대 애송이에 의해 살해되었다.[fix]
[ru:]какие-то отмороженные малолетки, метившие на его место.
[zh:]我只记得他的手特柔软
[en:]All I remember is that his hand was so soft,
[fre:]Tout ce dont je me rappelle, c'est que se main était douce,
[ar:]لا أتذكر إلا نعومة يديه
[ru:]Все, что я помню - его рука была очень мягкая
[zh:]像女人的
[en:]it was like a girl's.
[fre:]comme celle d'une fille.
[ar:]كيدين فتاة
[ko:]그에 대해 기억나는 것이라곤, 그의 손이 아주 부드러웠다는 것이다.[fix] 마치 여자의 손처럼.[fix]
[ru:]как у девчонки.
[zh:]我终于没出意外
[en:]So I got off without a scratch.
[fre:]Je m'en suis donc tiré sans une égratignure.
[ar:]بالنهاية، خرجتُ بلا أي جرح[fix]
[ru:]Так что я вышел из этого дела без единой царапины.
[zh:]但另一件事却使我怒上心头
[en:]But something else was driving me completely mad.
[fre:]Mais quelque chose d'autre me tourmentait.
[ar:]لكن شيئا آخرا كان يصيبني بالجنون
[ko:]그래서 나는 상처 하나 없이 돌아왔다.[fix] 그러나 다른 일로 나는  완전히 돌아버릴 지경이었다.[fix]
[ru:]Но была еще и другая проблема, которая сводила меня с ума.
[zh:]我总是寻不见米兰
[en:]Mi Lan seemed to be avoiding me.
[fre:]Mi Lan avait l'air de m'éviter.[fix]
[ar:](لم أكن قادرا على إيجاد (مي لان
[ru:]Ми Лань, казалось, избегала меня.
[zh:]她似乎存心在躲着我
[ar:]وبدا أنها تتجنبني عمداً[fix]
[ko:]미란이 나를 피하는 것처럼 보였던 것이다.[fix]
[ru:]Я опять никак не мог ее застать.
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan.
[fre:]Mi Lan.
[ar:]مي لان)؟)[fix]
[ko:]미란.[fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань.
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan!
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:]مي لان)؟)
[ko:]미란![fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань!
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan!
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:]مي لان)؟)
[ko:]미란![fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань!
[zh:]谁呀
[en:]Who's there?
[fre:]Qui est là ?
[ar:]من هناك؟[fix]
[ko:]누구야?[fix]
[ru:]Кто там?
[zh:]哦 是你呀
[en:]Oh, it's you.
[fre:]Oh, c'est toi.
[ar:]أوه، هذا أنت[fix]
[ko:]아, 너구나.[fix]
[ru:]А, это ты...
[zh:]上这边来吧
[en:]Come over here.
[fre:]Viens par là.
[ar:]تعال هنا[fix]
[ko:]이리로 와.[fix]
[ru:]Иди сюда.
[zh:]你怎么没去上课啊
[en:]Why aren't you in school?
[fre:]Pourquoi tu n'es pas à l'école ?
[ar:]لماذا لست بالمدرسة؟
[ru:]А ты почему не в школе?
[zh:]那什么
[en:]Uh...
[fre:]Euh...
[ar:]بلا سبب
[ru:]А это...
[zh:]我们老师病了 上午改自习 我就溜出来了
[en:]Teacher's sick. We're having study period. I snuck out.
[fre:]Le prof est malade, alors on a du temps pour étudier. J'ai séché.
[ar:]معلمنا مريض، ولدينا حصة بعد الظهر فخرجت متسللا
[ko:]왜 학교 안 갔니?[fix] 음...[fix] 선생님이 아프셔. 수업시간 중이지만 빠져나왔어.[fix]
[ru:]Учитель заболел. Нас распустили, я шел мимо, и думаю - дай зайду.
[zh:]你来找过我吗
[en:]Have you been by before?
[fre:]Tu es déjà venu ici ?
[ar:]هل جئت للبحث عني؟
[ko:]전에도 온 적 있니?[fix]
[ru:]Ты ко мне раньше заходил?
[zh:]没有
[en:]No.
[fre:]Non.
[ar:]لا
[ru:]Нет.
[zh:]为什么
[en:]Hmph, Why not?
[fre:]Pourquoi ça ?
[ar:]لم لا؟
[ko:]아니.[fix] 음, 근데 오늘은 왜?[fix]
[ru:]Хм... А почему нет?
[zh:]我们快期末考试了
[en:]I've been busy with...
[fre:]J'étais occupé avec...
[ar:]عندنا امتحانات نهائية قريبا[fix]
[ko:]그 동안 기말 시험...[fix]
[ru:]Да я занят был.
[zh:]课程挺紧的
[en:]end of term exams...
[fre:]mes exams de fin d'année...
[ar:]لذا فالحصص مليئة بالدروس[fix]
[ko:]때문에 바빴거든...[fix]
[ru:]Экзамены скоро.
[zh:]所以也没时间来找你
[en:]I haven't had any time.[fix]
[fre:]Je n'avais vraiment pas le temps.
[ar:]ولم يكن لدي وقت لآتي[fix]
[ru:]Времени вообще ни на что не хватает.[fix]
[zh:]我现在太忙
[en:]I've been really busy.
[fre:]J'étais très occupé.
[ar:]كنت مشغولا جدا
[ko:]시간이 없었어.[fix] 정말로 바빴어.[fix]
[ru:]Я правда занят был.
[zh:]实在是忙
[en:]Really busy.
[fre:]Très occupé.
[ar:]مشغول جدا
[ru:]Честное слово.
[zh:]我还想呢
[en:]And I was thinking...
[fre:]Et moi qui pensais...
[ar:]...كنت أتساءل فقط
[ko:]정말로 바빴다고.[fix] 네가 어디로 사라졌을까...[fix]
[ru:]А я думала...
[zh:]怎么见了一面 人就没影了
[en:]where he's disappeared to?
[fre:]Où a-t-il disparu ?
[ar:]لماذا اختفيتَ بعد أن التقينا .بتلك المرة فقط[fix]
[ko:]생각하고 있었어.[fix]
[ru:]куда он подевался?
[zh:]是不是哪儿认了姐姐
[en:]Off meeting other "elder sister"?
[fre:]À la recherche de "sœurs aînées " ?
[ar:]ذهبتَ للقاء "أخوات كبرى" أخريات ارتبطتَ بهن؟[fix]
[ru:]Бегаешь к очередной "старшей сестре"?
[zh:]给绊住了
[zh:]不是 不是
[en:]No, no.
[fre:]Non, non.
[ar:]لا، لا[fix]
[ko:]다른 '누나' 만나고 다닌거 아니야?[fix] 아냐, 아냐.[fix]
[ru:]Нет, нет!
[zh:]我问你
[en:]So...
[fre:]Alors...
[ar:]دعني أسألك
[ru:]Так...
[zh:]你最近没有新认什么人吧
[en:]have you met anyone new lately?
[fre:]tu as rencontré quelqu'un ces derniers temps ?
[ar:]هل التقيت بأحد جديد مؤخرا؟[fix]
[ko:]그럼...[fix] 최근에 누구 새로 만난 사람 있니?[fix]
[ru:]А с какой-нибудь новенькой познакомился?
[zh:]瞧你说的
[ar:]أتمزحين معي؟[fix]
[zh:]好象我除了在大街上闲逛
[en:]Seems like I've nothing better to do!
[fre:]Comme si je n'avais rien de mieux à faire !
[ar:]كل ما افعله هذه الأيام هو قضاء الوقت متسكعا بالشارع[fix]
[ko:]날 보면, 잘해볼 만한 여자도 없는  사람처럼 보이잖아![fix]
[ru:]Мне и без этого есть чем заняться
[zh:]我就不干别的了
[ar:]لم افعل شيئا آخرا[fix] لا شيء
[zh:]绝对没有
[en:]No, definitely not.
[fre:]Non, bien sûr que non.
[ar:]بكل تأكيد[fix]
[ko:]아냐, 정말 아니야.[fix]
[ru:]Нет, правда нет!
[zh:]好吧
[en:]OK!
[fre:]OK !
[ar:]حسنا
[ko:]좋아![fix]
[ru:]Ладно.
[zh:]哎 帮我个忙 成吗
[en:]Give me a hand, would you?
[fre:]Tu peux m'aider ?
[ar:]هلا ساعدتني بهذا؟ - بالتأكيد -[fix]
[ru:]Можешь мне немного помочь?
[zh:]成
[en:]Sure.
[fre:]Bien sûr !
[ru:]Конечно!
[zh:]你到楼道里 把那锅开水拎来
[en:]Fetch that kettle from the hallway?
[fre:]Apporte-moi la bouilloire qui est dans le couloir.
[ar:]أيمكن أن تحضر لي غلاية الماء تلك بالممر؟[fix] بالتأكيد[fix]
[ko:]잠깐 도와줄래?[fix] 물론.[fix] 복도에 가서 주전자 좀 갖다 줄래?[fix]
[ru:]Принеси, пожалуйста, чайник из прихожей.
[zh:]哎 小心点 别烫着
[en:]Careful, don't burn yourself.
[fre:]Attention, ne te brûle pas.
[ar:]انتبه، لا تحرق نفسك[fix]
[ru:]Осторожнее, не обожгись.
[zh:]没问题 放心吧
[en:]No problem. Don't worry.
[fre:]Pas de problème. Ne t'inquiète pas.
[ar:]لا مشكلة لا تقلقي
[ko:]조심해, 데지 말고.[fix] 문제 없어. 걱정 마.[fix]
[ru:]Да без проблем. Не волнуйся.
[zh:]我帮你冲吧
[en:]Let me help you rinse it.
[fre:]Je vais t'aider à les rincer.
[ar:]سأساعدك بغسله
[ru:]Давай помогу тебе сполоснуть.
[zh:]好啊
[en:]Thanks.
[fre:]Merci.
[ar:]حسنا
[ko:]헹구는거 도와줄게.[fix]
[ru:]Спасибо.
[zh:]兑上点凉水
[en:]Put in a bit of cold water first.
[fre:]Mets un peu d'eau froide avant.[fix]
[ar:]ضع قليلا من الماء البارد أولا إلا إن أردت حرقي[fix]
[ru:]Холодной водой разбавить не хочешь?
[zh:]你想烫死我啊 对 对 对
[ar:]صحيح، فهمت[fix]
[ko:]고마워.[fix] 먼저 찬물 좀 섞어.[fix]
[ru:]Ой, да.
[zh:]烫吗
[en:]Oh, Ok. Too hot?[fix]
[fre:]C'est chaud ?
[ar:]حار؟
[zh:]嗯 不烫 浇吧
[en:]No, go ahead!
[fre:]Non, vas-y !
[ar:]لا، جيد
[ko:]어때, 너무 뜨거워?[fix] 아니, 계속해![fix]
[ru:]Не горячо?[fix] Да нет, лей.
[zh:]天可真热
[en:]It's so hot.
[fre:]Il fait si chaud,
[ar:]الجو حار جدا
[ru:]Жарко как.
[zh:]才几月份啦
[en:]And summer's barely begun.
[fre:]et l'été commence juste.
[ar:]والصيف بدأ للتو
[ru:]А лето только началось.
[zh:]你会游泳吗
[en:]Can you swim?
[fre:]Tu sais nager ?
[ar:]تجيدين السباحة؟ - لا -[fix]
[ko:]좀 덥다.[fix] 이제 여름이 시작됐나봐.[fix] 수영할 줄 알아?[fix]
[ru:]Ты плавать умеешь?
[zh:]我不会
[en:]No.
[fre:]Non.
[ru:]Нет.
[zh:]你呢
[en:]And you?
[fre:]Et toi ?
[ar:]وأنت؟
[ru:]А ты?
[zh:]等那天我游给你看吧
[en:]Yes, I'll show you some day.
[fre:]Oui, je te montrerai un jour.
[ar:]أجل، سأريك يوما ما عظيم[fix]
[ko:]아니.[fix] 너는?[fix] 할 줄 알지. 나중에 실력을 보여줄게.[fix]
[ru:]Да. Как-нибудь продемонстрирую.
[zh:]那好啊
[en:]Great.
[fre:]Très bien.
[ru:]Прекрасно.
[zh:]赶明儿我要是掉进水里
[en:]If I fall in...
[fre:]Si je me noie,
[ar:]لو سقطت بالماء أيمكنك أن تأتي لإنقاذي؟[fix]
[ko:]좋아.[fix] 내가 물에 빠지면...[fix]
[ru:]То есть если я упаду в воду,
[zh:]你可以来救我吗
[en:]you can save me then?
[fre:]tu pourras me sauver alors ?
[ar:]بالتأكيد، لا مشكلة[fix]
[ru:]ты меня спасешь?
[zh:]那 那没问题
[en:]You bet...
[fre:]Bien sûr...
[ru:]Готов спорить -
[zh:]不过你个儿太大了 我的技术还得再练练才成
[en:]though you're a bit big for me so I'll have to work out a bit first.
[fre:]mais tu es un peu trop lourde pour moi, alors il faudra que je m'entraîne.
[ar:]لكنك كبيرة قليلا علي فأحتاج للتمرن أولا[fix]
[ko:]그럼 나를 구할 수 있겠네?[fix] 물론...[fix] 내가 감당하기엔 네가 덩치가 좀 크긴 하지만,  그래도 제일 먼저 구해줄거야.[fix]
[ru:]ты для меня слишком тяжелая. Мне придется мышцы качать на озере Шиша.
[zh:]那你就天天上什刹海去练吧
[en:]Every day, in Shisha Lake.
[fre:]Tous les jours, au lac Shisha.
[ar:]حسنا، يمكنك الذهاب لبحيرة (شيشا) كل يوم
[ko:]매일, 신샤 호수에서 놀아야겠군.[fix]
[ru:]А как же школа?
[zh:]那我就不上课啦
[en:]What about school?
[fre:]Et pour l'école ?
[ar:]لكن ماذا عن المدرسة؟
[ko:]방과 후에 어때?[fix]
[ru:]Ну вот, экзамены сдам,
[zh:]等期终考完试
[en:]When I finish with exams, we...
[fre:]Quand j'aurais fini les exams, on...
[ar:]سأنتظر نهاية الامتحانات أولا - ضعه هناك -
[ru:]и сразу же туда.
[zh:]搁那边
[en:]Put it over there.
[fre:]Mets-le là.
[ru:]Может, с тобой поехать?
[zh:]咱俩一块去吧
[en:]Yeah, we can go there together.
[fre:]Ouais, on pourra y aller tous les deux.
[ar:]نعم، يمكننا الذهاب هناك معاً[fix]
[ko:]시험이 끝나서...[fix] 그거 저기다 둬.[fix] 거기 같이 갈 수 있는데.[fix]
[ru:]Поехали.
[zh:]好吧 站那儿别动
[en:]Stand there, don't move.
[fre:]Reste là, ne bouge pas.
[ar:]حسنا، قف هناك ولا تتحرك[fix]
[ko:]거기 서 있어.  움직이지 말고.[fix]
[ru:]- Стой там и не двигайся. - Стою
[zh:]哎
[en:]OK.
[fre:]OK.
[ru:]Что вы изучаете,
[zh:]你们现在上课都学些什么呀
[en:]What are you studying?
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que tu étudies ?
[ar:]ماذا تدرس حاليا؟[fix]
[ko:]좋아.[fix] 넌 뭘 공부하고 있니?[fix]
[ru:]в школе?
[zh:]啊 学什么呢
[en:]Studying?
[fre:]Ce que j'étudie ?
[ar:]ادرس؟
[ko:]공부?[fix]
[ru:]Изучаем?
[zh:]我也不知道学什么
[en:]Dunno...
[fre:]Je sais pas...
[ar:]لا أعرف[fix]
[ru:]Да разное изучаем.
[zh:]对 学了 学那个造酒
[en:]I mean, how to make wine...
[fre:]Si, enfin, comment faire le vin...
[ar:]بلى، نتعلم صناعة النبيذ[fix]
[ko:]잘 모르겠는데...[fix] 아.. 내 말은,  포도주 만드는 거 배운다고...[fix]
[ru:]Например, как делать вино...
[zh:]做小提琴
[en:]and, uh, violins...
[fre:]et, euh, les violons...
[ar:]و... الكمان[fix]
[ru:]и, эти... скрипки.
[zh:]还有做芝麻酱什么的
[en:]sesame paste, stuff like that.
[fre:]la pâte de sésame, des choses dans ce genre.
[ar:]والطحينة، وأشياء كهذه
[ko:]그리고, 음...바이올린...[fix] 참깨죽...뭐 그런거.[fix]
[ru:]кунжутную пасту изучаем и прочую фигню.
[zh:]在哪儿学的这些乱七八糟的东西
[en:]Where do you learn those silly things?
[fre:]Où est-ce que tu apprends ces trucs inutiles ?
[ar:]أين تدرس هذه الأشياء الفوضوية؟[fix]
[ru:]И где это вы все эти глупости изучаете?
[zh:]学工学农啊
[en:]From the workers and peasants!
[fre:]Des ouvriers et des paysans ![fix]
[ar:]من العمال والفلاحين
[ru:]У рабочих и крестьян.
[zh:]我们在造酒厂学了一个月工啊
[en:]We worked for a month in the wine factory,
[fre:]On a travaillé un mois à la fabrique de vin,
[ar:]عملنا لمدة شهر في مصنع النبيذ
[ko:]그런 바보 같은 것들을 어디서 배워?[fix] 노동자와 농민들한테![fix] 우리는 한 달 동안  포도주 공장에서 일했어.[fix]
[ru:]Мы где-то месяц на винной фабрике работали
[zh:]我们还跟那边大孩子打架
[en:]got into a big fight there,
[fre:]où on a eu une grosse bagarre,
[ar:]وتقاتلنا مع بعض الفتية هناك[fix]
[ko:]그런데 거기서 큰 싸움이 났어.[fix]
[ru:]Там большая драка, кстати, случилась.
[zh:]他们来了二百多人
[en:]200 of them,[fix]
[ar:]أحضروا 200 رجل[fix]
[ru:]Человек 200 билось.[fix]
[zh:]全让我们给打回去了
[en:]but we won,
[fre:]ils étaient au moins 200, mais on a gagné,[fix]
[ar:]لكننا ردينا الضرب لهم[fix]
[ko:]200명이 붙었는데,[fix] 우리가 이겼어.[fix]
[ru:]Но мы победили
[zh:]后来我们上课时包里全是菜刀
[en:]and now we always carry cleavers in our book bags.
[fre:]et maintenant on a toujours des couteaux dans nos sacs.
[ar:]والآن نحمل دائما سواطير في حقائبنا[fix]
[ko:]우리들은 항상 책가방속에 칼을 넣고 다니거든.[fix]
[ru:]и теперь таскаем в портфелях разделочные ножи.
[zh:]然后有一大孩子都说服了
[en:]This older kid was begging for mercy,
[fre:]Le plus vieux nous implorait,
[ar:]ذات يوم، طلب شاب الرحمة
[ru:]Там один мужик зассал и плакать начал, не трогайте, мол.
[zh:]那人被砍了好几菜刀呢
[en:]but we slashed him up anyway.
[fre:]mais on l'a quand même tailladé.
[ar:]لكننا جرحناه بسواطير عدة مرات ولم نبالي[fix]
[ko:]어떤 나이든 애가  봐달라고 싹싹 빌더라고.[fix] 그래도 그냥 베어버렸지.[fix]
[ru:]Но мы ему все равно наваляли.
[zh:]是吗
[en:]Really?
[fre:]Vraiment ?
[ar:]حقا؟[fix]
[ko:]진짜?[fix]
[ru:]Ладно.
[zh:]那你们考试考什么呀
[en:]So what do they test you on?[fix]
[fre:]Alors, ils vous interrogent sur quoi ?
[ar:]إذن في ماذا اختبروك؟
[ru:]А на экзаменах вы что делаете?[fix]
[zh:]是考造酒啊 还是考打架
[en:]Wine-making or fighting?
[fre:]La fabrication du vin ou la bagarre ?
[ar:]في صنع النبيذ[fix] أو القتال؟
[ko:]그러면 무슨 시험을 보는데?[fix] 포도주 만드는거, 아니면 싸우는거?[fix]
[ru:]Вино перегоняете, или морды бьете?[fix]
[zh:]哎 你坐吧
[en:]Sit down.
[fre:]Assieds-toi.
[ar:]اجلس - أين؟ -[fix]
[ru:]Садись.
[zh:]那哪儿成啊
[en:]You kidding?
[fre:]Tu veux rire ?
[ru:]Шутишь?
[zh:]我们就学了一个月工
[en:]We were only there one month.
[fre:]On n'y est resté qu'un mois,
[ar:]عموماً، كنا هناك لشهر فقط
[ko:]앉아.[fix]
[ru:]Мы там только месяц были.
[zh:]其他时候还得上课
[en:]the rest of the time we're in the classroom.
[fre:]le reste du temps, on est en classe. J'aime lire.[fix]
[ar:]كنا لا نزال نحضر الحصص ببقية الوقت
[ko:]농담하는거야?[fix] 우리는 거기서 겨우 한 달간만 일한거라고.[fix] 나머지 시간은 학교 교실에 있었어.[fix]
[ru:]А в основном в классе сидим.
[zh:]不过平时我自己也找书看
[en:]I like reading.
[ar:]لكن عادةً أجد كتب وأقرأها بنفسي وحسب
[ko:]난 독서를 좋아해.[fix]
[ru:]Мне нравится. Я люблю читать.
[zh:]你都看什么书啊
[en:]What sort of books do you like?
[fre:]Quel genre de livres tu aimes ?
[ar:]ما نوع الكتب التي تقرأها؟
[ko:]어떤 책들을 좋아하는데?[fix]
[ru:]Да? И какие книги тебе нравятся?
[zh:]《钢铁是怎样练成的》
[en:]How Steel Is Tempered,
[fre:]Comment l'Acier est Trempé,
[ar:](كيف سقينا الفولاذ)
[ko:]강철은 어떻게 단련되었는가,[fix]
[ru:]"Как закалялась сталь",
[zh:]《牛虻》
[en:]Gadfly,
[fre:]L'Envol des Dieux,
[ar:](ذباب الخيل)[fix] (أغنية الشباب)[fix]
[ru:]"Овод"
[zh:]《青春之歌》还有《苦菜花》什么的
[en:]The Song of Youth, Bitter Blossoms, that sort of thing.
[fre:]Le Chant de la Jeunesse, Les Fleurs Amères, ce genre de livres.
[ar:].أزهار مُرة)، وما شابه)[fix]
[ko:]쇠파리,[fix] 젊음의 노래, 원한의 꽃...뭐 그런거.[fix]
[ru:]"Песня молодежи", "Горький цветок" - такого типа.
[zh:]喜欢冬妮娅吗
[en:]Do you like the heroine Dunya?
[fre:]Tu aimes l'héroïne Dunya ?
[ar:]هل تعجبك شخصية (تونيا)؟[fix] (يعجبني (بافل[fix]
[ko:]여자 주인공인 듀냐 좋아하니?[fix]
[ru:]А тебе нравится Тоня из "Как закалялась сталь"?
[zh:]我喜欢保尔
[en:]I like Pavel,
[fre:]J'aime Pavel,
[ru:]Мне Павка нравится.
[zh:]冬妮娅也喜欢
[en:]but I like Dunya too.[fix]
[fre:]mais j'aime aussi Dunya.
[ar:]لكن تعجبني (تونيا) أيضا
[ru:]Но Тоня тоже ничего.[fix]
[zh:]可惜后来她变了
[en:]Pity how she changed...[fix]
[fre:]C'est dommage qu'elle ait changé,
[ar:]مؤسف أنها تغيرت وأصبحت برجوازية[fix]
[ko:]난 파벨이 좋아,[fix] 그렇지만 듀냐도 좋아해.[fix] 그녀가 변해서...[fix]
[ru:]Жаль, что она переродилась[fix]
[zh:]成了资产阶级了
[en:]and became bourgeois.
[fre:]et soit devenue bourgeoise.
[ko:]부르조아가 되었을 때 얼마나 안타깝던지...[fix]
[ru:]и стала буржуйкой.
[zh:]这些书你都看完了吗 没有
[en:]Have you finished all those books? No.
[fre:]- Tu as fini tous ces livres ? - Non.
[ar:]أكملتَ كل هذه الكتب؟ - كلا -[fix]
[ru:]- А ты все эти книги дочитал? - Нет.
[zh:]为什么
[en:]Why not?
[fre:]Pourquoi ça ?
[ar:]لم لا؟[fix]
[ru:]Почему нет?
[zh:]嗨 都是些没头没尾的旧书
[en:]They're just old books without beginning or end.
[fre:]Ce sont justes de vieux livres, sans commencement ni fin.
[ar:]إنها كتب قديمة بلا بداية لها ولا نهاية[fix]
[ko:]- 너 그 책들 다 읽었니? - 아니.[fix] 왜?[fix] 그것들은 시작도 끝도 없는 구닥다리 책들이야.[fix]
[ru:]Потому что они у нас зачитанные, без начала и конца.
[zh:]哎 二百首你看过吗
[en:]What about "200 Songs"? You read that?
[fre:]Et "200 chants" ? Tu l'as lu ?
[ar:]ماذا عن (مائتي أغنية)؟ قرأتِـه؟[fix]
[ko:]"200곡"은 어때? 그거 읽어봤어?[fix]
[ru:]А что насчет "200 песен"? Читала?
[zh:]当然
[en:]Of course!
[fre:]Bien sûr !
[ar:]طبعا
[ru:]Конечно!
[zh:]那本书叫外国民歌二百首
[en:]200 Folk Songs from Abroad.
[fre:]200 Chants Folkloriques de l'Étranger ?
[ar:](اسمه (مائتي أغنية شعبية من الخارج
[ko:]물론![fix] 200곡의 외국 포크송 모음집이잖아.[fix]
[ru:]"200 зарубежных народных песен".
[zh:]是歌本
[en:]It's a songbook.
[fre:]C'est un livre de musique.
[ar:]إنه كتاب أغاني[fix]
[ko:]그건 노래책이야.[fix]
[ru:]Только это песенник.
[zh:]我不认谱 我拿来当书看了
[en:]I can't read music, I just read the lyrics.
[fre:]Je ne sais pas lire la musique, je lis juste les paroles.
[ar:]لا أجيد قراءة الموسيقى فأقرأ الكلمات فقط[fix]
[ko:]나도 노래는 안 읽어, 그냥 그 가사를 읽었다는거지.[fix]
[ru:]Ну, да. Я ноты читать не имею, поэтому только стихи читал.
[zh:]赶明儿你教我唱吧
[en:]Why don't you teach me to sing them?
[fre:]Tu pourrais m'apprendre à les chanter ?
[ar:]لمَ لا تعلميني لأغنيها يوما ما؟[fix]
[ru:]А что бы тебе не научить меня этим песням?
[zh:]没问题
[en:]Sure, no problem.
[fre:]Bien sûr, sans problème.
[ar:]بالتأكيد، لا مشكلة[fix]
[ko:]그 노래들 좀 가르쳐줄래?[fix] 좋아, 문제 없지.[fix]
[ru:]Как-нибудь научу.
[zh:]你在哪儿上班啊
[en:]Where do you work?
[fre:]Tu travailles où ?
[ar:]أين تعملين؟[fix] بعيدا
[ru:]А ты где работаешь?
[zh:]特远
[en:]Really far away.
[fre:]Très loin d'ici.
[ru:]Далеко отсюда.
[zh:]那你就不去了
[en:]So why aren't you there?
[fre:]Alors pourquoi tu n'es pas là-bas ?
[ar:]لماذا ليس عليك العودة لهناك؟[fix]
[ru:]А почему ты не на работе?
[zh:]去啊 前一阵儿 我一直在那儿
[en:]I'm just back,
[fre:]J'en reviens juste,
[ar:]علي ذلك أنا دائما هناك[fix] وعادة أبقى هناك[fix]
[ko:]넌 어디서 일해?[fix] 아주 멀어.[fix] 그럼 지금은 왜 여기 있는데?[fix] 방금전에 돌아왔어.[fix]
[ru:]Я только что вернулась.
[zh:]还住那儿呢
[en:]I usually stay there.
[fre:]je reste là-bas d'habitude.
[ru:]Обычно я там ночую.
[zh:]说你怎么老不在家呆着
[en:]That's why you're never home.
[fre:]C'est pour ça que tu n'es jamais là.
[ar:]أوه، هذا السبب أنك لا تتواجدي بالمنزل
[ko:]대개 거기에 있어.[fix] 그래서 거의 집에 없는거구나.[fix]
[ru:]Поэтому тебя никогда дома нет?
[zh:]你来找过我
[en:]So you have come to see me?
[fre:]Alors tu es passé me voir ?
[ar:]إذن أتيتَ لرؤيتي؟ - كلا -[fix]
[ru:]Так ты все-таки приходил сюда?
[zh:]没有
[en:]No.
[fre:]Non.
[ar:]كاذب - لم آتي -[fix]
[ru:]Нет.
[zh:]你骗人 没有
[en:]Liar.
[fre:]Menteur !
[ru:]Врешь.
[zh:]我外婆都告诉过我了 没有那
[en:]My grandma told me you've been by.[fix]
[fre:]Ma grand-mère m'a dit que tu es passé.
[ar:]أخبرتني جدتي أن صبي دائما يأتي[fix]
[ru:]Мне бабушка сказала, что ты был.[fix]
[zh:]有个小孩儿 那不是我
[en:]A kid would call out "Mi Lan"...[fix]
[fre:]Un gamin qui appelait "Mi Lan"
[ar:]ويهرب عندما تفتح الباب[fix]
[ko:]날 보러 온 적이 있니?[fix] 아니.[fix] 거짓말쟁이.[fix]
[ru:]Мол, какой-то ребенок стучал в дверь, звал Ма Лань...[fix]
[zh:]一开门他就跑了
[en:]and run when she opened the door.
[fre:]et qui s'enfuyait dès qu'elle ouvrait la porte.
[ar:]ليس أنا
[ko:]내 할머니가, 네가 왔다갔다고 말해줬어.[fix] 어떤 애가 "미란" 이렇게 부르기에...[fix] 문을 열었더니만, 뛰어가더라고.[fix]
[ru:]а когда она открыла - убежал.
[zh:]那真不是我
[en:]That wasn't me.
[fre:]Ce n'était pas moi.
[ar:]حقا ليس أنا
[ko:]그건 나 아니야.[fix]
[ru:]Это был не я!
[zh:]真的
[en:]Really.
[fre:]Vraiment.
[ar:]حقا[fix]
[ko:]진짜야.[fix]
[ru:]Честно.
[zh:]好吧
[en:]Fine.[fix]
[fre:]Bien.
[ar:]حسنا
[ru:]Ладно.[fix]
[zh:]这阵儿我病了
[en:]Anyway, I'm on sick leave.
[fre:]Enfin, je suis en congé de maladie,
[ar:]عموما، أنا في اجازة مرضية فمر علي إذا عندك وقت[fix]
[ko:]좋아.[fix] 나, 병가 냈어.[fix]
[ru:]Вообще-то, я в отпуске по болезни.
[zh:]在家里 有空你过来吧
[en:]Come visit anytime.
[fre:]viens me rendre visite quand tu voudras.
[ru:]Так что можешь приходить когда хочешь.
[zh:]你得什么病了 少打听
[en:]What's wrong? Mind your own business.
[fre:]- Qu'est-ce que tu as ? - C'est pas tes affaires.
[ar:]ما بك؟ - لا تتدخل -[fix]
[ko:]아무 때나 보러 와.[fix] - 어디 아픈데? - 신경 쓰지 마.[fix]
[ru:]- А что случилось? - Не лезь не в свое дело.
[zh:]哦 哦 哦
[ar:]أوه، حسنا
[zh:]你是不是有张照片 是穿游泳衣的
[en:]Isn't there a photo of you in a bathing suit?
[fre:]Il n'y avait pas une photo de toi en maillot de bain ?
[ar:]أليس لديك صورة وأنت بلبس السباحة؟[fix]
[ko:]수영복 입고 찍은 사진 있지?[fix]
[ru:]А куда делась твое фото в купальнике?
[zh:]你胡说
[en:]Nonsense!
[fre:]Pas du tout !
[ar:]هراء
[ru:]Что ты мелешь?
[zh:]我什么时候有穿游泳衣的
[en:]When have I ever worn a bathing suit?
[fre:]Quand est-ce que j'aurais porté un maillot de bain ?
[ar:]متى ارتديتُ أصلاً لبس السباحة؟
[ko:]말도 안 되는 소리![fix] 내가 언제 수영복을 입었겠냐?[fix]
[ru:]Где это я была в купальнике?
[zh:]原来就挂在这儿的 没错
[en:]It was hanging right there. I'm sure of it.
[fre:]Elle était accrochée là. J'en suis sûr.
[ar:]كانت معلقة هناك أنا متأكد
[ru:]Оно вот здесь висело! Я уверен.
[zh:]这儿是有一张照片 可没有穿游泳衣
[en:]There was a photo, but I wasn't in a bathing suit.
[fre:]Il y avait bien une photo, mais pas en maillot de bain.
[ar:]كان هناك صورة لكن لم أكن بلبس السباحة
[ko:]저기 걸려있었어.  분명해.[fix] 사진이야 있었지, 하지만 수영복 입은 사진 아니야.[fix]
[ru:]Здесь была фотография, но я была не в купальнике.
[zh:]不可能 拿出来我看
[en:]Impossible! Show it to me.
[fre:]Pas possible ! Montre-la moi.
[ru:]Да быть не может! Ну-ка покажи ее.
[zh:]叫朋友拿走了
[en:]A friend took it.
[fre:]Un ami l'a prise.
[ar:]مستحيل. أريني إياها - أخذها صديق -[fix]
[ru:]Ее один знакомый забрал.
[zh:]不对 绝对是穿游泳衣的
[en:]I'm positive you were in a bathing suit.
[fre:]Je suis sûr que tu étais en maillot de bain.
[ar:]أنا متأكد أنك كنت بلبس السباحة
[ko:]말도 안 돼! 내게 보여줘 봐.[fix] 친구가 가져갔어.[fix] 분명히 네가 수영복 입은 사진이야.[fix]
[ru:]А я уверен, что ты была в купальном костюме.
[zh:]你这孩子真倔
[en:]Such a stubborn kid!
[fre:]Quel enfant borné !
[ar:]يا لك من فتى عنيد[fix]
[ko:]고집불통이군![fix]
[ru:]Вот упрямый ребенок.
[zh:]那给你看
[en:]Want to see?
[fre:]Tu veux voir ?
[ar:]انظر إذن[fix]
[ko:]볼래?[fix]
[ru:]На, смотри.
[zh:]绝对在这里边
[en:]Strange! I'm so sure.
[fre:]C'est bizarre ! J'en suis si sûr.
[ar:]متأكد أنها هنا[fix]
[ko:]이상하네! 정말인데.[fix]
[ru:]Странно. А я был так уверен.
[zh:]有吗
[en:]Really?
[fre:]Alors ?
[ar:]موجودة؟[fix]
[ko:]정말이야?[fix]
[ru:]Ну и что?
[zh:]跟这张一模一样的
[en:]Just like this one,
[fre:]Comme celle-là,
[ar:]كانت مثل هذه تماما[fix]
[ru:]Вот на эту похожа,
[zh:]穿游泳衣的
[en:]but with a bathing suit.
[fre:]mais en maillot.
[ar:]ولكن بلبس السباحة[fix]
[ko:]이거하고 비슷했는데,[fix] 이건 수영복이 아니군.[fix]
[ru:]но в купальнике.
[zh:]不对呀
[en:]No?
[fre:]Non ?
[ar:]ليست هذه...أكانت معلقة هناك؟
[ko:]아닌가?[fix]
[ru:]Она?
[zh:]就是挂在这儿这张
[en:]Hanging right here?
[fre:]Accrochée là ?
[ar:]أأنا ارتدي لبس السباحة؟[fix]
[ru:]Ты посмотри на нее.
[zh:]你先说 有没有穿游泳衣呀
[en:]Just tell me this, am I wearing a bathing suit?
[fre:]Je porte un maillot, là ?
[ru:]Я на ней в купальнике?
[zh:]还真没有
[en:]No, you're not.
[fre:]Non.
[ar:]لا[fix]
[ko:]걸려있던게 이건가?[fix] 이게 수영복 입고 있는거니?[fix] 아니, 그거 아니야.[fix]
[ru:]Нет.
[zh:]也不是
[en:]I don't get it.[fix]
[fre:]Je ne comprends pas.
[ar:]ليست هذه[fix]
[ru:]Я ее здесь не вижу.[fix]
[zh:]原来就挂在这儿 还彩色的
[en:]It was hanging there, I remember it was in color.
[fre:]Elle était accrochée là, elle était en couleur.
[ar:]كانت معلقة هناك... بالألوان[fix]
[ko:]모르겠네.[fix] 거기 걸려있던건,  칼라 사진이었는데...[fix]
[ru:]Она висела здесь, я помню. И она была цветная.
[zh:]好了 好了 好了
[en:]OK...
[fre:]OK...
[ar:]حسنا، حسنا[fix]
[ko:]알았어, 알았어...[fix]
[ru:]Ладно, бог с ним.
[zh:]等以后 你给我拍张得了
[en:]why don't you a photo of me like that sometime?
[fre:]Tu n'auras qu'à faire une photo de moi comme ça, un jour.
[ar:]لمَ لا تلتقط صورة لي بوقت ما؟[fix]
[ko:]언제 그런 사진 한 장 찍어줄래?[fix]
[ru:]Раз это так важно, сфотай меня сам как-нибудь.
[zh:]啊 嗯
[en:]OK.
[fre:]OK.
[ar:]حسنا
[ru:]Хорошо.
[zh:]这张给我吗
[en:]Can I keep this one?
[fre:]Je peux garder celle-là ?
[ar:]أيمكنك أن تدعيني آخذ هذه؟
[ko:]좋아.[fix] 나 이거 가져도 돼?[fix]
[ru:]А можно я ее заберу?
[zh:]不行
[en:]No.
[fre:]Non.
[ar:]لا[fix]
[ru:]Нет.
[zh:]给我嘛
[en:]Come on.
[fre:]Allez.
[ar:]أرجوك، دعيني آخذها
[ru:]Пожалуйста...
[zh:]不行
[en:]No.
[fre:]Non.
[ar:]لا
[ru:]Нет.
[zh:]你要照片干嘛
[en:]Why do you want my photo anyway?
[fre:]Pourquoi tu veux ma photo, d'ailleurs ?
[ar:]ما الذي تريده بصورتي أصلا؟
[ko:]안 돼.[fix] 제발.[fix] 안 돼.[fix] 왜 자꾸 내 사진을 가지려고 하니?[fix]
[ru:]Зачем это тебе мое фото?
[zh:]真不给我
[en:]You really won't give it to me?
[fre:]Tu ne veux vraiment pas me la donner ?
[ar:]، إن لم تعطيني إياها[fix] سأضطر لسرقتها[fix]
[ru:]Что - правда не дашь?
[zh:]那我可抢了
[en:]Then I'll steal it.
[fre:]Alors je vais te la voler.
[ru:]Тогда я ее украду.
[zh:]你敢
[en:]You'd dare!
[fre:]Tu n'oserais pas !
[ar:]!هذا طبعك[fix]
[ko:]정말로 안 줄거야?[fix] 그럼 훔쳐가야지.[fix] 어디 감히![fix]
[ru:]Только попробуй!
[zh:]哎 你站住
[en:]Stop it!
[fre:]Arrête !
[ar:]!توقف
[ko:]거기 서![fix]
[ru:]Стой!
[zh:]哎呀 哎呀
[zh:]生气了
[en:]Angry?[fix]
[fre:]Tu m'en veux ?
[ar:]أأنت مجنون؟
[ko:]화났어?[fix]
[ru:]Сердишься?[fix]
[zh:]别不高兴 真的
[en:]Don't be. really...[fix]
[fre:]Tu ne devrais pas. Ce n'est pas bien
[ar:]لا تكن تعيساً، حقاً
[ru:]Это правда нехорошо[fix]
[zh:]拿女孩照片不好
[en:]it's not good to take girls' photos.[fix]
[fre:]d'avoir des photos de filles.
[ar:]ليس لطيفا أن تأخذ صور الفتيات بالقوة
[ru:]воровать фотографии девушек.[fix]
[zh:]过来坐吧
[en:]Come over here.[fix]
[fre:]Viens par là.
[ar:]تعال هنا
[ko:]그러지 마. 진짜로...[fix] 숙녀의 사진을 가져가는 건 못된 짓이야.[fix] 이리 와 앉아.[fix]
[ru:]Иди сюда.[fix]
[zh:]送你样东西
[en:]I've got something for you.[fix]
[fre:]J'ai quelque chose pour toi.
[ar:]لدي شيء لك[fix]
[ru:]У меня есть для тебя подарок.[fix]
[zh:]过来
[en:]Come here.[fix]
[fre:]Viens là.
[ar:]تعال هنا[fix]
[ko:]너한테 줄게 있어.[fix]
[ru:]Подойди.[fix]
[zh:]给
[en:]Here.[fix]
[fre:]Tiens.
[ar:]هاك[fix]
[ko:]가까이.[fix]
[ru:]Вот, держи.[fix]
[zh:]有三种颜色
[en:]It's got three colors.[fix]
[fre:]Il a trois couleurs.
[ar:]به ثلاثة ألوان
[ko:]여기.[fix] 세 가지 색깔이야.[fix]
[ru:]Она трехцветная.[fix]
[zh:]有段时间我几乎天天和她见面
[en:]I saw her practically every day.[fix]
[fre:]J'allais la voir pratiquement tous les jours.
[ar:]بفترة رأيتُها كل يوم تقريبا
[ko:]실제로 나는 그녀를 매일 만났다.[fix]
[ru:]Я видел ее практически каждый день[fix]
[zh:]为了吹嘘自己
[ar:]، ولتحسين صورتي
[zh:]我总是把别人干过的事都安在自己头上
[en:]To make myself look good...[fix] I'd claim credit for things other people had done...[fix]
[fre:]Pour faire mon intéressant, je racontais avec désinvolture[fix]
[ar:]كنت أنسب لنفسي أشياء فعلها أشخاص آخرين
[ko:]멋있게 보이기 위해...[fix] 난 다른 사람들이 한 일을  마치 내가 한 것인양,[fix]
[ru:]Старался выставить себя с лучшей стороны.[fix] Я  рассказывал о делах других людей[fix]
[zh:]经过夸大和渲染
[en:]exaggerating and padding...[fix]
[fre:]les exploits des autres que je faisais mien,
[ar:]أزيّن وأبالغ في قصصي بلا اكتراث[fix]
[ru:]беззастенчиво приписывая все себе Я  рассказывал о делах других людей беззастенчиво приписывая все себе[fix]
[zh:]娓娓道出
[en:]out the stories with abandon.[fix]
[fre:]en brodant et exagérant.
[ko:]내멋대로 이야기를...[fix]
[ru:]и привирал при этом безбожно.[fix]
[zh:]遗憾的是
[fre:]Mes mauvaises actions
[zh:]我已扮成一个和自己年龄 极不相称的胆大妄为的强盗
[en:]My alleged evil deeds...[fix] matched neither my actual age or experience.[fix]
[fre:]ne collaient ni avec mon âge, ni avec mon expérience.
[ar:]الأسوأ، أن مغامراتي الجريئة لم تطابق عمري الحقيقي ولا خبرتي[fix]
[ko:]과장하기도 하고 덧붙이기도 했다.[fix] 내가 했다고 주장한 나쁜 짓들은...[fix] 내 실제 나이나 경험과는  절대로 어울리는 것이 아니었다.[fix]
[ru:]Мои сомнительные злодейства[fix] абсолютно не соответствовали ни моему возрасту, ни опыту.[fix]
[zh:]她竟从不以惊谔来为我喝彩
[en:]She encouraged me, never looking shocked at anything I said.[fix]
[fre:]Mais elle m'encourageait, en ne paraissant jamais choquée quand je lui parlais.
[ar:]ومع ذلك، أشادت بي دائما ولم تبدو مذهولة من أي شيء قلته[fix]
[ko:]그녀는 내가 하는 이야기에 전혀 놀라지 않았고,  나를 격려해줬다.[fix]
[ru:]Но она со всем соглашалась, ни разу не высказав удивления.[fix]
[zh:]我告诉她我会配钥匙
[en:]I told her how I'd learned how to make keys...[fix]
[fre:]Je lui ai raconté comment j'avais appris à faire des clés,
[ar:]أخبرتُها أني تعلمت صناعة المفاتيح
[ru:]Я рассказал ей, как научился делать ключи...[fix]
[zh:]能开各种不同的锁
[en:]and pick locks...[fix]
[fre:]ouvrir les serrures,
[ar:]وأني أستطيع فتح أي قفل
[ko:]나는 그녀에게 열쇠를 어떻게 만드는지...[fix]
[ru:]и отмычки...[fix]
[zh:]甚至开过她的家
[ar:]أخبرتُها أني اقتحمت منزلها حتى
[zh:]玩过她的望远镜
[en:]and broken into her house...[fix]
[fre:]et comment j'étais rentrée chez elle,[fix]
[ar:]ولعبت بمنظارها
[ko:]자물쇠를 어떻게 따는지...[fix] 그리고 그녀의 집에 들어와서...[fix]
[ru:]и как залез в ее квартиру...[fix]
[zh:]看见过她的大照片什么的
[en:]and seen her photo...[fix]
[fre:]et vu sa photo.
[ar:]ورأيت صورتها
[ru:]и увидел ее фото...[fix]
[zh:]她也只是说 是吗
[en:]and all she said was, "Really"?[fix]
[fre:]Et tout ce qu'elle m'a répondu fut "Vraiment ?"
[ar:]"وكل ما قالته هو، "حقا؟
[ko:]그녀의 사진을 본 얘기를 해줬다.[fix] 그 때 그녀가 보인 응답은  "진짜?"라는 말 뿐이었다.[fix]
[ru:]но она сказала всего лишь "Да ты что?"[fix]
[zh:]有时候 说着 说着 她就睡着了
[en:]Sometimes she'd fall asleep,[fix]
[fre:]Parfois, elle s'endormait,
[ar:]أحيانا أثناء كلامي تنام
[ru:]Иногда она засыпала[fix]
[zh:]而我则尽力不去看 她无意中裸露出来的身体
[en:]and I'd try my hardest not to stare at her body,[fix]
[fre:]et je devais faire tout mon possible pour ne pas fixer son corps,
[ar:]وأحاول بشدة ألا أحدق لا إرادياً بجسدها المكشوف[fix]
[ko:]때때로 그녀는 잠이 들었다.[fix] 그럴때면, 나는 그녀의 몸을 보지 않으려고 무진 노력을 했고,[fix]
[ru:]И я сдерживался изо всех сил, чтобы не пялиться на ее тело.[fix]
[zh:]可脑子里却在胡思乱想
[en:]and keep my thoughts under control.[fix]
[fre:]et garder mon self-contrôle.
[ar:].لكن أفكاري سرحت بلا سيطرة
[ko:]내 마음을 진정시키려고 애썼다.[fix]
[ru:]и не позволять своим мыслям заходить слишком далеко.[fix]
[zh:]慢着
[fre:]Mais le problème,
[ar:]...مهلا لحظة
[zh:]我的记忆好象出了毛病
[en:]But wait...[fix] My memory plays tricks.[fix]
[fre:]c'est que ma mémoire me joue des tours.
[ar:]يبدو أن ذاكرتي تخدعني
[ko:]그렇지만, 잠깐...[fix]
[ru:]Но, погодите![fix] Возможно, это моя память опять играет в игры[fix]
[zh:]事实和幻觉又搅到了一块儿
[en:]I've confused reality and dreams.[fix]
[fre:]Je mélangeais rêves et réalité.
[ar:]ولقد خلطتُ بين الواقع والأحلام
[ru:]Я перепутал реальность и мечты[fix]
[zh:]可能她根本就没有当我的面睡过觉
[en:]Maybe she never fell asleep in front of me.[fix]
[fre:]Elle ne s'est peut-être jamais endormie en face de moi.
[ar:]ربما أنها لم تنم أمامي مطلقا
[ko:]내 기억이 장난을 친다.[fix] 실재와 꿈이 헷갈린다.[fix] 어쩌면 그녀는 결코 내 앞에서 잠들지 않았을지도 모른다.[fix]
[ru:]Возможно, она никогда и не засыпала при мне[fix]
[zh:]可能她根本就没有这样凝视过我
[en:]She may never have stared at me like that.[fix]
[fre:]Elle ne m'a peut-être jamais regardé fixement.
[ar:]ربما أنها لم تحدق بي كهذا على الإطلاق[fix]
[ru:]Наверное, она никогда не смотрела на меня так[fix]
[zh:]那么她锥子般锐利的目光
[en:]Heavens! If not, Why is her gaze...[fix]
[fre:]Mon Dieu ! Sinon, pourquoi son regard fixe
[ar:]إذن فكيف أن نظراتها الخارقة بشدة ، وجسدها الهانئ بالنوم[fix]
[ru:]Боже! Но если этого не было, почему ее пристальный взгляд[fix]
[zh:]和熟睡的样子又是 怎么跑到我的头脑中来的呢
[en:]and her sleeping figure so deeply etched in my brain?[fix]
[fre:]et son beau visage endormi restent ancrés si profondément dans ma tête ?[fix]
[ar:]محفور بشدة بذهني؟[fix]
[ko:]결코 그처럼 나를 바라보지 않았을지도 모른다.[fix] 맙소사! 만약 그렇지 않다면,  어째서 그녀의 시선과...[fix] 그녀의 자는 모습이 내 머릿속에  이리도 깊게 각인되어 있단 말인가?[fix]
[ru:]и силуэт ее тела на кровати так глубоко отпечатались в моем мозгу?[fix]
[zh:]总算考完了最后一门课
[en:]I passed my last exam...[fix]
[fre:]J'ai réussi mon examen final,
[ar:]أديتُ أخيرا امتحاني الأخير
[ru:]Я сдал последний экзамен..[fix]
[zh:]过两天 我们就要放暑假了
[en:]and holidays were beginning in two days.[fix]
[fre:]et les vacances commençaient dans deux jours.
[ar:]وستكون عطلة الصيف بعد يومين[fix]
[ko:]난 마지막 시험을 통과했다...[fix] 이제 이틀 뒤면 방학이 시작된다.[fix]
[ru:]и через два дня начинались каникулы.[fix]
[zh:]你还买菜 像个小媳妇
[en:]You shop for groceries? Like a little housewife.[fix]
[fre:]Tu es allée faire les courses ? Une vraie petite femme au foyer.
[ar:]اشتريتِ المواد الغذائية كربة منزل صغيرة؟[fix]
[ko:]식품점 갔다 온거야?  꼭 가정주부 같다.[fix]
[ru:]Ты была на рынке? Выглядишь как настоящая хозяйка.[fix]
[zh:]小媳妇就小媳妇呗
[en:]A housewife I am then.[fix]
[fre:]Alors, je suis une femme au foyer.
[ar:]قل عني ربة منزل صغيرة إن أردتَ[fix]
[ru:]А я и есть хозяйка.[fix]
[zh:]不买菜 吃什么
[en:]How else am I supposed to eat?[fix]
[fre:]Comment je pourrais manger autrement ?
[ar:]لكن لو لم اشترها ماذا سنأكل؟[fix]
[ko:]그래, 나 가정주부야.[fix] 먹고는 살아야지.[fix]
[ru:]Как же я, по твоему, ем?[fix]
[zh:]后天我们就放假了
[en:]We go on vacation day after tomorrow.[fix]
[fre:]On part en vacances après-demain.
[ar:]لدينا عطلة بعد غد[fix]
[ru:]А у нас послезавтра каникулы.[fix]
[zh:]还是当学生好啊
[ar:]يا لروعة أن تكون طالبا
[zh:]每年还有两个假期
[en:]How wonderful to be a student.[fix] Two holidays a year.[fix]
[fre:]C'est beau d'être étudiant... Deux vacances par an...[fix]
[ar:]ويكون لديك عطلتين بالسنة
[ko:]모레면 나 방학이야.[fix]
[ru:]Как хорошо быть школьником.[fix] Два отпуска в году.[fix]
[zh:]可能一不上学 我就不能天天来找你了
[en:]But if I don't go to school, I might not be able to come every day.[fix]
[fre:]Mais si je n'allais pas à l'école,[fix] je ne pourrais peut-être pas venir ici tous les jours.[fix]
[ar:]لكن لو لم يكن علي الذهاب للمدرسة لكان بإمكاني المجيء لرؤيتك كل يوم[fix]
[ko:]학생들은 참 좋겠다.[fix] 일년에 방학이 두 번이니.[fix] 근데, 학교에 가지 않으면, 매일 보러 올 수 없을지도 몰라.[fix]
[ru:]Если бы я не был школьником, я бы не смог торчать у тебя каждый день.[fix]
[zh:]哎 跟我上楼吧
[fre:]Tu montes ?
[zh:]哎 不 得回去了
[en:]Come on up.[fix] No, I have to go.[fix]
[fre:]Non, je dois partir.
[ar:]لم لا تدخل؟ - لا، يجب أن أذهب -[fix]
[ko:]들어 와.[fix] 아니, 나 가볼데가 있어.[fix]
[ru:]Ну, пошли?[fix] Не, мне надо бежать.[fix]
[zh:]我都等了你一下午了
[en:]I've been here all afternoon.[fix]
[fre:]Je suis resté là toute l'après-midi.
[ar:]كنت انتظرك هنا العصر كله
[ru:]Я и так проторчал здесь целый день.[fix]
[zh:]是吗 啊 找我有事
[en:]Really? What's up?[fix]
[fre:]Vraiment ? Pourquoi ?
[ar:]حقا؟ لماذا كنت تنتظرني؟[fix]
[ko:]오후 내내 이곳에서 기다렸어.[fix]
[ru:]Правда? Как у тебя дела?[fix]
[zh:]哎 哪天 你到我们那儿玩去
[en:]Uh, when are you coming to visit me?[fix]
[fre:]Euh, quand est-ce que tu viens me voir ?
[ar:]متى يمكنك أن تطلعي وتتمشي معنا؟[fix]
[ko:]진짜? 무슨 일인데?[fix] 음...언제 나 만나러 오지 않을래?[fix]
[ru:]Нормально. А когда ты к нам придешь?[fix]
[zh:]不去
[fre:]Je ne le ferai pas.
[ar:]لن افعل
[zh:]我才不想认识你们那帮坏孩子呢
[en:]I'm not.[fix] I've no desire to meet that gang of bad kids.[fix]
[fre:]Je ne veux pas voir ce gang de mauvais garçons.
[ar:]لا رغبة لي بلقاء عصابة الفتيان الفاسدين خاصتك
[ko:]안 가.[fix]
[ru:]Никогда.[fix] У меня нет никакого желания общаться с бандой юных уголовников.[fix]
[zh:]那你又不认识 你怎么知道是坏小孩呢
[en:]You haven't met them, how do you know they're bad?[fix]
[fre:]Tu ne les as jamais vus, comment sais-tu qu'ils sont mauvais ?
[ar:]أنت لم تلتقي بهم فكيف تعرفين أنهم سيئون؟[fix]
[ko:]나쁜 애들 패거리 만날 생각 없어.[fix] 걔들을 만나보지도 않았으면서, 나쁘다는걸 어떻게 알아?[fix]
[ru:]Ты же их не знаешь, почему ты решила, что они плохие?[fix]
[zh:]你去看看
[fre:]Vraiment,
[zh:]真的挺好玩的
[en:]Really,[fix] they're a lot of fun.[fix]
[fre:]ils sont très sympas.
[ar:]عليك أن تأتي وتقابليهم إنهم مرحون جدا[fix]
[ru:]На самом деле[fix] они очень даже прикольные.[fix]
[zh:]再说吧
[fre:]Un autre jour.
[zh:]别再说
[en:]Some other time.[fix] That's no good.[fix]
[fre:]Je ne suis pas d'accord.
[ar:]بوقت آخر - ...لا ينفع هذا -[fix]
[ko:]진짜로,[fix] 재밌는 애들이야.[fix] 기회되면 갈게.[fix]
[ru:]Как нибудь потом.[fix] Нет, так не пойдет.[fix]
[zh:]到时候就不好联系了
[en:]how will we get in touch?[fix]
[fre:]Comment on va rester en contact ?
[ar:]لن نعرف إذن كيف نكون على تواصل[fix]
[ru:]Когда мы встретимся?[fix]
[zh:]你还是说准的吧
[en:]Let's set a day now.[fix]
[fre:]Prévoyons un jour.
[ar:]لنحدد يوماً الآن[fix]
[ko:]그러지 말고.[fix] 우리가 어떻게 연락하지?[fix]
[ru:]Давай сейчас назначим день.[fix]
[zh:]好吧 那你说哪天
[en:]All right, then. What day's good?[fix]
[fre:]Bon, d'accord. Quel jour tu veux ?
[ar:]حسنا. أي يوم يناسبك؟[fix]
[ru:]Ладно, давай. Когда тебя устроит?[fix]
[zh:]星期一 星期一 我们院大人少
[en:]Monday. Fewer adults around.[fix]
[fre:]Lundi. Il y aura moins d'adultes.
[ar:]الاثنين الكبار قليلي التواجد أيام الاثنين[fix]
[ko:]지금 날을 잡자.[fix] 그럼 좋아, 어느 날이 좋은데?[fix] 월요일. 그날은 어른들이 거의 없거든.[fix]
[ru:]В понедельник. Меньше взрослых будет вокруг.[fix]
[zh:]行
[fre:]OK.
[ar:]حسنا[fix]
[zh:]这是我画的联络图
[en:]OK.[fix] This is a map.[fix]
[fre:]Voilà un plan.
[ar:]هذه خريطة استطلاع رسمتُها لك[fix]
[ko:]좋아.[fix]
[ru:]Хорошо.[fix] Это план.[fix]
[zh:]你顺着箭头走 准能找着我
[en:]Just follow the arrow and you'll find it.[fix]
[fre:]Suis la flèche et tu trouveras.
[ar:]فقط اتبعي السهم وستجديني[fix]
[ru:]Иди по стрелке, и найдешь это место.[fix]
[zh:]我就在院门口等你
[en:]I'll be at the gate.[fix]
[fre:]Je serai à la porte.
[ar:]سأنتظرك عند بوابة المجمع[fix] حسنا[fix]
[ko:]이게 약도야.[fix] 화살표대로 따라오면,  찾을 수 있을거야.[fix]
[ru:]Я буду ждать у ворот.[fix]
[zh:]好吧
[en:]OK.[fix]
[fre:]OK.
[ko:]내가 문 앞에 나와있을게.[fix] 알았어.[fix]
[ru:]Договорились.[fix]
[zh:]哎 这边
[ar:]هنا[fix]
[zh:]唉 抽根烟得了
[en:]Give me a cigarette.[fix]
[fre:]Donne-moi une cigarette.
[ar:]أعطني سيجارة
[ko:]담배 하나 줘.[fix]
[ru:]Дай сигарету.[fix]
[zh:]你丫怎么老蹭人家呀
[en:]Why don't you buy it yourself?[fix]
[fre:]Pourquoi tu ne t'en achètes pas ?
[ar:]لماذا دائما تطلب الأشياء من الناس؟ لم يسبق أن اشتريت بنفسك[fix]
[ru:]А самому купить нигда не хотелось?[fix]
[zh:]从来就没自己买过
[zh:]有什么呀 回头还你一盒不得了吗
[ar:]وما المشكلة؟ سأعطيك علبة كاملة لاحقا، حسنا؟
[ko:]니가 직접 사서 펴.[fix]
[zh:]不成 就一根
[en:]Just one, please.[fix]
[fre:]Juste une, s'il te plaît.
[ar:]كلا - أعطني واحدة فقط -
[ko:]하나만 주라.[fix]
[ru:]Да только одну. Пожалуйста.[fix]
[zh:]玩去
[fre:]Va plutôt jouer. Fumer sous la porte,[fix]
[ar:]إليك عني
[zh:]大门口还抽烟
[en:]Go play.
[ru:]Пойду поиграю.
[zh:]就跟你有多大烟瘾似的
[en:]Smoke at the gate...[fix] just like a heavy smoker.[fix]
[fre:]comme les gros fumeurs...
[ar:]تدخن عند البوابة كالمدمن[fix]
[ru:]Только кури за воротами,[fix] как все нормальные курильщики.[fix]
[zh:]再说了让人米兰看见
[en:]Don't smoke here.[fix]
[fre:]Ne fume pas là.
[ar:]دعني أوضح ، لو تركتَ (مي لان)  تراك تدخن
[ko:]배드민턴이나 쳐.[fix] 골초처럼...[fix] 문에 붙어서 피지 그래.[fix] 여기서 피지 말고.[fix]
[ru:]Не кури здесь.[fix]
[zh:]这给人印象多不好
[ar:]سيكون انطباعها عنا سيء[fix]
[zh:]说这马猴净跟什么样的孩子在一起玩
[ar:]وستقول، ما هؤلاء الأصدقاء الذين يتسكع معهم هذا القرد؟[fix]
[zh:]是吧 马猴
[ar:]صحيح يا قرد؟[fix]
[zh:]来不来啦
[fre:]Elle va vraiment venir ou c'est juste une blague ?[fix]
[ar:]ستأتي هي أم لا؟ لا تحاول تخدعنا الآن[fix]
[zh:]别把咱给骗了
[en:]Is she really coming or is this a trick?[fix]
[ru:]А она вправду придет или ты наврал?[fix]
[zh:]对 马猴 你给人骗了吧
[en:]Yeah, Monkey, you've been had.[fix]
[fre:]Ouais, Monkey, tu t'es fait avoir.
[ar:]!يا قرد أأنت تحاول أن تخدعنا؟[fix]
[ko:]그 여자 진짜 오는거야?  사기친거 아니야?[fix] 야, 원숭아. 올 시간 지났잖아.[fix]
[ru:]Тебя, Обезьяна, похоже, поимели.[fix]
[zh:]那是米兰吗
[en:]Maybe she's not even Mi Lan.[fix]
[fre:]C'est peut-être même pas Mi Lan.
[ar:]متأكد أنك تعرف (مي لان)؟
[ko:]아무래도 그 여자 미란이 아닌가보다야.[fix]
[ru:]Может, он и не знаком с Ми Лань.[fix]
[zh:]你们还是先回去得了
[en:]Why don't you wait inside[fix]
[fre:]Pourquoi vous n'allez pas attendre dedans
[ru:]Да что вы здесь торчите со мной?[fix]
[zh:]跟这儿乱七八糟瞎嚷什么啊
[en:]and stop clogging up the view?[fix]
[fre:]au lieu de boucher la vue ?
[ar:]لمَ لا تسبقوني بدلا من العبث والبقاء هنا؟[fix]
[ko:]시야 가리지 말고,[fix]
[ru:]Идите на место, что цирк устраивать?[fix]
[zh:]走 我们在后院等你 走
[en:]OK, we'll be behind the hill.[fix]
[fre:]OK, on sera derrière la colline.
[ar:]حسنا، سننتظرك خلف المجمع[fix] هيا[fix]
[ko:]안에 들어가 있는게 어때?[fix] 그래, 우린 언덕 뒤에 있을게.[fix]
[ru:]Ладно, тогда мы будет за холмом.[fix]
[zh:]古伦木
[fre:]On y va. Gu Lunmu !
[ar:]غلومو[fix]
[zh:]欧巴
[en:]Let's go. Gu Lunmu!
[fre:]Oo-ba !
[ar:]اوبا
[ru:]Поехали! Гулуму!
[zh:]古伦木
[en:]Ouba!
[ru:]Оо-ба!
[zh:]欧巴
[ar:]غلومو[fix]
[ko:]가자. 구루무![fix] 오바![fix]
[zh:]欧巴
[en:]Ouba![fix]
[fre:]Oo-ba !
[ar:]اوبا[fix]
[ru:]Оо-ба![fix]
[zh:]哎 马猴
[fre:]Je peux rester avec toi, Monkey ?[fix]
[ar:]يا قرد، أيمكن أن ابقى هنا معك؟[fix]
[ko:]오바![fix]
[zh:]陪陪你成吗
[en:]Can I stay here with you, Monkey?[fix]
[ru:]Можно, я с тобой постою, Обезьяна?[fix]
[zh:]行 甭跟这乱闹啊
[en:]If you behave.[fix]
[fre:]Si tu veux.
[ar:]حسنا، بشرط أن تكف عن العبث
[ko:]같이 있어줄까, 원숭아?[fix] 맘대로 해.[fix]
[ru:]Ну, если хочешь...[fix]
[zh:]哎 米兰长什么样啊
[en:]What's she look like? Pretty?[fix]
[fre:]Elle ressemble à quoi ? Jolie ?
[ar:]كيف تبدو (مي لان)؟ أهي مثيرة؟[fix]
[ko:]저 여자 어때? 예쁘지?[fix]
[ru:]На кого она хоть похожа? Симпатичная?[fix]
[zh:]特精神 你也到后山去得了
[en:]Why don't you just go with the others?[fix]
[fre:]Pourquoi tu ne vas pas avec les autres ?
[ar:]لمَ لا تذهب مع الآخرين؟[fix]
[ru:]Слушай, а что бы тебе не пойти к пацанам?[fix]
[zh:]不是 你告诉我 我也好帮你盯着点儿
[en:]No, tell me, I can help you look out for her.[fix]
[fre:]Non, dis-moi. Je peux t'aider à la chercher.
[ar:]كلا، إن أخبرتَني يمكنني أن أساعدك بمراقبتها
[ko:]그냥 다른 애들하고 같이 가라.[fix] 아냐, 그 여자 찾는거 도와줄게.[fix]
[ru:]Не, ну расскажи. Я помогу тебе ее высматривать.[fix]
[zh:]哎
[en:]Hey![fix]
[fre:]Hé !
[ru:]Э![fix]
[zh:]哎
[ko:]어어.[fix]
[zh:]是她吧 是
[en:]That her? Yes.[fix]
[fre:]- C'est elle ? - Oui.
[ar:]أهذه هي؟ - أجل -[fix]
[ko:]- 저 여자야?  - 응.[fix]
[ru:]- Это она? -Да.[fix]
[zh:]你怎么从这边来
[en:]Why'd you come from that direction?[fix]
[fre:]Pourquoi tu arrives par là ?
[ar:]لماذا جئتِ من هذا الاتجاه؟[fix]
[ko:]왜 그쪽에서 와?[fix]
[ru:]Слушай, а что ты с той стороны пришла?[fix]
[zh:]抱歉 我迷了路
[en:]I got lost cause of your dumb map.[fix]
[fre:]Je me suis perdue à cause de ton plan minable.[fix]
[ar:]آسفه، ضعتُ
[ko:]너의 그 바보같은 약도 때문에 길 잃었어.[fix]
[ru:]Потому что из-за твоей дурацкой карты я заблудилась.[fix]
[zh:]都是你这张联络图搞的
[ar:]كل هذا بسبب خريطتك الاستطلاعية
[zh:]图
[ar:]خريطة؟[fix]
[zh:]从这儿上去
[en:]This way.[fix]
[fre:]C'est par là.[fix]
[ar:]لنذهب من هنا[fix]
[ru:]Сюда.[fix]
[zh:]他们都在上面亭子那儿等着我们
[en:]They're waiting by the pavilion.[fix]
[fre:]Ils attendent sur le pavillon.
[ar:]إنهم ينتظرون فوق عند المظلة
[ko:]이쪽이야.[fix] 누각에서 친구들이 기다리고 있어.[fix]
[ru:]Они ждут вон в той беседке.[fix]
[zh:]我见过你
[en:]I've seen you before.[fix]
[fre:]On s'est déjà vu avant.
[ar:]رأيتُك من قبل[fix]
[ru:]А я тебя знаю.[fix]
[zh:]你是不是和余北蓓一个农场的
[en:]You work at the same farm as Yu Beipei.[fix]
[fre:]Tu travailles à la même ferme que Yu Beipei.
[ar:]ألستِ تعملين بنفس المزرعة التي تعمل فيها (يو بـيـپـي)؟[fix]
[ko:]전에 널 본적이 있어.[fix]
[ru:]Ты работаешь на той же ферме, что и Юй Бэйпэй.[fix]
[zh:]啊 是
[en:]Yes.[fix]
[fre:]Oui.
[ar:]نعم، صحيح
[ko:]너 유베이페이가 일하는 농장에서 일하지?[fix] 그래.[fix]
[ru:]Да.[fix]
[zh:]余北蓓跟我们特熟
[en:]We're good friends with Yu Beipei.[fix]
[fre:]On est de bons amis avec Yu Beipei.
[ar:](نحن أصدقاء مقربين من (يو بـيـپـي[fix]
[ru:]А мы хорошие друзья с Юй Бэйпэй.[fix]
[zh:]是吗
[en:]Really?[fix]
[fre:]Vraiment ?
[ar:]حقا؟[fix]
[ru:]Правда?[fix]
[zh:]她是认识人挺多的
[en:]She knows a lot of people.[fix]
[fre:]Elle connaît beaucoup de monde.
[ar:]إنها تعرف كثير من الناس
[ko:]우리들은 유베이페이와 친한 친구사이야.[fix] 진짜?[fix] 걔는 아는 사람이 많지.[fix]
[ru:]У нее куча знакомых.[fix]
[zh:]这是我常跟你说的刘忆苦
[en:]This is Liu Yiku, whom I've told you about.[fix]
[fre:]Lui, c'est Liu Yiku, dont je t'ai parlé.
[ar:]هذا هو الرجل الذي أخبرتُك عنه (ليو إيكو)[fix]
[ru:]Это Лю Еку, я тебе про него рассказывал.[fix]
[zh:]这是他弟弟 刘思甜
[en:]This is his brother Liu Sitian.[fix]
[fre:]Voici son frère Liu Sitian.
[ar:](هذا أخوه الصغير، (ليو سيان[fix]
[ko:]이쪽은 류이쿠야. 내가 말한 적 있지?[fix] 얘는 동생인 류시챤.[fix]
[ru:]Это его брат Лю Сытиань[fix]
[zh:]这是大蚂蚁
[fre:]Lui, c'est Big Ant,
[ar:](هذا (النملة الكبيرة الذي قابلتِـه للتو[fix]
[zh:]你已经知道了
[en:]This is Big Ant,
[fre:]tu l'as déjà vu.
[ru:]Это Большой Муравей,
[zh:]哎 羊搞呢
[en:]you've just met.
[fre:]Où est Yang Gao ?
[ar:]أين (يانغ غاو)؟
[ru:]вы уже познакомились.
[zh:]买冰棍
[en:]Where's Yang Gao?[fix]
[fre:]Parti acheter des eskimos.
[ar:]ذهب لشراء المثلجات
[ko:]얘는 왕개미.[fix] 방금전에 만났지.[fix]
[ru:]А где Янг Гао?[fix]
[zh:]还有一个呢
[en:]Buying ice-pops.[fix]
[ru:]За фруктовым льдом пошел.[fix]
[zh:]全都我哥们
[en:]They're all my pals.[fix]
[fre:]Voilà tous mes amis.[fix]
[ar:]بقي واحد. جميعهم رفاقي[fix]
[ko:]양가오는 어디있어?[fix] 아이스캔디 사러 갔어.[fix] 모두 내 친구들이야.[fix]
[ru:]Они все мои друзья.[fix]
[zh:]你们这真不错
[en:]Not a bad place you live in.[fix]
[fre:]C'est pas mal où vous habitez.
[ar:]مكانكم هنا رائع[fix] ساعدني يا النملة الكبيرة[fix]
[ru:]А вы неплохо устроились.[fix]
[zh:]蚂蚁 帮哥们一把
[en:]Give me a hand, Ant.[fix]
[fre:]Aide-moi, Ant.
[ar:](هذا (يانغ غاو[fix]
[ko:]그렇게 안 좋은 곳에 사는건 아니구나.[fix]
[ru:]Муравей, дай руку.[fix]
[zh:]接一下羊搞
[en:]This is Yang Gao.[fix]
[fre:]Voici Yang Gao.
[ru:]Это Янг Гао.[fix]
[zh:]怎么这么慢才回来
[en:]What took you so long?[fix]
[fre:]T'as pris ton temps !
[ar:]ما الذي أخرك؟[fix]
[ko:]도와줘, 개미야.[fix]
[ru:]Ты чего так долго?[fix]
[zh:]你好 她是米兰 你好
[en:]This is Mi Lan. Hi.[fix]
[fre:]- Voici Mi Lan. - Salut.
[ar:]مرحبا - (هذه (مي لان -
[ko:]얘가 양가오야.[fix] 왜 이렇게 오래 걸렸어?[fix] - 이쪽은 미란이야.  - 안녕.[fix]
[ru:]- Это Ми Лань - Привет![fix]
[zh:]谢谢
[fre:]Tiens, un eskimo.[fix]
[zh:]快渴死了
[en:]Have an ice-pop.[fix] Thanks, I was dying of thirst.[fix]
[fre:]Merci, je mourais de chaud.
[ar:]شكرا، سأموت من العطش[fix]
[ko:]아이스캔디 먹어.[fix] 고마워, 목말라 죽을거 같았는데.[fix]
[ru:]Фруктовый лед хочешь?[fix] Спасибо. То, что надо, пить хочу.[fix]
[zh:]你怎么会从这儿过来 多悬啦
[en:]It's dangerous to come this way?[fix]
[fre:]Ce n'est pas dangereux de passer par là ?
[ar:]لماذا جئتَ من هنا؟ هذا خطير[fix]
[ru:]А это не опасно здесь ходить?[fix]
[zh:]这儿 捷径 捷径
[en:]It's a short cut.[fix]
[fre:]C'est un raccourci.
[ar:]إنه اختصار
[ko:]이쪽으로 다니는건 위험하지 않니?[fix]
[ru:]Зато короче.[fix]
[zh:]你知道今天放什么片子吗
[en:]Know which film's on tonight?[fix]
[fre:]Tu sais quel film il passe ce soir ?
[ar:]أتعرفون أي فيلم سيعرض الليلة؟ - ما هو؟ -[fix]
[ko:]여기가 지름길이거든.[fix] 오늘밤 어떤 영화하는지 알아?[fix]
[ru:]Знаете, какое сегодня кино?[fix]
[zh:]什么呀
[fre:]Lequel ?
[ar:](لينين بعام 1918)
[zh:][列宁在一九一八]
[en:]Which?[fix]
[fre:]"Lénine en 1918".
[ar:]!حقا؟ رائع[fix]
[ru:]Какое?[fix]
[zh:]真的 是吗
[en:]"Lenin in 1918".
[fre:]Vraiment ?
[ru:]"Ленин в 1918 году"
[zh:]瓦西里
[en:]Really?[fix] Great. Vasily![fix]
[fre:]Génial. Vasily... !
[ar:]!(فاسيلي)[fix]
[ko:]뭔데?[fix]
[ru:]Что, правда?[fix] Классно! Василий![fix]
[zh:]让我来
[en:]Quick, take this.[fix]
[fre:]Hé, attends.
[ar:]بسرعة، اقفز[fix]
[ko:]"1918년 레닌"[fix] 정말?[fix] 이야~. 바실리...![fix]
[ru:]Держись![fix]
[zh:]捷尔任斯基
[fre:]Va vite dire à Kerensky...
[ru:]Беги и расскажи, что Керенский...[fix]
[zh:]布哈林
[en:]Quick go tell Kerenshy...[fix] Bukharin[fix]
[fre:]Boukharine...
[ar:](قل لـ(كيرينسكي) أن (بوخارين"  و(تروتسكي) خائنان[fix]
[ru:]Бухарин,[fix]
[zh:]洛夫斯基
[en:]Trotsky[fix]
[fre:]Trotski...
[ru:]Троцкий[fix]
[zh:]他们是叛徒
[en:]are traitors.[fix]
[fre:]sont des traîtres.
[ko:]빨리 가서 케렌스키에거 전해...[fix] 부하린과[fix] 트로츠키가[fix]
[ru:]предатели.[fix]
[zh:]他们要刺杀列宁
[en:]They want to assassinate Lenin.[fix]
[fre:]Ils veulent assassiner Lénine.
[ar:]"(يريدان اغتيال (لينين[fix]
[ru:]Они хотят убить Ленина.[fix]
[zh:]不要紧
[en:]It's all right. BANG BANG![fix]
[fre:]C'est bon. BANG BANG !
[ar:]لا تقلق"
[ko:]반역자들이라고.[fix] 그들이 레닌을 암살하려하고 있어.[fix] 알았어. 빵빵![fix]
[ru:]Все хорошо. Бах, бах![fix]
[zh:]你丫怎么不死呀
[en:]Bastard, die already. BANG![fix]
[fre:]Bâtard, crève ! BANG !
[ar:]"!هيا مت يا وغد[fix]
[ko:]야 이 새끼야, 벌써 죽었어. 빵![fix]
[ru:]Умри, ублюдок. Бах![fix]
[zh:]哎 那女的 一看老战士
[en:]That girl really looks an old trooper,[fix]
[fre:]Cette fille a l'air d'avoir de l'expérience,
[ar:]يبدو أن لدى هذه الفتاة خبرة[fix]
[ru:]А это девочка, похоже, видала виды.[fix]
[zh:]屁股都给操圆了
[en:]her ass is round from too much fucking.[fix]
[fre:]elle a le cul bien rond à force de trop baiser.
[ar:]مؤخرتها مدورة من كثر المضاجعة[fix]
[ru:]Смотри, какая задница круглая. Это от постоянного трахания.[fix]
[zh:]我抽你丫
[en:]I'll kill you![fix]
[fre:]J'vais te tuer !
[ar:]!سأقضي عليك[fix]
[ko:]저 여자애, 꼭 말(馬)같지 않냐?[fix] 엉덩이가 거시기를 많이해서 그런가  빵빵하잖아.[fix] 너 죽여버린다![fix]
[ru:]Я тебя убью![fix]
[zh:]你觉得她好看吗
[fre:]Tu crois qu'elle est bien foutue ?
[ar:]أتعتقد أنها جميلة؟[fix]
[ru:]Слушай, ну она и красавица.[fix]
[zh:]好看
[en:]Do you think she's good looking?
[fre:]À ton avis.
[ar:]طبعا
[zh:]那你动过她了
[en:]You bet.[fix] Have you made a move yet?[fix]
[fre:]Tu as déjà conclu ?
[ar:]هل قد ضاجعتَها؟
[ko:]니가 보기에 쟤 이쁘냐?[fix] 당근이지.[fix] 벌써 해본거야?[fix]
[ru:]А то![fix] Ты уже к ней подкатывал?[fix]
[zh:]你想我能闲着吗
[en:]What d'ya reckon?[fix]
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que tu crois ?
[ar:]أتظن أن بإمكاني مغازلتها؟
[ru:]А ты думал?[fix]
[zh:]哎 发兄弟我一个
[en:]Get one for me, too, please.[fix]
[fre:]Trouve-m'en une pour moi aussi ?
[ar:]ماذا عن تدبير ذلك لأخيك أيضا؟
[ko:]너 무슨 생각하고 있는거야?[fix]
[ru:]Слушай, а найди мне кого-нибудь.[fix]
[zh:]发兄弟我一个吧
[en:]Please? One for me too?[fix]
[fre:]S'il te plaît ? Une pour moi ?
[ar:]مرة واحدة لأخيك؟[fix]
[ko:]나도 한 번만 하게 해주라.[fix] 제발...나도 한 번만..[fix]
[ru:]Ну пожалуйста, ну тебе трудно что ли?[fix]
[zh:]起来
[en:]Get up![fix]
[fre:]Pousse-toi !
[ar:]ابتعد[fix]
[ru:]Отвали![fix]
[zh:]我操 站住
[en:]Shit, hold it right there![fix]
[fre:]Merde ! Reviens là !
[ar:]!اللعنة! توقف[fix]
[ko:]저리 비켜![fix] 제기랄, 거기 서![fix]
[ru:]Стоять, дерьмо![fix]
[zh:]你要会拉小提琴就好了
[en:]If only you could play violin.[fix]
[fre:]Si seulement tu jouais du violon,
[ar:]ليتك تجيدين عزف الكمان[fix]
[ru:]Если бы вы только могли играть на скрипке.[fix]
[zh:]我爹他们文工团就缺一小提琴
[en:]My dad's cultural troupe needs a violinist.[fix]
[fre:]la troupe culturelle de mon père à besoin d'un violoniste.
[ar:]فرقة أبي الثقافية بحاجة لعازف كمان[fix]
[ru:]Ансамблю моего отца нужен скрипач.[fix]
[zh:]能弹琵琶不能拉小提琴吗
[en:]Can't you play violin if you play pipe?[fix]
[fre:]On peut pas jouer du violon quand on sait jouer de la pipa ?
[ar:](أليس من يجيد عزف الـ(بيبا يجيد عزف الكمان؟[fix]
[ko:]네가 바이올린 할 수 있으면.[fix] 내 아버지가 운영하는 문화단에서  바이올리니스트가 필요하다는데.[fix]
[ru:]Раве ты не сумеешь играть на скрипке, если играешь на пипе (китайская лютня)?[fix]
[zh:]两回事
[fre:]C'est différent.
[ar:]إنهما مختلفان[fix]
[zh:]一个是弹拨乐 一个是弦乐
[en:]They're different.[fix] You pluck one and use a bow on the other.[fix]
[fre:]Pour l'un on pince, pour l'autre on se sert d'un archet.[fix]
[ar:]الأول يعزف بالأصابع والآخر بالقوس[fix]
[ko:]비파 할 줄 알면 바이올린도 할 줄 아는거 아냐?[fix]
[ru:]Это разные вещи.[fix] Тут щиплешь струны, а там играешь смычком.[fix]
[zh:]得使弓子
[ar:]يجب استخدام القوس
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan![fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:](مي لان)[fix]
[ko:]그 두가지는 달라.[fix] 하나는 뜯는거고,  다른 하나는 활로 연주하는거야.[fix] 미란![fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань![fix]
[zh:]你可千万别进他爹那文工团
[en:]Don't join his dad's troupe whatever you do.[fix]
[fre:]Ne rejoins surtout pas la troupe de son père.
[ar:]افعلي أي شيء إلا الانضمام لفرقة والده[fix]
[ru:]Не вздумай идти в ансамбль его отца.[fix]
[zh:]你去了 先让他爹给糟蹋了
[en:]His father would ravage you first off.[fix]
[fre:]Son père voudra coucher avec toi avant toutes choses.
[ar:]سيتحرش بك والده عندما يراك مباشرة
[ko:]뭘 할줄 알던간에,  그 문화단에는 들어가지 마.[fix]
[ru:]Его отец первым делом тебя... испортит.[fix]
[zh:]马猴 记错了吧 那是你爹
[en:]Monkey. sure you're not thinking of your dad?[fix]
[fre:]Monkey, tu es sûr de ne pas confondre avec ton père ?
[ar:]يا قرد، متأكد أنك لا تتكلم عن والدك أنت؟
[ko:]류이쿠 아버지가 제일 먼저  널 가만두지 않을거야.[fix] 원숭아, 너, 니 아버지 생각은 안 하냐?[fix]
[ru:]Обезьяна, а ты уверен, что ты не про своего отца говоришь?[fix]
[zh:]你爹不是因为作风问题降的职吗
[en:]He's the one who got demoted for bad... behavior.[fix]
[fre:]C'est lui qui s'est fait rétrograder pour mauvaises... habitudes.
[ar:]أليس هو من أنزلوا رتبته لسوء السلوك؟[fix]
[ru:]Это ведь его понизили в должности из-за плохих привычек.[fix]
[zh:]你爹 那是你爹
[en:]Your dad! It was yours![fix]
[fre:]C'était ton père ! Le tien ! Il avait deux femmes,[fix]
[ar:]!هذا أبوك أنت
[ko:]니 아버지, 나쁜...짓 해서, 강등당했잖아.[fix]
[ru:]Твоего отца! Это - про твоего отца![fix]
[zh:]反正我听说 你爹有俩老婆
[en:]He has two wives.[fix]
[ar:]سمعتُ أنه متزوج اثنتين
[ru:]У него две жены.
[zh:]一个在乡下 一个就是现在的
[en:]one in the country, and one here.[fix]
[fre:]une au pays, et l'autre là-bas.
[ar:]واحدة في الريف و واحدة جديدة
[ko:]그거 니 아버지 얘기지![fix]
[ru:]Одна в провинции, другая здесь.
[zh:]要不你们怎么一个 叫忆苦一个叫思甜呢
[en:]That's why you're Sitian - "thinking sweetness" and he's Yiku - "recalling bitterness".[fix]
[fre:]C'est pour ça que tu t'appelles Sitian "la douce pensée"[fix] et lui Yiku "le souvenir amer".[fix]
[ar:](لماذا تعتقد أن هذا يدعى سيان (فكرة حلوة والآخر إيكو (ذكرى مُرة) ؟[fix]
[ko:]류이쿠 아버지는 부인이 둘이 있어.[fix] 한 명은 시골에, 한 명은 여기에.[fix] 그게 네 이름은 '시챤'('달콤함을 생각함')이고,  쟤는 '이쿠'('쓴맛을 생각함')인 까닭이야.[fix]
[ru:]Поэтому ты Сытиань - "воображаемая сладость",[fix]
[zh:]回去问家长吧
[en:]Monkey's insulting your dad... shall we beat him up?[fix]
[fre:]Monkey insulte ton père, on le tape ?[fix]
[ar:]القرد يسيء لوالدك هل نلقنه درسا؟[fix] لا عليك...دعنا نعامله باحترام اليوم[fix]
[ko:]원숭이가 네 아버지를 모욕했어. 우리가 패줄까?[fix]
[ru:]а он Еку - "напоминающий горечь".[fix] Обезьяна оскорбляет нашего отца - давай ему вломим![fix]
[zh:]今天怎么啦
[fre:]Laisse tomber, on le tapera plus tard.[fix]
[zh:]得 得 得 甭这么着急 我又不是马上就去文工团
[en:]Forget it, let's give him a bit of face today.[fix] Enough, already, no need for panic.[fix]
[fre:]Ça suffit, pas besoin de s'emporter ainsi.
[ar:]يكفي، لا داعي لهذا الذعر[fix] أحقا تعتقد أني سأنضم للفرقة في هذه اللحظة؟[fix]
[ko:]됐어, 오늘은  저녀석 얼굴 좀 세워주지 뭐.[fix] 이제 그만해. 흥분할 필요 없잖아.[fix]
[ru:]Давайте только без мордобоя сегодня.[fix] Да хватит вам, было бы из-за чего спорить.[fix]
[zh:]哎 你是特别想当兵吗
[en:]I'm not going to join the troupe today.[fix]
[fre:]- Tu veux vraiment aller dans l'armée ? - Oui.[fix]
[ar:]إذن أتريدين حقا الانضمام للجيش؟
[ko:]오늘은 그 단체에 가입할 생각이 없으니까.[fix]
[ru:]Я не собираюсь поступать в ансамбль его отца.[fix]
[zh:]想啊
[ar:]أجل[fix]
[zh:]你干嘛不去考战友呢
[en:]So do you really want to join the army? Yes.[fix]
[fre:]Essaie la troupe des Amis des Soldats.
[ar:]وماذا ستفعلين؟ ستجربين المشاركة في فرقة (أصدقاء الجنود)؟
[ko:]- 너 정말로 군대에 가고 싶어?  - 응.[fix]
[ru:]- Ты действительно собираешься вступить в армию? - Да.[fix]
[zh:]我还想考总政呢
[en:]Try out for "The Soldiers' Friends" troupe.[fix] I'm aiming for "Political Headquarters".[fix]
[fre:]Je vise plutôt le quartier général.
[ar:]أسعى لمنصب سياسي[fix]
[ko:]그러지 말고, "군인의 벗들"에 들어가봐.[fix] 난 "정치 사령부"에 들어가려고 해.[fix]
[ru:]Тогда иди в ансамбль "Солдатские друзья"[fix] Я хочу попробоваться в "Политический штаб".[fix]
[zh:]你会弹琵琶 一定会弹吉它
[en:]Mi Lan, if you play the pipe, you can play guitar, can't you?[fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan, si tu joues de la pipa, tu sais jouer de la guitare, non ?
[ar:](مي لان)، من يجيد عزف الـ(بيبا) يجيد عزف الغيتار، صحيح؟[fix]
[ru:]Ма Лань, если ты играешь на пипе, ты, наверное, и на гитаре сможешь?[fix]
[zh:]那还差不多
[en:]More or less.[fix]
[fre:]Plus ou moins.
[ar:]تقريبا
[ko:]미란, 비파를 연주할 줄 알면, 기타도 칠 줄 알겠네?[fix]
[ru:]Более-менее.[fix]
[zh:]我家有把琴 我去给你拿来
[fre:]On a une guitare. Je vais la chercher.[fix]
[ar:]لدينا آلة (غوتشين) في المنزل سأحضرها لك[fix]
[zh:]你丫闹不闹啊
[en:]We've got a guitar. I'll go get it.[fix] Keep your pants on.[fix]
[fre:]Calme-toi !
[ar:]عما تتحدث بحق الجحيم؟
[ko:]조금은.[fix]
[ru:]А у нас есть гитара. Я сбегаю, принесу.[fix] Штаны не потеряй.[fix]
[zh:]我想飞
[en:]I want to fly![fix]
[fre:]Je voudrais m'envoler !
[ar:]!أريد أن أطير
[ko:]우리 기타 있어.  가서 가져올게.[fix] 니 바지나 잘 챙겨.[fix]
[ru:]Я хочу летать![fix]
[zh:]我想飞上天空
[ar:]أريد أن أطير عاليا في السماء عبر السحب[fix]
[ko:]날고 싶다![fix]
[zh:]飞入云霄
[zh:]我要飞向克里姆林宫
[en:]I want to fly into the skies all way to the Kremlin.[fix]
[fre:]Je voudrais m'envoler dans le ciel jusqu'au Kremlin.[fix]
[ar:](إلى أن أصل إلى...(الكرملين[fix]
[ko:]크레믈린을 향해 창공을 날아가고 싶어.[fix]
[ru:]Я хочу лететь по небу к Кремлю![fix]
[zh:]我要飞向列宁格勒
[en:]To Leningrad.[fix]
[fre:]Vers Leningrad.
[ar:](سأطير إلى (لينينغراد[fix]
[ko:]레닌그라드로.[fix]
[ru:]И к Ленинграду![fix]
[zh:]飞呀 飞呀
[fre:]Vole ! Vole ![fix]
[ar:]طر إذن - أجل، طر -[fix]
[zh:]飞呀 飞呀 还是飞呀
[en:]Fly! Fly![fix]
[ar:]!لمَ أنت جالس؟ هيا[fix]
[ru:]Так лети, блин, лети![fix]
[zh:]坐着干嘛
[en:]Why sit down?[fix]
[fre:]Pourquoi tu t'assois ?
[ko:]날아! 날아![fix]
[ru:]Что ты сел?[fix]
[zh:]我要登高远望
[en:]I want to ascend the heights and revel in the view.[fix]
[fre:]Je veux atteindre les hauteurs et me délecter de la vue.
[ar:]سأصعد إلى الأعالي وأتمعن المنظر من بعيد[fix]
[ko:]왜 앉냐?[fix]
[ru:]Давай, лети![fix]
[zh:]今儿个马猴是有点不一样
[fre:]Monkey a l'air différent aujourd'hui.
[ar:]القرد يبدو اليوم مختلفا بعض الشيء[fix]
[zh:]说起话来倍儿有诗意
[en:]Monkey seems a bit different today.[fix] He's talking all poetic.[fix]
[fre:]Il parle comme un poète.
[ar:]يتحدث بشكل شاعري
[ko:]나는 높이 올라가, 풍경에 빠지고 싶어.[fix]
[ru:]Обезьяна сегодня какой-то странный.[fix] Поэтичный такой стал...[fix]
[zh:]是吗
[en:]Really?[fix]
[fre:]Ah bon ?
[ar:]حقا؟
[ko:]원숭이가 오늘은 조금 달라보이네.[fix] 시적인 말만 하잖아.[fix] 진짜?[fix]
[ru:]Правда?[fix]
[zh:]你干嘛那么吓人 一惊一乍的
[en:]Stop scaring us like that.[fix]
[fre:]Arrête de nous effrayer comme ça.
[ar:]ما الذي تفعله؟ تخيف الجميع هكذا[fix]
[ru:]Хватит уже нас пугать.[fix]
[zh:]没听说他要登高远望吗
[en:]Didn't he say he wanted to ascend the heights?[fix]
[fre:]Il n'a pas dit qu'il voulait atteindre les hauteurs ?
[ar:]ألم يقل أنه يريد الصعود للأعالي؟
[ko:]놀래키는 행동은 그만해.[fix]
[ru:]А разве он не сказал, что хотел бы подняться ввысь?[fix]
[zh:]这儿也不算高啊
[en:]This isn't a "height"![fix]
[fre:]Ce n'est pas ici le plus haut.
[ar:]ولكن هذا المكان ليس عاليا لهذا الحد[fix]
[ko:]쟤는 높은데 올라가고 싶대잖아.[fix]
[ru:]Какая это высота.[fix]
[zh:]你们这儿还有更高的地儿吗
[en:]Isn't there anyplace higher in this compound?[fix]
[fre:]Il n'y a pas de point plus haut dans le quartier ?
[ar:]أيوجد مكان أعلى من هذا؟[fix]
[ru:]Разве здесь нет ничего повыше?[fix]
[zh:]大烟囱
[en:]Yes, the smokestack over there.[fix]
[fre:]Si, la cheminée, là-bas.
[ar:]أجل، تلك المدخنة[fix]
[ko:]여기는 높지 않지![fix] 여기에 더 높은 데 없어?[fix]
[ru:]Конечно есть! Вон та труба.[fix]
[zh:]那儿 那儿 那儿高
[en:]That's a height![fix]
[fre:]Ça, c'est haut !
[ar:]هناك، هذا ارتفاع كبير
[ru:]Вон какая высокая.[fix]
[zh:]羊搞 你别来劲
[en:]Yang Gao, don't stir him up.[fix]
[fre:]Yang Gao, ne le pousse pas.
[ar:]يانغ غاو)، بلا مزاح)[fix]
[ko:]있지. 저쪽에 굴뚝 있어.[fix] 저거 높아![fix]
[ru:]Янг Гао, не подначивай его.[fix]
[zh:]你怎么不上去呀
[fre:]À moins que tu veuilles essayer. Tu y vas et on regarde.[fix]
[ar:]ما رأيك أن تذهب أنت أولا ونحن سنشاهد[fix]
[zh:]你先上去我看看
[en:]Unless you want to try.
[ru:]Что - испугался?
[zh:]我没说要登高远望
[en:]You go and we'll watch.[fix] I didn't say I wanted to ascend the heights.[fix]
[fre:]Je n'ai pas dit que je voulais atteindre les hauteurs.
[ar:]لستُ من قال أني أريد صعود الأعالي[fix]
[ko:]양가오, 부추기지 마.[fix] 니가 할 것도 아니잖아.[fix] 우리가 가서 구경해줄까?[fix]
[ru:]Иди, залезь, а мы посмотрим.[fix] Я не говорил, что хочу подняться на высоту.[fix]
[zh:]这上面 上去过人吗
[fre:]- Personne n'a déjà atteint le sommet ? - Si, moi ![fix]
[ar:]هل سبق أن تسلق أحد للقمة؟[fix]
[zh:]我上去过
[en:]Has anyway ever climbed to the top?
[ru:]А вообще кто-нибудь туда лазил?
[zh:]是吗
[en:]I have![fix] Really![fix]
[fre:]Vraiment !
[ar:]أنا - حقا؟ -[fix]
[ko:]나는 높은 데 올라가고 싶다고  말한적 없어.[fix] 저 높은데 올라가본 적 있어?[fix] 올라가봤지![fix]
[ru:]Я лазил.[fix] Правда?[fix]
[zh:]可以啊
[fre:]Tu es vraiment fort !
[ar:]أنت عجيب[fix]
[zh:]表演一回给咱们看
[en:]You're really something!
[fre:]Montre-nous !
[ar:]لمَ لا ترنا؟
[ru:]Это действительно круто.
[zh:]算了
[en:]Show us![fix] Forget it.[fix]
[fre:]Laisse tomber.
[ar:]مستحيل
[ko:]진짜?![fix] 너 정말 대단하구나![fix] 보여줘 봐![fix]
[ru:]А ну-ка, залезь![fix] Забудь.[fix]
[zh:]来一回 让米兰也开开眼
[fre:]Allez, montre-lui !
[ar:]هيا، دع (مي لان) تراك وأنت تفعلها[fix]
[zh:]下来我给你两包牡丹过滤
[en:]Come on, show her![fix] We'll give you two packs of cigarettes.[fix]
[fre:]On te donnera deux paquets de cigarettes.
[ar:](سنعطيك علبتين من سجائر (الفاونيا
[ko:]집어쳐.[fix]
[ru:]Давай, покажи ей.[fix] А мы тебе две пачки сигарет дадим.[fix]
[zh:]玩去 两包
[en:]Get lost. Just two?[fix]
[fre:]Oublie ça. Que deux ?
[ar:]علبتين فقط؟[fix]
[ko:]어서, 쟤 앞에서 보여줘 봐![fix] 우리가 담배 두 갑 사줄게.[fix]
[ru:]Обломись. За две пачки?[fix]
[zh:]再加两包凤凰过滤
[ar:](و علبتين من (فينكس بالرياح
[zh:]苦哥 上一回 四包过滤了
[en:]Plus two packs of filters.[fix] There were four last time.[fix]
[fre:]- Plus deux paquets de filtres. - Il y en avait quatre la dernière fois.[fix]
[ar:]صحيح، حصل على 4 علب عندما صعد بالمرة السابقة
[ko:]집어쳐. 겨우 두 갑?[fix] 필터 담배 두 갑 추가.[fix] 이제 4갑이네.[fix]
[ru:]Плюс еще две пачки с фильтром.[fix] Итого - четыре пачки.[fix]
[zh:]我上去过
[en:]But I've been up there before.[fix]
[fre:]Mais je l'ai déjà fait avant.
[ar:]لكني قد سبق وفعلتها
[ru:]Но я уже туда лазил.[fix]
[zh:]好汉不提当年勇
[en:]A here doesn't bring up past glories.[fix]
[fre:]Ça ne compte plus aujourd'hui.
[ar:]البطل لا يستحضر أمجاد الماضي
[ru:]Прошлые заслуги в расчет не принимаются.[fix]
[zh:]不要吃老本 要立新功嘛
[en:]Don't rest on your laurels, make new contributions![fix]
[fre:]Ne te repose pas sur tes lauriers, recommence !
[ar:]لا يجب الرضى بإنجاز وحيد !قم بإسهامات جديدة[fix]
[ko:]전에 올라가봤다니까.[fix] 영웅은 과거의 영광만을 내세우면 안 되지.[fix] 과거의 명예에 안주하지 말고, 새로운 공헌을 하라![fix]
[ru:]Не почивай на лаврах, соверши новый подвиг.[fix]
[zh:]你怎么不立新功啊
[fre:]Pourquoi tu ne le fais pas, toi ?
[ar:]لمَ لا تقم أنت بإسهامات جديدة؟[fix]
[zh:]哎 这样吧
[en:]Why don't you do us?
[fre:]Que dis-tu de ça,
[ru:]А что бы тебе не полезть?
[zh:]四包过滤都归你
[en:]How about this...
[ru:]Давай так:
[zh:]再加两包中华怎么样
[en:]four packs of filtertips,[fix] plus two of Cathay.[fix]
[fre:]quatre paquets de filtres, plus deux Cathay.[fix]
[ar:]ماذا عن...4 علب من فلتر السجائر إضافة لعلبتين من (كاذيس)؟[fix]
[ko:]그럼 니가 해보지 그래?[fix] 그럼 이건 어때?[fix] 필터 담배 네 갑에,[fix] 캐세이 담배 두 갑 추가.[fix]
[ru:]четыре пачки с фильтром,[fix] и еще две пачки китайских.[fix]
[zh:]真的
[fre:]Sérieux ?
[ar:]!موافق
[zh:]哎 马小军
[en:]Your serious?[fix]
[fre:]Ma Xiaojun ![fix]
[ar:]!(ماشياو جون)
[ko:]진짜지?[fix] 마샤오준!...[fix]
[ru:]Идет![fix]
[zh:]马小军
[en:]Ma Xiaojun![fix]
[ar:]!(ماشياو جون)[fix]
[ru:]Ма Сяоцзюнь![fix]
[zh:]他真去了
[fre:]Il va vraiment le faire !
[ar:]!سيفعلها حقا
[zh:]不会的 他根本就不知道从哪儿上
[en:]He's really going to do it![fix] No way. He doesn't know how to get up there.[fix]
[fre:]Non. Il ne sait pas comment y accéder.
[ar:]مستحيل. لا يعرف كيف يصعد إلى هناك
[ko:]진짜로 올라가려나봐![fix] 아니야. 쟤는 거기에  어떻게 올라가는지도 몰라.[fix]
[ru:]Он и вправду полез.[fix] Не бойся. Он к трубе и не подойдет.[fix]
[zh:]下半截扶手缠着铁丝网哪
[fre:]Des barbelés empêchent l'accès à l'échelle.[fix]
[ar:]السلم مغطى بلفات من الأسلاك الشائكة لا يمكنه الصعود[fix]
[zh:]上不去
[zh:]蚂蚁 他上不去吧
[en:]Rolls of barbed wire are blocking the ladder.[fix]
[ar:]أيمكنه الصعود يا النملة؟ - مستحيل، إنه يحاول إخافتنا وحسب -[fix]
[ko:]사다리에 가시 철조망이 쳐 있어.[fix]
[ru:]Там все колючей проволокой огорожено.[fix]
[zh:]不会的 他吓唬你的 真的
[en:]He's just trying to scare us. Don't worry.[fix]
[fre:]Il veut juste nous faire peur. Ne t'inquiète pas.
[ru:]Это он просто понтуется. Не переживай.[fix]
[zh:]没事 他一会儿准会来
[en:]He'll be back in no time.[fix]
[fre:]Il va revenir en un rien de temps.
[ar:]حقا يا (مي لان)، سيعود فورا[fix]
[ko:]우리를 놀래줄려고 하는거 뿐이야. 걱정 마.[fix] 곧 돌아올거야.[fix]
[ru:]Сейчас вернется.[fix]
[zh:]瓦西里
[fre:]Vasily !
[ar:]!(فاسيلي)[fix]
[zh:]在那儿 在那儿呐
[en:]Vasily![fix] There he is![fix]
[fre:]Le voilà !
[ar:]!هناك! إنه هناك
[ko:]바실리![fix] 저깄다![fix]
[ru:]Василий![fix] Вон он![fix]
[zh:]瓦西里
[zh:]真是马猴呢
[zh:]丫怎么上去的
[en:]Vasily! Vasily! Ha Ha![fix]
[fre:]Vasily ! Vasily ![fix]
[ar:]أهذا هو القرد حقا؟ - كيف صعد بحق الجحيم؟ -[fix]
[ko:]바실리! 바실리! 하하![fix]
[ru:]Василий! Василий! О-го-го!!![fix]
[zh:]瓦西里
[ar:]!(فاسيلي)[fix] !(فاسيلي)[fix]
[zh:]下来吧 你丫怎么下来呀
[fre:]Descends de là, maintenant ![fix]
[ar:]!انزل - !بسرعة انزل يا قرد -[fix]
[zh:]快下来 你下来 马猴
[en:]Get down from there, now![fix]
[ru:]Слезай оттуда, придурок![fix]
[zh:]瓦西里
[en:]Vasily![fix]
[fre:]Vasily !
[ar:]!(فاسيلي)[fix]
[ko:]당장 내려와![fix] 바실리![fix]
[ru:]Василий![fix]
[zh:]马猴 你丫别乱动
[en:]Don't be stupid! Monkey![fix]
[fre:]Ne fais pas l'idiot ! Monkey !
[ar:]!انزل - !بلا عبث يا قرد -[fix]
[ru:]Не будь дураком, Обезьяна![fix]
[zh:]下来吧
[en:]Get down from there, now![fix]
[fre:]Descends de là, maintenant !
[ar:]!انزل - !هيا يا قرد -[fix]
[ko:]바보같은 짓 하지마! 원숭아![fix]
[ru:]Слезай, идиот![fix]
[zh:]下来吧
[ar:]!انزل - !انزل -[fix]
[ko:]당장 내려와![fix]
[zh:]走
[fre:]Viens !
[ar:]!استقبل
[zh:]我操
[en:]Coming!
[fre:]Putain !
[ar:]!اللعنة
[ru:]Ловите!
[zh:]马猴 别扔了
[en:]Shit!
[fre:]Voilà l'autre !
[ru:]Блин!
[zh:]快下来
[en:]Here's another![fix]
[ar:]!يا قرد، انزل بسرعة[fix]
[ko:]간다![fix] 빌어먹을![fix] 여기 또 한짝![fix]
[ru:]А вот второй![fix]
[zh:]别扔了 快下来吧 下来吧
[en:]Come down, Monkey![fix]
[fre:]Descends, Monkey !
[ar:]!لا ترمه يا قرد - !انزل -[fix]
[ru:]Слезай, Обезьяна![fix]
[zh:]快下来
[en:]You mad?[fix]
[fre:]T'es timbré ?[fix]
[ar:]!هيا - !أنت مجنون -
[ko:]원숭아, 내려와![fix]
[ru:]С  ума сошел?[fix]
[zh:]疯了
[zh:]我们都是神枪手
[en:]We're all excellent shots[fix]
[fre:]Nous sommes tous de bons tireurs,
[ar:]جميعنا ماهرون في القنص[fix]
[ko:]너 미쳤어?[fix] 우리는 모두 명사수라네.[fix]
[ru:]Мы все - превосходные стрелки...[fix]
[zh:]每一颗子弹消灭一个敌人
[en:]and each bullet takes down an enemy.[fix]
[fre:]et chacune de nos balles atteint l'ennemi.
[ar:]كل رصاصة منّا تسقط عدواً[fix]
[ru:]и каждая пуля находит врага.[fix]
[zh:]马猴 马猴 马猴 马小军
[en:]Ma Xiaojun, where are you?[fix]
[fre:]Ma Xiaojun, t'es où ?
[ar:]يا قرد - يا قرد أين أنت؟ -
[ko:]모든 총알이 적들을 쓰러뜨릴지니.[fix]
[ru:]Ма Сяоцзюнь, ты что делаешь!?[fix]
[zh:]不喊了
[zh:]会吓着他的
[fre:]Il faut faire quelque chose ![fix]
[ar:]!لا تصرخوا عليه! سيخاف[fix]
[ko:]마샤오준, 너 어디 있냐?[fix]
[zh:]哎哟 冒烟了
[fre:]Putain, il est plus là ![fix]
[ar:]!دخان[fix]
[ru:]Смотри! Он упал![fix]
[zh:]马小军
[fre:]Ma Xiaojun ! T'es où ?[fix]
[ar:]!(ماشياو جون)[fix]
[zh:]你在哪儿
[ar:]أين أنت؟[fix]
[ru:]Ма Сяоцзюнь! Отзовись![fix]
[zh:]给我买烟去
[fre:]Allez m'acheter mes cigarettes !
[en:]Go buy my cigarettes!
[fre:]Mes cigarettes !
[ru:]Иди покупай мои сигареты.
[zh:]给我买烟去
[en:]My cigarettes!
[fre:]Mes cigarettes !
[zh:]给我买烟去
[en:]My cigarettes![fix] My cigarettes![fix]
[fre:]Mes cigarettes !
[ar:]!اذهبوا واشتروا سجائري[fix]
[ko:]내 담배 사와![fix] 내 담배![fix] 내 담배![fix] 내 담배![fix]
[ru:]Мои сигареты![fix]
[zh:]米兰 你今晚别走了
[en:]Mi Lan, don't go away.[fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan, ne pars pas.
[ar:]مي لان)، لا تذهبي الآن) ابقي للفيلم الليلة[fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань, не уходи.[fix]
[zh:]跟这儿看电影
[en:]Stay for the film tonight.[fix]
[fre:]Reste pour le film de ce soir.
[ko:]미란, 가지 마.[fix] 오늘밤 같이 영화 보자.[fix]
[ru:]Давай вечером в кино сходим.[fix]
[zh:]大家都觉得我是个神奇的人
[en:]Everyone said I was charmed.[fix]
[fre:]Tout le monde a dit que j'avais eu de la chance.
[ar:]الكل قال أني كنت محاطا بالسحر[fix]
[ru:]Все сказали, что я заколдованный.[fix]
[zh:]那时候 还没有人体特异功能的传说
[en:]No one talked about supernatural powers then...[fix]
[fre:]Personne n'a parlé de pouvoirs surnaturels...
[ar:]لم يتحدث أحد عن القوى الخارقة للطبيعة بذاك الوقت[fix]
[ko:]애들은 내가 뭔가에 홀린거라고 말했다.[fix]
[ru:]Никто об этом чуде не рассказал,[fix]
[zh:]不然我早出名了
[en:]otherwise I'd have been famous.[fix]
[fre:]Dommage, je serais devenu célèbre.
[ar:]وإلا لكنتُ مشهورا[fix]
[ko:]아무도 내가 그 때 보여준 초인적인 힘에 대해 말하지 않았다.[fix]
[ru:]и славы героя из сказки мне не досталось.[fix]
[zh:]后来才知道 是大烟囱那上升的气流
[en:]Later I figured out that it was the upward draft[fix]
[fre:]Plus tard, je me suis aperçu que c'était la poussière
[ar:]اكتشفتُ لاحقا أن نجاتي كانت بسبب هواء المدخنة المتصاعد
[ko:]그렇지 않았으면, 난 유명해졌을 것이다.[fix]
[ru:]Позже я узнал, что все дело было в восходящей тяге[fix]
[zh:]和沉积多年的烟灰 救了我一命
[en:]and years of accumulated ashes that saved my life.[fix]
[fre:]et les années de cendres accumulées qui m'ont sauvé la vie.
[ar:].وسنوات من الرماد المتراكم[fix]
[ko:]훗날 나는 깨달았다.  내 생명을 살린 것은,[fix] 굴뚝속에서 위로 올라오는 대류와  수 년 동안 쌓인 재였다는 사실을.[fix]
[ru:]и годами копившемся пепле, который спас мне жизнь.[fix]
[zh:]你把人给吓死了
[en:]You scared us to death.[fix]
[fre:]Tu nous as vraiment fait peur.
[ar:]أخفتنا كثيرا[fix]
[ru:]Ты испугал нас до смерти.[fix]
[zh:]居然没受伤
[en:]You're not even scratched![fix]
[fre:]Tu n'as même pas une égratignure !
[ar:]!ولم تصب بأي أذى حتى
[ru:]Ни одной царапины![fix]
[zh:]你也真够神的
[en:]Amazing![fix]
[fre:]Incroyable !
[ar:]تكاد تكون شيئا خارقا
[ko:]넌 우리를 너무 놀래켰어.[fix] 그런데도 상처 하나 없다니![fix] 놀라워![fix]
[ru:]Невероятно.[fix]
[zh:]干嘛傻愣着不说话
[en:]Cat got your tongue?[fix]
[fre:]Tu as avalé ta langue ?
[ar:]ما بك يا غبي؟ لم تقل شيئا[fix]
[ko:]왜 꿀먹은 벙어리야?[fix]
[ru:]Язык проглотил?[fix]
[zh:]还挺爱生气的
[en:]What a temper![fix]
[fre:]Quel tempérament !
[ar:]!ولا زلتَ تغضب
[ko:]화났나 보네![fix]
[ru:]Ну и характер.[fix]
[zh:]你不理我 我可走了
[en:]If you won't talk to me. I'll be off.[fix]
[fre:]Si tu ne me parles pas, je vais y aller.
[ar:]إن كنت لا تريد الكلام معي فيمكنني أن اذهب[fix]
[ru:]Если ты будешь молчать, я уйду.[fix]
[zh:]谁生气了
[en:]What temper?[fix]
[fre:]Quoi mon tempérament ?
[ar:]من الذي يغضب؟[fix]
[ko:]나랑 말하기 싫으면, 나 갈래.[fix]
[ru:]А что "характер"?[fix]
[zh:]你是不是特爱跟不认识的男的聊
[en:]So you really like talking with strange boys?[fix]
[fre:]Alors comme ça, tu aimes parler aux étrangers ?[fix]
[ar:]ألا تحبين الكلام مع الفتيان الغريبين؟[fix]
[ko:]화났냐고?[fix] 너는 잘 모르는 다른 애들하고 얘기하는게 진짜 좋아?[fix]
[ru:]Тебе действительно так нравится клеиться к незнакомым парням?[fix]
[zh:]你说呢
[fre:]À quoi tu penses ?
[ar:]ماذا تعتقد أنت؟[fix]
[zh:]我不知道
[en:]What do you think?[fix] Dunno.[fix]
[fre:]J'sais pas.
[ar:]لا أعرف
[ko:]무슨 생각하고 있는거야?[fix] 몰라.[fix]
[ru:]А ты как думаешь?[fix] Я не знаю[fix]
[zh:]还挺爱吃醋的
[en:]I think you're jealous.[fix]
[fre:]Je pense que tu es jaloux.
[ar:]!والآن تغار
[ko:]질투하는구나.[fix]
[ru:]А я думаю, что ты ревнуешь.[fix]
[zh:]行了 我是那样的人吗
[en:]Come on, what sort of girl do you think I am?[fix]
[fre:]Tu me prends pour quelle sorte de fille ?
[ar:]حسنا، أتعتقد حقا أنني فتاة من هذا النوع؟[fix]
[ko:]넌 나를 어떤 여자로 보는거야?[fix]
[ru:]Кем ты меня, интересно, считаешь?[fix]
[zh:]谁吃醋啊
[en:]Who's jealous?[fix]
[fre:]Qui est jaloux ?
[ar:]من يغار؟[fix]
[ru:]А что "ревнуешь"?[fix]
[zh:]那你跟刘忆苦在那儿瞎聊什么
[en:]What were you talking about with Liu Yiku, anyway?[fix]
[fre:]Au fait, de quoi tu parlais avec Liu Yiku ?
[ar:]عما كنت تتحدثين مع (ليو إيكو)؟[fix]
[ko:]누가 질투를 해?[fix] 어쨌든, 네가 류이쿠와  이야기를 하고 있었잖아?[fix]
[ru:]А о чем вы тогда шептались с Лю Еку?[fix]
[zh:]没聊什么呀
[en:]Nothing![fix]
[fre:]De rien !
[ar:]لاشيء مهم[fix]
[ru:]Ни о чем.[fix]
[zh:]就说我想当兵 他说他能帮我
[en:]About joining the army, he said he'd help.[fix]
[fre:]De rejoindre l'armée. Il m'a dit qu'il m'aidera.
[ar:]أخبرتُه أني أريد الانضمام للجيش وقال أنه سيساعدني[fix]
[ko:]그런거 아냐![fix] 군대에 들어가는 이야기 중이었어. 도와준다고 하더라.[fix]
[ru:]Мы говорили о поступлении в армию, он обещал помочь.[fix]
[zh:]我怎么不知道你想当兵啊
[fre:]Tu ne m'avais jamais dit que tu voulais rejoindre l'armée.[fix]
[ar:]لماذا لم أعرف أنك تريدين الانضمام للجيش؟[fix]
[zh:]你从来没跟我说过
[en:]You never told me you wanted to join the army.[fix]
[ar:]لم تخبريني أنك تريدين ذلك
[ru:]Ты никогда мне не говорила, что хочешь пойти в армию.[fix]
[zh:]怎么头一回见他就跟他说啊
[en:]You meet him once and tell him everything.[fix]
[fre:]Tu le vois une fois, et tu lui racontes tout.
[ar:]تقابلينه مرة واحدة وتخبرينه كل شيء[fix]
[ko:]나한테는 군대에 가고 싶다고 말한 적 없잖아.[fix]
[ru:]А его только увидела и уже рассказываешь ему все.[fix]
[zh:]熟得够快的
[en:]Fast mover.[fix]
[fre:]Un peu rapide.
[ar:]...أنت تتنقلين بسرعة[fix]
[ko:]걔는 한 번 만났으면서, 걔한테는 이야기를 다 했어.[fix] 빠르기도 하시지.[fix]
[ru:]Быстрая ты.[fix]
[zh:]那干嘛
[ar:]ما الذي كان يفترض أن افعله؟[fix]
[zh:]干坐着呀
[en:]What was I supposed to do?[fix] Just site there?[fix]
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que tu voulais que je fasse ? Que je reste assise ?[fix]
[ar:]اجلس هناك وحسب؟[fix]
[ko:]너는 내가 어떻게 할것 같았는데?[fix]
[ru:]А что я должна была делать?[fix] Сидеть и молчать?[fix]
[zh:]可是你约我来的
[en:]You ask me here,[fix]
[fre:]Tu m'as dit de venir,
[ru:]Ты меня туда позвал[fix]
[zh:]我来 你又不理我
[en:]and then you ignore me.[fix]
[fre:]et tu m'ignores.
[ar:]أنت طلبتني أن اذهب إلى هناك ثم تجاهلتني[fix]
[ko:]거기 그냥 앉아있는거?[fix]
[ru:]и не обращал на меня никакого внимания.[fix]
[zh:]跟大蚂蚁当什么英雄 玩什么瓦西里
[en:]You just play heroes of "Lenin in October" with Big Ant.[fix]
[fre:]Tu jouais aux héros de "Lénine en Octobre" avec Big Ant.[fix]
[ar:]وتلعب أدوار أبطال (فاسيلي)، من (لينين في اكتوبر)[fix]
[ko:]오라고 한 사람은 너였어.[fix] 그런데 넌 날 무시했어.[fix] 넌 왕개미와 "10월의 레닌" 이나 흉내내며 놀았잖아.[fix]
[ru:]только играл в героев "Ленина в Октябре" с Муравьем.[fix]
[zh:][列宁在十月]
[zh:]那是[列宁在一九一八]
[en:]That's "Lenin in 1918".[fix]
[fre:]C'était "Lénine en 1918".
[ar:](بل (لينين بعام 1918[fix]
[ru:]Это был "Ленин в 1918 году".[fix]
[zh:]哦 行 [列宁在一九一八]
[en:]Whatever, "Lenin in 1918".[fix]
[fre:]Qu'importe, "Lénine en 1918".
[ar:](حسنا، (لينين بعام 1918[fix]
[ko:]"1918년의 레닌"이야.[fix] "1918년의 레닌"이든 뭐든,[fix]
[ru:]Пусть "Ленин в 1918 году".[fix]
[zh:]可你也不能把我晒一边啊
[en:]But that's no excuse for ignoring me.[fix]
[fre:]Ce n'est pas une excuse pour m'ignorer.[fix]
[ar:]هذا أيضا ليس عذرا لعدم اهتمامك بي[fix]
[ko:]넌 날 무시한거에 대해선 사과 안했어.[fix]
[ru:]Это повод игнорировать меня?[fix]
[zh:]爸
[en:]Oh, Dad?[fix]
[fre:]Oh, papa ?
[ar:]أبي؟[fix] ...هذه[fix]
[ko:]어, 아빠?...[fix]
[ru:]Ой, папа?[fix]
[zh:]这 这是我爸
[en:]Uh, this is my father.[fix]
[fre:]Euh, voici mon père.
[ar:]هذا أبي[fix]
[ru:]Познакомься, это мой отец.[fix]
[zh:]这是
[en:]This... this is...[fix]
[fre:]C'est... c'est...
[ar:]...هذه[fix]
[ru:]А это... Это...[fix]
[zh:]你好 叔叔
[fre:]Bonjour, mon Oncle.
[ar:]مرحبا يا عم
[zh:]我们老师
[en:]Hello, Uncle.[fix] Our teacher.[fix]
[fre:]Notre professeur.
[ar:]معلمتنا[fix]
[ko:]우리 아빠야.[fix]
[ru:]Здравствуйте, дядя.[fix] ... моя учительница.[fix]
[zh:]啊 你好
[en:]Oh, how do you do?[fix]
[fre:]Oh, comment allez-vous ?
[ar:]أوه، أهلا[fix]
[ko:]이쪽은...이쪽은...[fix] 안녕하세요, 아저씨.[fix] 우리 선생님이세요.[fix] 아, 안녕하십니까?[fix]
[ru:]Добрый день.[fix]
[zh:]那我先回去了
[en:]I'll be off then.[fix]
[fre:]Je vais m'en aller.
[ar:]علي الذهاب إذن[fix]
[ru:]Извините, мне уже пора.[fix]
[zh:]再见 马小军
[en:]Bye, Ma Xiaojun, Uncle.[fix]
[fre:]Au revoir, Ma Xiaojun, mon Oncle.
[ar:](مع السلامة، (ماشياو جون[fix]
[ko:]그럼, 나 간다.[fix]
[ru:]До свидания, Ма Сяоцзюнь. Всего доброго, дядя.[fix]
[zh:]再见 叔叔
[en:]Bye.[fix]
[fre:]Au revoir.
[ar:]مع السلامة يا عم - مع السلامة -[fix]
[ru:]Всего доброго.[fix]
[zh:]小同志 你叫
[en:]Oh, little comrade,[fix]
[fre:]Oh, camarade,
[ar:]...أيتها الرفيقة، اسمك[fix] ذكريني به؟[fix]
[ko:]마샤오준, 아저씨, 안녕히 계세요.[fix] 안녕히 가세요.[fix] 동지,[fix]
[ru:]Прошу прощения,[fix]
[zh:]贵姓啊
[fre:]quel est votre nom déjà ?
[zh:]我叫米兰
[en:]What is your name again?[fix] Mi Lan.[fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan.
[ar:](اسمي (مي لان[fix]
[ko:]성함이 어떻게 되시죠?[fix]
[ru:]сын вас не представил.[fix] Меня зовут Ми Лань.[fix]
[zh:]那您还有事吗
[en:]Is there anything else, sir?[fix]
[fre:]Quelque chose d'autre, monsieur ?
[ar:]أهناك شيء آخر يا سيدي؟ - لا، هذا كل شيء -
[ko:]미란입니다.[fix] 뭐 다른 용건은?[fix]
[ru:]Вы еще что-то хотели узнать?[fix]
[zh:]没事啦
[fre:]Euh, non, ce sera tout.
[ar:]سأذهب إذن
[zh:]没事 那我先走了
[en:]Uh, no, that'll be all.
[fre:]Alors j'y vais. Au revoir.
[ar:]حسنا - مع السلامة -[fix]
[ru:]Нет, это все.
[zh:]好
[en:]Then I'll be going. Bye!
[ru:]Тогда я пойду. До свидания.
[zh:]再见 再见
[en:]Ok, bye.
[fre:]OK, au revoir.[fix]
[ar:]مع السلامة[fix]
[ko:]아뇨, 없습니다. 됐습니다.[fix] 그럼 이만 가보겠습니다.[fix] 예, 안녕히 가세요.[fix]
[ru:]До свидания.
[zh:]你去把那个大衣给我找出来
[en:]Get my overcoat.[fix]
[fre:]Donne-moi mon pardessus.
[ar:]أحضر لي معطفي[fix] ماذا تريد به في هذا اليوم الحار؟[fix]
[ru:]Принеси мне шинель.[fix]
[zh:]这么热的天 你要大衣干嘛
[en:]Why do you need that on such a hot day?[fix]
[fre:]Pour quoi faire, il fait si chaud ?
[ru:]Зачем тебе шинель в такую жару?[fix]
[zh:]去把大衣找出来 那好
[en:]I said get my overcoat.[fix]
[fre:]J'ai dit, donne-moi mon pardessus.[fix]
[ar:]قلت أحضر معطفي - حسنا -[fix]
[ko:]아빠 코트 좀 가져와라.[fix] 이렇게 더운 날, 코트는 뭐하시게요?[fix] 가져오라니까![fix]
[ru:]Я сказал - принеси шинель.[fix]
[zh:]啊 大衣
[en:]Here it is, Dad.[fix]
[fre:]Tiens, papa.
[ar:]ها هو[fix]
[ko:]여기요, 아빠.[fix]
[ru:]Вот она, папа.[fix]
[zh:]坐这儿
[en:]Sit down.[fix]
[fre:]Assieds-toi.[fix]
[ar:]اجلس[fix]
[ko:]앉아라.[fix]
[ru:]Садись.[fix]
[zh:]你这个老师 在哪个单位工作呀
[en:]So where does this teacher of yours really work?[fix]
[fre:]Alors, où est-ce que ton professeur travaille vraiment ?
[ar:]في أي وحدة عمل تعمل معلمتك هذه؟[fix]
[ru:]Ну и где эта твоя учительница работает?[fix]
[zh:]啊 我们老师 啊 我们学校啊
[en:]She works... at our school.[fix]
[fre:]Euh... à l'école.
[ar:]تلك المعلمة تعمل...في مدرستنا[fix]
[ko:]아까 그 선생은 어디서 일하냐?[fix] 우리 학교에...계세요.[fix]
[ru:]Она работает в нашей школе.[fix]
[zh:]新来的吧
[fre:]C'est une nouvelle, non ?
[zh:]对 新来的
[en:]New, is she?[fix] Yes.[fix]
[fre:]Oui.
[ar:]جديدة، صحيح؟ - أجل -[fix]
[ko:]새로왔냐?[fix] 예.[fix]
[ru:]Новенькая?[fix] Да.[fix]
[zh:]住哪儿
[en:]Where's she from?[fix]
[fre:]Elle vient d'où ?
[ar:]من أين هي؟[fix] ...من بمكان ما على الجانب الغربي[fix]
[ru:]И откуда она?[fix]
[zh:]她从西城什么的
[en:]Somewhere in the west city,[fix]
[fre:]Quelque part à l'est de la ville...
[ru:]Откуда-то с запада,[fix]
[zh:]哎 不 是西单
[en:]er, Xidan,[fix]
[fre:]euh... Xidan,
[ar:]...(لا مهلا...من (شيدان (أجل، من (شيدان[fix]
[ko:]어디서 왔는데?[fix] 서쪽에 있는 도시라던데.[fix]
[ru:]с Сиданя, что ли?[fix]
[zh:]西单调来的
[en:]yeah, Xidan.[fix]
[fre:]oui, Xidan.
[ko:]'시단'이라던가..[fix]
[ru:]Да, с Сиданя.[fix]
[zh:]你这老师教你啥功课啊
[en:]What does she teach?[fix]
[fre:]Elle enseigne quoi ?
[ar:]تدرس أي مادة؟[fix]
[ru:]И что же она преподает?[fix]
[zh:]她啊 她什么都教
[en:]Uh, a bit of everything.[fix]
[fre:]Euh, un peu de tout.
[ar:]تدرس قليلا من كل شيء[fix]
[ko:]예, '시단'.[fix] 뭘 가르치냐?[fix]
[ru:]Да так... Все понемножку.[fix]
[zh:]这不刚来做家访了吗
[en:]She's making home visits,[fix]
[fre:]Elle fait les visites à domicile,
[ar:]رأيتَها للتو تقوم بزيارات منزلية، صحيح؟[fix]
[ru:]У нее в плане посещение учеников,[fix]
[zh:]现在可能 又到别的同学家去了
[en:]probably seeing the others now.[fix]
[fre:]elle doit être en train de voir les autres, là.
[ar:]على الأرجح أنها الآن تقابل طلاب آخرين[fix]
[ko:]이것 저것요.[fix] 가정 방문 오셨어요.[fix] 지금쯤 다른 애들 집으로 가시고 계실거에요.[fix]
[ru:]и теперь она пошла к следующему.[fix]
[zh:]啥老师啊
[fre:]Professeur, mon cul !
[ar:]!معلمة؟ كاذب[fix]
[zh:]哪个老师管我叫叔叔
[en:]Teacher my ass![fix] What teacher calls me "uncle"?[fix]
[fre:]Quel genre de professeur m'appellerait "mon Oncle" ?
[ar:]أي معلمة تدعوني بـ"عم" ؟
[ko:]선생은 무슨 선생![fix] 선생이 날 보고 "아저씨"라고 불러?[fix]
[ru:]Какая, в жопу, учительница?![fix] Разве учительница назвала бы меня "дядей"?[fix]
[zh:]你骗到你老子头上来了
[en:]You'd lie to your old man?[fix]
[fre:]Tu as menti à un vieil homme ?
[ar:]تكذب على والدك هكذا؟[fix] !يا لوقاحتك[fix]
[ru:]Ты уже врешь отцу?[fix]
[zh:]你好大的胆
[zh:]把军装给我脱了
[en:]You've get gall.[fix] Take off that uniform.[fix]
[fre:]Quelle effronterie ! Enlève cet uniforme ![fix]
[ar:]!اخلع هذا الزي[fix]
[ko:]애비한테 거짓말을 해?[fix]
[ru:]Не зли меня.[fix] Форму сними![fix]
[zh:]装模作样的
[zh:]我一看就不是那么回事
[en:]Liar. I saw through you right away.[fix]
[fre:]Menteur. Je l'ai vu dès le début.[fix]
[ar:]!تكذب هكذا كشفتُك مباشرة[fix]
[ko:]이 뻔뻔스러운 놈아.[fix] 그 옷 벗어.[fix] 그게 거짓말이라는건 내 한 눈에 알아봤어.[fix]
[ru:]Брехло. Я вас сразу раскусил.[fix]
[zh:]不好好温习功课
[fre:]Tu es mauvais élève, désobéissant,[fix]
[ar:]أنت طالب سيء بالمدرسة[fix] عاصي بالبيت
[zh:]在家里不学好
[en:]You're a bad student, disobedient,[fix]
[ru:]Мало того, что ты двоечник и прогульщик[fix]
[zh:]你交个那女 女朋友来了你
[en:]and now you've got a girlfriend.[fix]
[fre:]et maintenant tu as une petite amie ?
[ar:]والآن تحضر معك للبيت صديقة؟[fix]
[ru:]так ты еще и подружку себе завел?[fix]
[zh:]谁交女朋友了
[en:]Girlfriend?[fix]
[fre:]Petite amie ?
[ar:]أي صديقة؟[fix] جاءت لتغسل وجهها فقط[fix]
[ko:]불량 학생, 불효 자식도 모자라서,[fix] 이젠 여자친구까지 사겨?[fix] 여자친구요?[fix]
[ru:]Какая подружка?[fix]
[zh:]她就来这洗洗脸
[fre:]Elle est venue se laver la figure.
[zh:]什么洗脸
[en:]She just came to wash her face.
[fre:]Se laver la figure ?[fix]
[ar:]تغسل وجهها؟ أي وجه؟[fix]
[ru:]Она просто умыться зашла.
[zh:]洗什么脸呀
[en:]Wash her face?[fix]
[ru:]Умыться?[fix]
[zh:]那个脸蛋都是红的 我还看不出来
[en:]You think I couldn't see her blushing?[fix]
[fre:]Tu crois que je ne l'ai pas vue rougir ?
[ar:]أتظن أني لم أرى احمرارها خجلا؟[fix]
[ko:]She just came to wash her face. 씻으러 가다 들른 것 뿐이에요.[fix] 씻으러 가다?[fix] 그 애가 얼굴 빨개지는거  내가 못 본줄 알아?[fix]
[ru:]Ты думаешь, я не видел, как она покраснела?[fix]
[zh:]你别忘了
[fre:]N'oublie pas que je suis ton père,[fix]
[ar:]لا تنس أني والدك[fix]
[zh:]我是你爸爸
[en:]Don't forget I'm your father.[fix]
[ru:]Не забывай, что я твой отец,[fix]
[zh:]我吃的盐比你吃的饭都多
[en:]I know everything.[fix]
[fre:]je sais tout.
[ar:]مررتُ بحياتي بأمور لم تمرَ بها
[ru:]и знаю тебя как облупленного.[fix]
[zh:]你不是交女朋友是啥
[en:]If she's not your girlfriend, what is she?[fix]
[fre:]Si elle n'est pas ta petite amie, c'est qui ?
[ar:]إن كانت ليست صديقتك فما تكونْ؟[fix]
[ko:]난 니 애비야.[fix] 난 다 알아.[fix] 그 여자애가 네 여자친구가 아니라면,  그럼 누구야?[fix]
[ru:]Если она не подружка, то кто?[fix]
[zh:]你这叫早恋
[en:]Puppy love![fix]
[fre:]Une amourette !
[ar:]!هذا يسمى حب مراهقة
[ru:]Любовь крутите![fix]
[zh:]那是犯错误的
[en:]That's not allowed.[fix]
[fre:]Ce n'est pas autorisé.
[ar:]!وهو غير مقبول[fix]
[ko:]풋사랑이군![fix] 그건 안 돼.[fix]
[ru:]Я запрещаю тебе ее видеть![fix]
[zh:]她是从哪儿来的啊
[en:]Where's she from?[fix]
[fre:]Elle vient d'où ?
[ar:]من أين هي إذن؟
[ru:]Откуда она?[fix]
[zh:]啊 行了 我没时间跟你论
[en:]Forget it. I've no time for this.[fix]
[fre:]Laisse tomber. Je n'ai pas le temps pour ça.
[ar:]أوه، انسى لا وقت لدي لهذا[fix]
[ru:]Ладно, времени нет.[fix]
[zh:]你妈从姥姥家回来告诉她
[fre:]Dis à ta mère qu'on m'envoie en Mongolie Intérieure.[fix]
[ar:]، عندما ترجع أمك من عند جدتك
[ko:]그 여자애는 어디 출신이냐?[fix] 아니, 때려쳐.  이런 얘기 할 시간 없다.[fix]
[zh:]我去内蒙古野营拉练了
[en:]Tell your mother I've been sent to Inner Mongolia.[fix]
[ar:]قل لها أني اُرسلت إلى منغوليا الداخلية للتدريب الميداني
[ko:]엄마한테 아빠가 내몽고로  파견됐다고 전해라.[fix]
[ru:]Скажи матери, что меня отправили во Внутреннюю Монголию.[fix]
[zh:]是紧急任务
[en:]Urgent mission. War games.[fix]
[fre:]Mission urgente. Stratégie militaire.
[ar:]إنها مهمة عاجلة[fix]
[ru:]Срочный вызов, там учения начались.[fix]
[zh:]您什么时候回来
[fre:]Quand est-ce que tu rentres ?
[zh:]一个月
[en:]When'll you be back?[fix] In a month.[fix]
[fre:]Dans un mois.
[ar:]متى ستعود؟ - خلال شهر -[fix]
[ko:]급한 임무야. 전쟁이 났어.[fix]
[ru:]А когда ты вернешься?[fix] Через месяц.[fix]
[zh:]干啥
[en:]Don't get into mischief while I'm away.[fix]
[fre:]Ne fais pas d'embrouille en mon absence.[fix]
[ar:]ما الأمر؟
[ko:]언제 돌아오시는데요?[fix] 한달 뒤.[fix] 내가 없는 동안에 나쁜짓 하지 마라.[fix]
[ru:]И если ты что-нибудь натворишь, пока меня не будет...[fix]
[zh:]你又可以胡闹了
[ar:]تظن أنك ستكون مفلوت مجددا بلا سيطرة صحيح؟[fix]
[zh:]嗯
[ar:]!جرب
[zh:]敢
[zh:]马参谋长
[fre:]Commissaire Ma ! Il est temps de partir ![fix]
[ar:]!(حضرة المفوض السياسي (ما حان وقت الذهاب[fix]
[zh:]哦
[en:]Political Commissar Ma! Time to go!
[ru:]Политический комиссар Ма! Опаздываем!
[zh:]走了
[fre:]J'arrive ![fix]
[ar:]!قادم[fix]
[zh:]来了
[en:]Coming![fix]
[ko:]마 정치위원님! 갈 시간입니다![fix] 가![fix]
[ru:]Иду![fix]
[zh:]这是我这个月的工资
[en:]This is this month's salary.[fix]
[fre:]Voilà le salaire du mois.
[ar:]هذا راتب الشهر هذا[fix]
[ru:]Вот моя месячная зарплата.[fix]
[zh:]给你妈
[en:]Give it to your mother.[fix]
[fre:]Donne-le à ta mère.
[ar:]أعطه أمك[fix]
[ko:]이거 이번달 월급이야.[fix]
[ru:]Отдашь матери.[fix]
[zh:]别惹你妈生气
[fre:]Ne la contrarie pas,
[ar:]لا تضايقها[fix]
[zh:]我再说一遍
[en:]Don't upset her.[fix] I'll say that once more.[fix]
[fre:]je te le répète.
[ar:]أكرر ذلك
[ko:]엄마 드려라.[fix] 엄마 힘들게 하지 말고.[fix] 한 번 더 말하니 명심해.[fix]
[ru:]Не расстраивай ее.[fix] Побереги мать.[fix]
[zh:]这两块钱是给你的
[en:]Take two Yuan for yourself,[fix]
[fre:]Garde 2 Yuan pour toi,
[ar:]هذه اليوانين لك
[ru:]На вот тебе два юаня,[fix]
[zh:]不许乱花啊
[en:]spend it carefully.[fix]
[fre:]économise-les.
[ar:]لا تهدرها[fix]
[ko:]2위안이다. 가져라.[fix] 아껴서 써.[fix]
[ru:]только не трать на ерунду.[fix]
[zh:]别随便带女孩子到咱们家
[en:]Don't go bringing girls back here.[fix]
[fre:]Ne ramène plus de filles à la maison !
[ar:]لا تصير تحضر الفتيات إلى هنا
[ko:]이곳으로 여자애 들이지 마라.[fix]
[ru:]Девчонок сюда не води.[fix]
[zh:]不要骗我 以后
[en:]Never lie to me again.[fix]
[fre:]Et ne me mens plus jamais !
[ar:]ولا تكذب علي مرة أخرى
[ko:]아빠한테 다시는 거짓말 하지 말고.[fix]
[ru:]И никогда не ври мне больше.[fix]
[zh:]行 走了
[en:]All right, I'm off.[fix]
[fre:]Bon, j'y vais.
[ar:]حسنا، سأذهب[fix]
[ko:]좋아, 아빠 간다.[fix]
[ru:]Ладно, все, я пошел.[fix]
[zh:]羊搞
[fre:]Yang Gao ![fix]
[ar:]!(يانغ غاو)[fix]
[ko:]양가오! 양가오! 양가오![fix]
[zh:]羊搞
[en:]Yang Gao! Yang Gao! Yang Gao![fix]
[fre:]Yang Gao !
[ar:]!(يانغ غاو)
[ru:]Янг Гао! Янг Гао! Янг Гао![fix]
[zh:]羊搞
[fre:]Yang Gao !
[ar:]!(يانغ غاو)[fix]
[zh:]同志们 大家静一静
[en:]Comrades, comrades, quiet down![fix]
[fre:]Camarades, camarades, calmez-vous !
[ar:]اهدأوا أيها الرفاق[fix]
[ru:]Товарищи, товарищи, успокойтесь![fix]
[zh:]喔
[en:]There's been a technical problem,[fix]
[fre:]Il y a eu un problème technique,
[ar:]يوجد مشكلة فنية
[ko:]동지들, 동지들, 조용히 하세요![fix] 기술적 문제가 좀 생겨서,[fix]
[ru:]Это плановая перебивка.[fix]
[zh:]喔
[ar:]يتم الآن حلها
[zh:]下面上演第二部 [列宁在一九一八]
[en:]so we'll move to the second film "Lenin in 1918".[fix]
[fre:]donc nous allons passer le second film "Lénine en 1918".
[ar:]لذا سننتقل للفيلم الثاني (لينين بعام 1918)[fix]
[ko:]두 번째 필름인 "1918년의 레닌"을  틀도록 하겠습니다.[fix]
[ru:]Сейчас мы покажем "Ленин в 1918 году".[fix]
[zh:]刘忆苦
[fre:]Liu Yiku ![fix]
[ar:](ليو إيكو)[fix]
[zh:]刘思甜
[en:]Liu Yi Ku! Liu Sitian![fix]
[fre:]Liu Sitian !
[ar:](ليو سيان)[fix]
[ko:]류이쿠! 류시챤![fix]
[ru:]Лю Еку! Лю Сытиань![fix]
[zh:]瓦西里
[fre:]Vasily ! Vasily ![fix]
[ar:]!(فاسيلي) "[fix]
[zh:]瓦西里
[en:]Vasily! Vasily![fix]
[zh:]快去救列宁
[en:]Quick, go save Lenin![fix]
[fre:]Vite, sauve Lénine !
[ar:]"(فاسيلي)...بسرعة، اذهب لإنقاذ (لينين)[fix]
[ko:]바실리! 바실리![fix] 서둘러, 가서 레닌을 구해![fix]
[ru:]Вася, быстрее, спаси Ленина.[fix]
[zh:]羊搞
[ar:]!(يانغ غاو)[fix]
[en:]Yang Gao! Yang Gao![fix]
[fre:]Yang Gao ! Yang Gao ![fix]
[ar:]!(يانغ غاو)[fix]
[ko:]양가오! 양가오![fix]
[ru:]Янг Гао! Янг Гао![fix]
[zh:]嘿 当心哪 有毒的
[en:]Careful, it's poison![fix]
[fre:]Attention, c'est du poison !
[ar:]!انتبهي، إنه مسمم[fix]
[ko:]조심해, 그건 독약이야![fix]
[ru:]Осторожно, это яд![fix]
[zh:]当心哪 有毒的
[en:]Careful, it's poison![fix]
[ar:]"!يحيا (لينين)! هجوم"[fix]
[ko:]조심해, 그건 독약이야![fix]
[zh:]我操 你丫上哪儿去了
[en:]Shit, where were you bastards?[fix]
[fre:]Putain, vous étiez où ?
[ar:]اللعنة، أين كنتم؟[fix] أين كنت أنت؟
[ko:]제기랄, 다들 어디있는거야?[fix]
[ru:]Уродцы, вы где шляетесь?[fix]
[zh:]你上哪儿去了
[fre:]T'étais passé où ?[fix]
[zh:]我出来找你
[en:]Where the hell did you go?[fix]
[ar:]كنت ابحث عنك بكل مكان - وأنا كذلك  - هيا -[fix]
[ru:]Куда вы, блин, потерялись?[fix]
[zh:]我也找你半天了
[fre:]On te cherchait partout.
[zh:]快走吧
[en:]Been looking all over for you.[fix] Never mind, follow me.[fix]
[fre:]Bref, suis-moi.[fix]
[ko:]도대체 넌 어딨었어?[fix] 너네들 찾고 있었지.[fix] 그만 됐어, 따라와.[fix]
[ru:]Я вас как дурак бегаю ищу.[fix] Неважно, пошли со мной.[fix]
[zh:]你怎么现在才来
[ar:]أين كنت؟[fix]
[zh:]找你们去了
[zh:]他们呢
[ar:]كنت ابحث عنك[fix]
[zh:]同志们
[ar:]أيها الرفاق[fix]
[zh:]现在礼堂里混进了几个小孩
[en:]Comrades! Some children have snuck into the theatre...[fix]
[fre:]Camarades ! Des enfants se sont infiltrés dans le cinéma,[fix]
[ar:]تسلل بعض الصغار للمسرح[fix]
[ko:]동지들! 몇몇 애들이 몰래 극장으로 들어왔습니다...[fix]
[ru:]Товарищи! В зал пробрались дети,[fix]
[zh:]对不起了 电影要暂时停放
[en:]so we've had to turn off the projector.[fix]
[fre:]nous avons donc dû éteindre le projecteur.
[ar:]نعتذر عن الايقاف المؤقت للفيلم[fix]
[ko:]그래서 영사기를 꺼야만 했습니다.[fix]
[ru:]поэтому мы вынуждены прекратить показ.[fix]
[zh:]小孩在哪里
[en:]Where are the kids?[fix]
[fre:]Où sont ces enfants ?
[ar:]أين الصغار؟[fix]
[ru:]Где дети?[fix]
[zh:]遍地都是啊
[en:]Everywhere.[fix]
[fre:]Partout.
[ar:]إنهم بكل مكان[fix]
[ko:]애들은 어디 있나?[fix] 여기저기 있습니다.[fix]
[ru:]Да везде.[fix]
[zh:]我怎么没看见
[en:]I didn't see them.[fix]
[fre:]Je ne les ai pas vus.
[ar:]ولماذا لا أرى أي منهم؟[fix] !ليقف كل الصغار[fix]
[ru:]А я не вижу.[fix]
[zh:]你们都起来
[fre:]Levez-vous,
[zh:]起来 起来 那边的
[en:]Stand up,[fix] stand up all of you.[fix]
[fre:]levez-vous tous !
[ar:]قفوا، هناك[fix]
[ko:]난 안보이는데...[fix]
[ru:]Встаньте[fix] Встаньте все.[fix]
[zh:]起来
[ar:]!قفوا[fix]
[ko:]일어서.[fix] 모두 일어서.[fix]
[zh:]怎么搞的
[en:]How's this happen?[fix]
[fre:]Comment ça a pu arriver ?
[ar:]كيف حدث هذا؟[fix]
[ko:]어떻게 된 일이야?[fix]
[ru:]Как это случилось?[fix]
[zh:]你是怎么负责看的门
[en:]Who was watching the door?[fix]
[fre:]Qui surveillait la porte ?
[ar:]من المسؤول عن مراقبة الباب؟[fix]
[ru:]Кто был на дверях?[fix]
[zh:]这些孩子可没有一个是从门走进来的
[en:]Not one came through the door![fix]
[fre:]Ils ne sont pas passés par la porte !
[ar:]ولا واحد منهم دخل من الباب[fix]
[ko:]출입문은 누가 지켰어?[fix] 출입문으로는 아무도 들어오지 않았습니다![fix]
[ru:]А они не через дверь пробрались.[fix]
[zh:]这是部受批判的电影
[en:]This film is under criticism,[fix]
[fre:]Ce film est sous la critique,
[ar:]هذا الفيلم تحت الانتقادات[fix]
[ko:]이 영화는 좋지 않다.[fix]
[ru:]Этот фильм критикуется[fix]
[zh:]毒性非常之大
[en:]it is extremely poisonous...[fix]
[fre:]il est extrêmement controversé...
[ar:]وهو مؤذٍ للغاية[fix]
[ru:]он чрезвычайно отвратительный[fix]
[zh:]小孩看了会犯错误的
[fre:]Les enfants pourraient s'égarer et commettre des méfaits importants.[fix]
[ar:]لو شاهده الصغار قد يرتكبوا جرائم
[ko:]이 영화는 아주 유독해서...[fix]
[zh:]会犯很大的错误
[en:]children could be let astray by it to commit major crimes.[fix]
[ar:]قد يرتكبوا جرائم كبيرة
[ko:]어린아이들을 타락시켜 비행을 저지르게 할 수도 있다.[fix]
[ru:]детей он может сбить с верной дороги и они докатятся до преступлений.[fix]
[zh:]不看了
[en:]That's it for the film.[fix]
[fre:]C'est fini pour le film.
[ar:]لا فيلم الآن[fix]
[ko:]오늘 영화는 이걸로 끝낸다.[fix]
[ru:]Очень правильно сказали.[fix]
[zh:]别 别 别
[zh:]这样吧
[ar:]، والآن[fix]
[zh:]谁的孩子 大人出来把他们都领走
[en:]Just let their parents take them home.[fix]
[fre:]Que leurs parents les ramènent à la maison.[fix]
[ar:]أياً كانوا آبائهم فليأتوا ويأخذونهم من هنا حالاً[fix]
[ko:]부모한테 쟤네들 모두  집으로 데려가라고 해.[fix]
[ru:]А теперь запишите фамилии и сообщите родителям.[fix]
[zh:]月色多么好
[ar:]ضوء القمر الجميل أبهج قلبي[fix]
[zh:]令我心神往
[en:]The moonlight stirs my heart on this enchanted evening.[fix]
[ko:]이 황홀한 밤에  달빛은 내 마음을 흔드네[fix]
[zh:]多少迷人的晚上
[fre:]Le clair de lune agite mon cœur en cette soirée enchanteresse.[fix]
[ar:]...أمسيات ساحرة عديدة[fix]
[zh:]我的心上人 坐在我身旁
[en:]With my sweetheart by my side.[fix]
[fre:]Avec mon amoureuse à mes côtés,[fix]
[ar:]بجانبي حبيبتي، أحدق بها بصمت بلا صوت[fix]
[ko:]내 곁에 사랑하는 사람 있으니[fix]
[zh:]默默看着我 不声响
[en:]Only the wind softly singing...[fix]
[fre:]seul le vent chante.[fix]
[ko:]바람만이 부드럽게 노래하고 있네...[fix]
[zh:]夜色多么好
[ar:]ليل جميل أبهج قلبي[fix]
[zh:]令我心神往
[en:]The moonlight stirs my heart on this enchanted evening.[fix]
[fre:]Le clair de lune agite mon cœur en cette soirée enchanteresse.[fix]
[ko:]이 황홀한 밤에  달빛은 내 마음을 흔드네[fix]
[zh:]多少迷人的晚上
[ar:]...أمسيات ساحرة عديدة[fix]
[zh:]长夜快过去 天色蒙蒙亮
[en:]The long night is quickly receding under the misty dawn[fix]
[fre:]La longue nuit cède rapidement place à l'aube brumeuse.[fix]
[ar:]يتراجع الليل الطويل بسرعة بضوء حلم[fix]
[ko:]긴 밤은 안개낀 새벽속으로  황급히 사라진다네[fix]
[zh:]衷心祝福你 好姑娘
[en:]I wish you well, girl, with all my heart[fix]
[fre:]Je te souhaite du bonheur, mon Amour, de tout mon cœur,[fix]
[ar:]بكل قلبي يا حلوة أتمنى لك الخير[fix]
[ko:]사랑하는 사람아,  나의 진심 모아, 당신 건강하기를 바라네.[fix]
[zh:]但愿从今后
[fre:]et espère qu'aucun de nous n'oubliera jamais[fix]
[ar:]لكن لازلتُ أرجو أن من هذا اليوم وصاعدا[fix]
[ko:]우리들을 영원히 잊지 말기를 바라네.[fix]
[zh:]你我永不忘
[en:]and hope that neither of us will ever forget[fix]
[ar:]ألا انسى ولا وتنسي هذا المساء في ضواحي موسكو[fix]
[zh:]莫斯科郊外的晚上
[en:]this evening on the outskirts of Moscow.[fix]
[fre:]cette soirée dans les faubourgs de Moscou.[fix]
[ko:]모스크바에서 먼 이곳의 밤에.[fix]
[zh:]你睡着了
[en:]You sleeping?[fix]
[fre:]Tu dors ?
[ar:]أنت نائمة؟[fix]
[ru:]Ты спишь?[fix]
[zh:]没有啊
[en:]No.[fix]
[fre:]Non.
[ar:]كلا[fix]
[ko:]자?[fix]
[ru:]Нет.[fix]
[zh:]那怎么一直没说话啊
[fre:]Pourquoi tu ne dis rien ?
[ar:]لماذا لم تتكلمي؟[fix]
[zh:]你也没说话呀
[en:]Why haven't you said anything?[fix] You haven't either.[fix]
[fre:]Toi non plus.
[ar:]أنت لم تتكلم
[ko:]아니.[fix] 근데 왜 아무 말도 안 해?[fix] 너도 안하잖아.[fix]
[ru:]А почему тогда молчишь?[fix] Ты тоже не разговариваешь.[fix]
[zh:]要不 你就睡会儿得了
[ar:]لمَ لا تحاولي النوم قليلا؟[fix]
[zh:]那还不掉下来呀
[en:]Why don't you try to sleep?[fix] I'd fall off.[fix]
[fre:]- Essaye donc de dormir ? - Je tomberais ?[fix]
[ar:]سأسقط[fix] تمسكي بوسطي[fix]
[ko:]잘래?[fix]
[ru:]А что не спишь?[fix] Свалиться боюсь.[fix]
[zh:]你扶住我腰嘛
[fre:]- Accroche-toi à ma taille. - Ça ne te dérange pas ?[fix]
[zh:]合适吗
[en:]Hold on to my waist.
[ru:]Возьми меня за пояс.
[zh:]合适
[en:]You don't mind?[fix] No.[fix]
[fre:]Non.
[ar:]لا مانع؟ - أجل -[fix]
[ko:]그러다 떨어져.[fix] 내 허리 꽉 잡아.[fix] 괜찮겠어?[fix] 응.[fix]
[ru:]А ты не укусишь?[fix] Нет.[fix]
[zh:]那是我一生中最美好的一天
[en:]That was the most perfect day of my life.[fix]
[fre:]Ce fut la plus belle journée de ma vie.
[ar:]ذلك اليوم كان الأروع في حياتي[fix]
[ko:]그 때가 내 인생에 있어서 가장 완벽한 나날이었다.[fix]
[ru:]Это был лучший день в моей жизни.[fix]
[zh:]晨风的抚摸使我一阵阵起了鸡皮疙瘩
[en:]The morning breeze raised goosebumps on my skin...[fix]
[fre:]La brise matinale me donnait la chair de poule,[fix]
[ar:]مداعبات نسيم الصباح سببت قشعريرة بجلدي[fix]
[ko:]그날 아침의 바람은  내 살갗에 닭살이 돋게 했고...[fix]
[ru:]Прохладный утренний ветерок пробирал до мурашек,[fix]
[zh:]周身发麻
[ar:]وشعرت بوخز بكل جسدي[fix]
[zh:]我还记得有股烧荒草的味道特别好闻
[en:]and I remember the delicious smell of burning-off.[fix]
[fre:]et je me rappelle de la bonne odeur d'herbe brûlée.
[ar:]ما زلت أتذكر الرائحة العطرية المميزة لاحتراق العشب التالف[fix]
[ko:]불타는 향긋한 냄새가  났던 것으로 기억한다.[fix]
[ru:]и я помню запах горящего сена.[fix]
[zh:]可是大夏天哪来的荒草呢
[en:]But who'd be burning dead grass in summer?[fix]
[fre:]Mais qui pouvait bien faire brûler de l'herbe en été ?
[ar:]لكن من الذي يحرق العشب في عز الصيف؟[fix]
[ko:]그런데, 누가 여름날  불타는 풀 냄새를 맡을 수 있단 말인가?[fix]
[ru:]Хотя кто бы стал жечь сухую траву посреди лета?[fix]
[zh:]但无论怎样
[fre:]Enfin, la vérité c'est que
[zh:]记忆中那年夏天发生的事
[en:]Whatever the truth is...[fix]
[ar:]،أياً كانت الحقيقة، بذاكرتي ...كل شيء حدث في ذلك الصيف[fix]
[ru:]Но правда это или нет,[fix]
[zh:]总是伴随着那么一股烧荒草的味
[en:]everything that happened that summer had the scent of burning grass.[fix]
[fre:]tous mes souvenirs de cet été ont l'odeur de l'herbe brûlée.[fix]
[ar:].صاحبه رائحة احتراق العشب[fix]
[ko:]진실이야 어찌됐건...[fix] 그 여름날 일어났던 모든 일들은 불타는 풀 냄새를 갖고 있다.[fix]
[ru:]у всего, что случилось тем летом, был аромат горящей травы.[fix]
[zh:]就这儿了 小军
[en:]Here it is.[fix]
[fre:]C'est là.
[ar:](هذا هو المكان، (شياوجون[fix]
[ru:]Это здесь.[fix]
[zh:]瞧 从这儿开始
[ar:]انظر، ابتداء من هنا كل هذه مزرعتنا[fix]
[zh:]那边都是我们农场
[en:]That's our farm.[fix]
[fre:]Voici notre ferme.
[ar:]حقا؟[fix]
[ko:]다 왔어.[fix] 여기가 우리 농장이야.[fix]
[ru:]Здесь наша ферма.[fix]
[zh:]谢谢你 送我这么远的路
[en:]Thanks for carrying me all that way![fix]
[fre:]Merci de m'avoir emmenée.
[ar:]شكرا لاصطحابي كل هذه المسافة
[ko:]태워다줘서 고마워.[fix]
[ru:]Спасибо, что отвез.[fix]
[zh:]没事 我再送你会吧
[en:]I can take you further if you like.[fix]
[fre:]Je peux t'amener plus loin si tu veux.
[ar:]هذا عادي. يمكنني اصطحبك لأبعد إن أردتِ[fix]
[ru:]Я могу и дальше отвезти, если что.[fix]
[zh:]不用了 从这儿穿过去就到了
[en:]No need, I can cut through this orchard.[fix]
[fre:]C'est bon, je peux couper par ce verger.
[ar:]لا داعي، يمكنني العبور من هنا
[ko:]네가 원한다면, 더 멀리라도 데려다줄 수 있어.[fix] 필요 없어. 이 과수원 질러 가면 돼.[fix]
[ru:]Да не надо, я пройду через сад.[fix]
[zh:]赶快回家睡觉吧
[en:]Go home and get some sleep. Bye![fix]
[fre:]Rentre chez toi et va te reposer.
[ar:]اذهب للبيت ونم
[ru:]Езжай домой и поспи немного. Пока![fix]
[zh:]再见 再见
[en:]Bye![fix]
[fre:]- Bye ! - Bye !
[ar:]مع السلامة - مع السلامة -
[ko:]집에 가서 좀 자. 안녕![fix] 안녕![fix]
[ru:]Пока![fix]
[zh:]昨天我在梦里 又见到了米兰
[en:]I saw Mi Lan again in my dreams last night.[fix]
[fre:]J'ai revu Mi Lan dans mes rêves, la nuit dernière.
[ar:]رأيتُ (مي لان) بأحلامي مرة أخرى بالأمس[fix]
[ko:]어젯밤 꿈속에서 미란을 다시 봤다.[fix]
[ru:]Ночью мне снова снилась Ми Лань.[fix]
[zh:]爸
[en:]Dad![fix]
[fre:]Papa !
[ar:]أبي[fix]
[ko:]아빠![fix]
[ru:]Папа![fix]
[zh:]姥爷死了
[en:]Mom's father died.[fix]
[fre:]Le père de maman est mort.
[ar:]جدك مات[fix]
[ko:]네 외할아버지가 돌아가셨어.[fix]
[ru:]Мой отец умер.[fix]
[zh:]东海扬波红日升
[ar:]، فوق موجات بحر الصين الشرقي المرتفعة[fix]
[zh:]按当时的说法
[ar:]، بعبارات تلك الأيام[fix]
[zh:]姥爷是畏罪自杀
[en:]They said Grandpa 'committed suicide to escape punishment'.[fix]
[fre:]Ils ont dit que grand-père "s'était suicidé pour éviter la punition".[fix]
[ar:]"ارتكب جدي"الانتحار هربا من العقاب[fix] ، تمت إدانته بأربع مسميات[fix]
[ru:]Они сказали, что дедушка "покончил с собой, чтобы избежать наказания".[fix]
[zh:]他有四顶帽子
[zh:]大地主 大资本家 国民党员 历史反革命
[en:]A 'landlord', 'capitalist', KMT member and 'counterrevolutionary'...[fix]
[fre:]Un "traître", "capitaliste", "membre du KMT et contre révolutionnaire".[fix]
[ar:](مالك كبير) و (رأسمالي كبير) (و(عضو حزب الكومينتانغ) و (معاد للثورة[fix]
[ko:]사람들은 할아버지가 형벌을 피하기 위해 자살했다고 말했다.[fix] '지주', '자본가', '국민당 당원'  그리고 '반혁명분자'...[fix]
[ru:]"Домовладелец", "капиталист", член Гоминдана и "контрреволюционер"[fix]
[zh:]文革以来 不断有人抄他的家
[fre:]Sa maison fut fouillée pour de l'or et des documents qu'il n'avait même pas.[fix]
[ar:]بعد بدء الثورة الثقافية تعرض منزله للتفتيش باستمرار بحثاً عن الذهب وأدلة اتهام[fix]
[zh:]要他交出黄金和委任状
[en:]his home was searched for gold and documents he didn't have.[fix]
[ru:]У него был обыск - искали золото и документы, которых у него не было.[fix]
[zh:]在饱受皮肉之苦和精神折磨后
[en:]Tortured physically and mentally,[fix]
[fre:]Torturé physiquement et mentalement,
[ar:]بعد أن تحمل هذا العذاب الجسدي والنفسي مات غضباً[fix]
[ko:]할아버지 집에서는 할아버지가 갖고 있지도 않던 금과 서류들이 발견되었다.[fix] 육체적, 정신적으로 고통받다,[fix]
[ru:]Измученный морально и физически,[fix]
[zh:]他愤然死去
[en:]he died in anger.[fix]
[fre:]il est mort en colère.
[ru:]он умер в гневе.[fix]
[zh:]后来才知道
[en:]Later I learned my father's superiors[fix]
[fre:]Plus tard, j'ai appris que les supérieurs de mon père
[ar:]لم أعرف إلا لاحقا أن زواج والداي لم توافق عليه السلطات[fix]
[ko:]할아버지는 분노에 쌓여 돌아가셨다.[fix]
[ru:]Позже я узнал, что папино начальство[fix]
[zh:]父母的婚姻上级是不赞成的
[en:]hadn't approved of my mother[fix]
[fre:]n'approuvaient pas ma mère,
[ru:]очень не одобряло его брак,[fix]
[zh:]因为他们不属于同一阶级
[en:]because of grandpa,[fix]
[fre:]à cause de grand-père,
[ar:]لأنهما كانا ينتميان لطبقتين مختلفتين[fix]
[ko:]아버지의 상관들은 외할아버지 때문에,[fix]
[ru:]из-за дедушки,[fix]
[zh:]但他们一意孤行 不听劝告
[fre:]et ça obstruait la carrière de mon père.[fix]
[ar:]لكنهما لم يباليا بالتحذيرات وأتما الزواج بكل حال[fix]
[ko:]엄마를 인정하지 않았고,[fix] 그로 인해 아버지는[fix]
[zh:]结果 爸爸为此断送了前途
[en:]and it hurt dad's career prospects.[fix]
[ar:]ونتيجة لذلك، ضاعت فرص أبي المهنية[fix]
[ko:]승진을 하지 못했다는 것을 알게 되었다.[fix]
[ru:]и это сильно повредило его карьере.[fix]
[zh:]妈妈也丢失了原来的教师工作
[en:]Ma also lost her teaching job[fix]
[fre:]Maman perdit aussi son travail d'enseignante
[ar:]وفقدت أمي وظيفتها في التدريس[fix]
[ko:]어머니 또한 그로 인해 교직(敎職)을 잃었고,[fix]
[ru:]Мама тоже потеряла работу учительницы,[fix]
[zh:]成了随军家属
[en:]and became an army dependent.[fix]
[fre:]et devint une dépendante de l'armée.
[ru:]и стала "иждивенкой".[fix]
[zh:]而且脾气变得越来越坏
[en:]And her temper got worse and worse.[fix]
[fre:]Son caractère devint de pire en pire.
[ar:]أصبحت ربة منزل تابعة للجيش وصار مزاجها من سيء لأسوء[fix]
[ko:]아버지의 월급에 의존하는 삶을 살게 되었다.[fix] 어머니의 성격은 갈수록 악화되었다.[fix]
[ru:]У нее начал портиться характер.[fix]
[zh:]上学以前 我生活在姥姥家
[en:]Before school, I lived with Grandpa and Grandma,[fix]
[fre:]Avant la reprise des cours, j'habitais avec grand-père et grand-mère.
[ar:]قبل دخولي للمدرسة كنت أعيش مع جدي وجدتي[fix]
[ru:]Перед школой я жил у дедушки с бабушкой.[fix]
[zh:]我一直不明白
[en:]I couldn't understand[fix]
[fre:]Je n'arrivais pas à comprendre
[ru:]Я не мог понять,[fix]
[zh:]姥爷竟是一个无产阶级的专政对象
[en:]how he could have been a class enemy.[fix]
[fre:]le fait qu'il soit un ennemi.
[ar:]لم أفهم كيف كان ممكنا أنه عدواً للبروليتاريا[fix]
[ko:]학교에 들어가기전에, 나는 외조부모와 함께 살았다.[fix] 나는 그 분들이 계급의 적이었다는 것을[fix] 이해할 수가 없다.[fix]
[ru:]как он быть "классовым врагом".[fix]
[zh:]姥爷死后
[zh:]妈妈变得沉默了
[en:]After Grandpa's death,[fix] Ma became sullen.[fix]
[fre:]Après la mort de grand-père, maman devint maussade.[fix]
[ar:]بعد وفاة جدي أصبحت أمي منعزلة على نفسها[fix]
[ko:]외할아버지가 돌아가신 후,[fix]
[ru:]После смерти дедушки[fix] мама стала совсем угрюмой.[fix]
[zh:]我却有点破罐破摔
[en:]I went back to my wicked old ways.[fix]
[fre:]Je suis alors retombé dans mes mauvaises habitudes.
[ar:]ولقد تركتُ المحاولة بأن أكون مهذباً[fix]
[ko:]어머니는 말이 없어졌다.[fix] 그리고 나는 예전의  그 못된 생활로 다시 돌아갔다.[fix]
[ru:]И я вернулся к своим "хулиганским привычкам".[fix]
[zh:]从唐山回来第一件事
[en:]The first thing I did after my return[fix]
[fre:]La première chose que j'ai faite à mon retour
[ru:]Первое, что я сделал после возвращения -[fix]
[zh:]就是去找米兰
[en:]was to look for Mi Lan.[fix]
[fre:]fut d'aller voir Mi Lan.
[ar:](بعد عودتي من (تانغشان (أول شيء فعلته كان البحث عن (مي لان[fix]
[ko:]내 생활로 다시 돌아온 후,  나는 제일 먼저[fix]
[ru:]отправился повидать Ми Лань.[fix]
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan! Mi Lan![fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:](مي لان)[fix]
[ko:]미란을 보러 갔다.[fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань! Ми Лань![fix]
[zh:]哪一个哟
[en:]Who's there?[fix]
[fre:]Qui est là ?
[ar:]من هناك؟[fix]
[ko:]미란! 미란![fix] 누구세요?[fix]
[ru:]Кто там?[fix]
[zh:]哪一个呀
[en:]Who's there?[fix]
[fre:]Qui est là ?
[ar:]من هناك؟[fix]
[ko:]누구세요?[fix]
[ru:]Кто там?[fix]
[zh:]哎 你莫跑
[en:]Don't run![fix]
[fre:]Ne t'enfuis pas !
[ar:]لا تهرب
[ko:]얘야, 잠깐만![fix]
[ru:]Не убегайте![fix]
[zh:]别哭啊
[en:]Don't cry![fix]
[fre:]Ne pleure plus.
[ar:]لا تبكي[fix]
[ko:]울지 마![fix]
[ru:]Не плачь.[fix]
[zh:]古伦木
[en:]Gooloomoo[fix]
[fre:]Gooloomoo.
[ar:]...غلومو[fix]
[ko:]구루무.[fix]
[ru:]Гулуму![fix]
[zh:]欧巴
[en:]Oo-ba![fix]
[fre:]Oo-ba !
[ar:]...اوبا[fix]
[ko:]오-바![fix]
[ru:]Оо-ба![fix]
[zh:]马小军
[ar:](ماشياو جون)[fix]
[zh:]哟 是马猴啊
[en:]Oh, Monkey![fix]
[fre:]Oh, Monkey !
[ar:]!إنه القرد[fix] أين كنت؟[fix]
[ko:]아, 원숭아![fix]
[ru:]О, Обезьяна![fix]
[zh:]你从哪儿钻出来的
[zh:]这些日子没见着 我们特想你
[en:]Where'd you come from?[fix] Haven't seen you for days! We missed you.[fix]
[fre:]Tu étais passé où ? On ne t'a pas vu depuis longtemps ![fix]
[ar:].لم نرك منذ أيام افتقدناك
[ru:]Когда ты вернулся?[fix] Мы тебя не видели много дней. Мы скучали по тебе.[fix]
[zh:]啊 是啊 我也特想你们
[en:]I missed you guys too.[fix]
[fre:]- Tu nous as manqué. - Vous m'avez manqué aussi.[fix]
[ar:]نعم، افتقدتكم أنا أيضا[fix]
[ko:]어디 갔다 온거야?[fix] 며칠 동안 안 보여서, 보고 싶었어.[fix] 나도 너희들이 보고 싶었어.[fix]
[ru:]Я тоже скучал по вам всем.[fix]
[zh:]我姥姥家出了点事 是吗
[en:]Something happened at my grandparents,[fix]
[fre:]Quelque chose est arrivé chez mes grands-parents,
[ar:]حدث شيء عند أجدادي - حقا؟ -[fix]
[ru:]Да там у дедушки с бабушкой проблемы были[fix]
[zh:]这两天跟他们回了趟唐山
[en:]and I went back to Tangshan with my folks.[fix]
[fre:]et j'ai dû aller à Tangshan avec ma famille.
[ar:]وذهبتُ إلى (تانغشان) مع أهلي[fix] كنت ابحث عنك[fix]
[ko:]할아버지한테 일이 좀 생겨서,[fix] 가족들하고 같이  탕산에 갔다왔어.[fix]
[ru:]и я ездил с родителями к ним в Таншань[fix]
[zh:]我正找你呢
[fre:]Je voulais te voir.
[zh:]我这儿一特好的主意
[en:]I wanted to see you.[fix] I've a great idea.[fix]
[fre:]J'ai une excellente idée.
[ar:]لدي فكرة رائعة[fix]
[ko:]나도 네가 보고 싶더라.[fix]
[ru:]Ты очень вовремя вернулся.[fix] У меня есть классная идея.[fix]
[zh:]什么
[fre:]Quoi ?
[ar:]ماذا؟[fix]
[zh:]是你的主意吗
[en:]What?[fix] You have a great idea?![fix]
[fre:]Tu as une excellente idée ?
[ar:]أنت لديك فكرة رائعة؟[fix]
[ko:]내게 기막힌 생각이 있어.[fix]
[ru:]Что?[fix] Что это еще за идея?[fix]
[zh:]怎么现在学得爱吹牛啊
[en:]When'd you get so full of yourself?[fix]
[fre:]Depuis quand tu es si sûr de toi ?
[ar:]متى صرتَ مغرورا هكذا؟[fix] توك تلاحظين؟[fix]
[ko:]뭔데?[fix] 네가 기막힌 생각을 했다고?![fix] 너 언제부터 그렇게 자신만만했졌냐?[fix]
[ru:]У тебя появились от меня секреты?[fix]
[zh:]你刚发现哪
[fre:]Tu viens juste de le remarquer ?
[zh:]可不是刚发现吗
[en:]You've just noticed, have you?
[ar:]كيف لم أر هذا من قبل؟[fix]
[ru:]Ты только что заметила?
[zh:]以前怎么不知道你爱吹牛啊
[en:]Just.[fix] But how'd you hide it from me?[fix]
[fre:]Tout juste. Mais pourquoi tu ne m'as rien dit ?[fix]
[ar:]كيف لم أعرف من قبل أنك مغرور هكذا؟
[ko:]너도 알아챘구나.[fix] 물론.[fix] 네가 날 어떻게 속여?[fix]
[ru:]Да, только что.[fix] И много ты еще скрываешь?[fix]
[zh:]我这是隐藏得比较深
[en:]I hid it deep inside.[fix]
[fre:]Je l'avais caché au plus profond de moi.
[ar:]كنت أخفي ذلك بداخلي
[ru:]Я все прячу глубоко внутри[fix]
[zh:]你还隐藏什么
[en:]What else are you hiding?[fix]
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que tu caches d'autre ?
[ar:]ما الذي تخفيه أيضا؟[fix] أحقا تريدين أن تعرفي الآن؟[fix]
[ko:]마음속에 꼭꼭 감춰뒀었는데.[fix]
[ru:]А что ты еще прячешь?[fix]
[zh:]你现在想知道
[en:]So, you want to know, do you?[fix]
[ru:]А тебе это надо знать?[fix]
[zh:]对 现在就想知道
[en:]Yes, right now.[fix]
[fre:]- Tu voudrais le savoir, hein ? - Oui, maintenant ![fix]
[ar:]نعم، الآن[fix] حسنا، سأخبرك إذن[fix]
[ko:]감춰둔게 또 뭐 있어?[fix] 너 알고 싶어?[fix]
[ru:]Да, и прямо сейчас.[fix]
[zh:]那我让你啊
[en:]Then, I'll tell you...[fix]
[fre:]Alors, je vais tout te dire...
[ar:]هيا
[ko:]응, 당장.[fix]
[ru:]Хорошо, я тебе скажу...[fix]
[zh:]说吧
[fre:]Vas-y.
[zh:]你这么想知道
[en:]Go on.[fix] You really want to know?[fix]
[fre:]Tu veux vraiment savoir ?
[ar:]تريدين أن تعرفي لهذه الدرجة، صحيح؟[fix]
[ko:]그럼, 말해줄게...[fix] Go on. 해 봐.[fix]
[ru:]Ну, договаривай.[fix] Ты правда это хочешь знать?[fix]
[zh:]废话
[ar:]لا لديك إلا الهراء[fix]
[ko:]너 정말로 알고 싶어?[fix]
[zh:]喂 马小军 晚上过来啊
[en:]Oh, Ma Xiaojun! Come over tonight![fix]
[fre:]Oh, Ma Xiaojun ! Viens ce soir !
[ar:]ماشياو جون)، تعال الليلة)[fix]
[ko:]야, 마샤오준! 오늘밤 와![fix]
[ru:]- Ой, Ма Сяоцзюнь. Приходи к нам вечером. - Хорошо.[fix]
[zh:]你是不是觉得我特笨
[ar:]أتعتقد أن جسمي محرج؟[fix]
[zh:]是不是太胖了
[en:]Do you think I'm awkward and fat?[fix]
[fre:]Tu ne me trouves pas grosse et maladroite ?[fix]
[ar:]أنا سمينة جدا، صحيح؟[fix]
[ko:]내가 많이 살쪘다고 생각해?[fix]
[ru:]Ты думаешь, что я неуклюжая и толстая?[fix]
[zh:]你丫够肥的 什么
[en:]You're fat cow. What?[fix]
[fre:]- Tu es une grosse vache. - Quoi ?
[ar:]أنت متينة جدا[fix] ماذا؟
[ru:]- Ага, толстая корова. - Что?[fix]
[zh:]是唉呀的呀 不是你丫挺的丫
[en:]I said, you're fatter now.[fix]
[fre:]J'ai dit, tu as pris du poids.
[ar:]قلت أنك جميلة ومتينة وليس متينة جدا
[ko:]- 살찐 암소같아. - 뭐야?[fix] 네가 더 쪘다고.[fix]
[ru:]Я сказал, что ты растолстела.[fix]
[zh:]哼
[ar:]"لن تحصل على العاج من فم الكلب"[fix]
[zh:]狗嘴里吐不出象牙来
[fre:]Ne t'attends pas à obtenir de l'ivoire de la bouche d'un chien ![fix]
[zh:]那人嘴里也吐不出象牙来啊
[en:]Can't get ivory from the mouth of a dog![fix]
[fre:]Ni d'un homme non plus !
[ar:]ولا من فم الانسان[fix]
[ru:]От собаки не добудешь слоновой кости, от тебя - доброго слова.[fix]
[zh:]你能吐出象牙来吗
[en:]Can't get ivory from a person, either.[fix] Can you produce ivory from your mouth?[fix]
[fre:]Tu sors de l'ivoire de ta bouche, toi ?
[ar:]أيمكنك انتاج العاج من فمك؟[fix]
[ko:]개 입에서 상아가 나올리 없지![fix] 사람 입에서도 상아는 안 나와.[fix] 네 입에서는 상아를 만들 수 있어?[fix]
[ru:]От тебя тоже ничего хорошего.[fix] Разве что бивни у тебя вырастут.[fix]
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan.[fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan.
[ar:](مي لان) يريدك أن تنظري وهو يغطس[fix]
[ko:]미란.[fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань.[fix]
[zh:]他是想跳水给你看
[fre:]Il veut que tu le regardes plonger.
[zh:]是吗 我不想看
[en:]He wants you to watch him dive.
[fre:]Ah oui ? Je ne veux pas le regarder.[fix]
[ar:]حقا؟ لا أريد أن أرى[fix]
[ru:]Он хочет, чтобы ты посмотрела как он прыгнет.
[zh:]哎 对了 马小军
[en:]Yeah? I don't want to watch.[fix]
[ar:]...(بالمناسبة، (ماشياو جون[fix]
[ko:]자기가 다이빙하는거 봐달래잖아.[fix] 그래? 보고 싶지 않아.[fix]
[ru:]Да? А я не хочу смотреть.[fix]
[zh:]讨厌
[ar:]يا له من غبي[fix]
[zh:]其实 我就是腰粗了一点
[en:]Actually, I'm just a bit thick-waisted.[fix]
[fre:]En fait, j'ai juste de grosses hanches.
[ar:]في الواقع، وركاي فقط هما المتينين قليلا
[ko:]사실, 내 허리가 좀 두껍긴 하지.[fix]
[ru:]На самом деле я немного раздалась только в талии.[fix]
[zh:]何止是腰啊
[en:]Not just your waist.[fix]
[fre:]Pas que les hanches.
[ar:]...ليس وركيك فقط
[ru:]Не только в талии.[fix]
[zh:]瞧你这腿 你这肚子
[en:]Look at those legs, that tummy,[fix]
[fre:]Regarde ces jambes, ce ventre,
[ar:]انظري لساقيك، وهذا البطن
[ko:]허리 뿐만이 아냐.[fix] 네 다리, 그리고 그 배[fix]
[ru:]И ноги, и живот...[fix]
[zh:]再瞧瞧这儿
[en:]and here![fix]
[fre:]et là !
[ar:]!وانظري لهذه هنا[fix]
[ru:]и вот здесь![fix]
[zh:]这儿 这儿
[zh:]够出口标准了
[en:]Export quality![fix]
[fre:]100 % pur porc !
[ar:]!جودة تصديرية
[ko:]그리고 여기![fix] 수출해도 되겠어![fix]
[ru:]Экспортная свинина.[fix]
[zh:]我是胖了点啊
[en:]I am a bit fat.[fix]
[fre:]Je suis un peu grosse.
[ar:]فعلا أنا سمينة بعض الشيء[fix]
[ru:]Да, я немного жирная.[fix]
[zh:]你说 我是不是不该穿这件游泳衣
[en:]Do you think I should be wearing a bathing suit?[fix]
[fre:]Tu penses que je ne devrais pas me mettre en maillot ?
[ar:]قل لي، أيفترض أن أكون مرتدية لبس السباحة؟[fix]
[ko:]내가 좀 찌긴 했지.[fix] 내가 수영복 입은거 어떻게 생각하니?[fix]
[ru:]Как ты думаешь, мне не позорно в купальнике?[fix]
[zh:]是不是太暴露了
[en:]Does it expose too much of me?[fix]
[fre:]Ça ne montre pas trop mes formes ?
[ar:]أهو يكشف الكثير مني؟[fix]
[ru:]Наверное, все вываливается?[fix]
[zh:]其实你不穿这游泳衣我也看得出来
[en:]Nothing I can't see when you're not wearing one.[fix]
[fre:]Rien que je ne peux voir quand tu n'en portes pas.
[ar:]لست أرى شيئا لا أراه وأنت بغير هذا اللبس[fix]
[ko:]너무 노출이 심한가?[fix]
[ru:]Да не больше, чем в другой одежде.[fix]
[zh:]什么
[fre:]Quoi ?
[ar:]ماذا؟ ما الذي تراه؟[fix]
[zh:]你看出什么啦
[en:]What?[fix]
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que tu veux dire ?
[ru:]Что?[fix]
[zh:]啊 算了 算了 你生气了
[en:]What do you mean?[fix] Never mind, you'd be angry.[fix]
[fre:]Laisse tomber, ça te mettrait en colère.
[ar:]لا عليك، ستغضبين[fix]
[ko:]네가 수영복을 입지 않았더라면, 난 아마 몰랐을거야.[fix] 뭘?[fix] 무슨 뜻이야?[fix]
[ru:]Что ты имеешь в виду?[fix] Не скажу, а то обидишься.[fix]
[zh:]你说 你说呗 说呗 我不生气
[en:]Tell me! I won't be angry.[fix]
[fre:]Raconte ! Je ne me fâcherai pas.
[ar:]قل لي! لن أغضب[fix]
[ko:]신경쓰지 마, 들으면 화낼거야.[fix]
[ru:]Нет уж, говори. Я не обижусь.[fix]
[zh:]跟那刚生了孩子似的
[en:]It's like you've just had a baby.[fix]
[fre:]C'est comme si tu venais juste d'accoucher.
[ar:]تبدين كأنك أنجبتِ للتو[fix]
[ko:]말해봐! 화 안 낼게.[fix]
[ru:]У меня такое впечатление, что ты беременная.[fix]
[zh:]马小军 嗯
[en:]Ma Xiaojun! I'm not speaking to you.[fix]
[fre:]Ma Xiaojun ! Je ne te parle plus ![fix]
[ar:]!(ماشياو جون)[fix]
[ko:]꼭 임신한 여자 같아.[fix] 마샤오준!  너랑 말 안 해![fix]
[ru:]Ма Сяоцзюнь, я с тобой не разговариваю.[fix]
[zh:]不理你
[ar:]لن أكلمك[fix]
[zh:]下来啊
[fre:]Mi Lan, viens !
[ar:]مي لان)، ادخلي المسبح)[fix]
[zh:]哈哈 不 我不下来
[en:]Mi Lan, come on in!
[fre:]Non, vous venez.[fix]
[ar:]لا، لن ادخل أنت اخرج
[ko:]미란, 들어 와![fix] 싫어, 너희들이 이리로 와.[fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань, иди сюда.
[zh:]你上来
[en:]No, you come here.[fix]
[ru:]Сам подойди.[fix]
[zh:]10米怎么样
[ar:]ماذا عن ارتفاع 10 أمتار؟ - لا أجيد الغوص -[fix]
[zh:]我不跳
[zh:]米兰
[zh:]快 快下来 米兰 我教你跳水
[ar:]مي لان)، تعالي وسأعلمك) - هيا -[fix]
[zh:]你下来
[zh:]马小军 你不是人
[en:]Ma Xiaojun, you're a beast.[fix]
[fre:]Ma Xiaojun, tu es un monstre.
[ar:]!ماشياو جون)! أنت وحش)[fix]
[ko:]마샤오준, 너 짐승이야.[fix]
[ru:]Ма Сяоцзюнь, ты скотина.[fix]
[zh:]去你的
[en:]Fuck off.[fix]
[fre:]Va te faire foutre ![fix]
[ar:]دعني يا لعين[fix]
[ko:]꺼져.[fix]
[ru:]Да пошел ты![fix]
[zh:]你别理他
[en:]Hey, kid, come here.[fix]
[ar:]تجاهله فقط[fix]
[ko:]야, 너, 이리 와봐.[fix]
[ru:]Эй, парень, иди сюда.[fix]
[zh:]你叫刘忆苦 对
[en:]You Liu Yiku?[fix]
[fre:]C'est toi Liu Yiku ?[fix] Ouais.
[ar:]أنت (ليو إيكو)؟[fix] صحيح
[ko:]니가 류이쿠냐?[fix]
[ru:]- Это ты Лю Еку? - Да.[fix]
[zh:]米兰你带着的
[fre:]C'est ta copine ?[fix]
[ar:]أحضرتَ (مي لان) إلى هنا؟[fix]
[zh:]对
[en:]Yes.[fix]
[fre:]Ouais.[fix]
[ar:]صحيح[fix]
[ko:]그래.[fix]
[ru:]- Ты ее парень? - Да.
[zh:]哥们 你们彼此还都不认识
[en:]Biaoge, don't you know each other?[fix]
[fre:]Biaoge, vous vous connaissez ?
[ar:]...لربما أنكم لم تتقابلوا من قبل
[ko:]비오거, 서로 모르는 사이인가?[fix]
[ru:]Бяогэ, вы не знакомы?[fix]
[zh:]小刘 我给你介绍介绍
[en:]Let me introduce you.[fix]
[fre:]Laisse-moi vous présenter.
[ar:]ليو)، دعني أعرفك به)[fix]
[ru:]Давайте я вас представлю.[fix]
[zh:]这是彪哥
[en:]This is the famous Biaoge.[fix]
[fre:]Voici le fameux Biaoge.
[ar:]هذا الأخ النمر[fix]
[ru:]Это почтенный Бяогэ.[fix]
[zh:]大名鼎鼎
[ar:]الذي تسبقه شهرته[fix]
[ko:]내가 소개시켜 줄게.[fix] 이쪽은 그 유명한 비오거.[fix]
[zh:]没什么
[fre:]Ne t'emballe pas,
[zh:]我就是问问
[en:]It's no big deal.[fix] Just asking.[fix]
[fre:]je demande juste.
[ar:]هذا كل شيء أنا أسأل فقط[fix] ما دام الأمر هكذا فسنذهب[fix]
[ko:]별 거 아니야.[fix] 그냥 물어볼게 있어서.[fix]
[ru:]Да ты не парься.[fix] Я просто так спросил.[fix]
[zh:]没事 我们就走了
[en:]If that's the case,[fix]
[fre:]Dans ce cas,
[ru:]Если просто так[fix]
[zh:]后会有期 朋友
[en:]see you around.[fix]
[fre:]on se reverra.
[ar:]حسنا. سنلتقي مجددا يا أصدقاء[fix]
[ko:]그런 이유라면, 나중에 보지.[fix]
[ru:]то бывай.[fix]
[zh:]走
[en:]See you around, pal![fix]
[fre:]On se reverra, mon ami !
[ar:]لنذهب[fix]
[ko:]좋아, 나중에 보자고, 친구들.[fix]
[ru:]Как-нибудь увидимся, приятель.[fix]
[zh:]米兰
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:](مي لان)[fix]
[zh:]那彪哥 彪哥是谁呀
[en:]Mi Lan![fix] Who's that Biaoge guy?[fix]
[fre:]C'est qui ce Biaoge ?
[ar:]...الأخ النمر ذاك[fix] من يكون؟[fix]
[ko:]미란![fix] 저 비오거라는 놈 누구야?[fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань![fix] Кто этот Бяогэ?[fix]
[zh:]你也想了解吗
[en:]You really want to know?[fix]
[fre:]Tu veux vraiment le savoir ?
[ar:]تريد أن تعرف حقا؟
[ko:]진짜 알고 싶어?[fix]
[ru:]Ты правда хочешь знать?[fix]
[zh:]少打听
[en:]Forget it.[fix]
[fre:]Laisse tomber.
[ar:]انسى[fix]
[ko:]신경 끄셔.[fix]
[ru:]Забудь о нем.[fix]
[zh:]每当我问起彪哥的事
[ar:]، كل مرة اسأل عن الأخ النمر ذاك[fix]
[zh:]他总是说少打听
[en:]Every time I asked about him, she told me to drop it.[fix]
[fre:]À chaque fois que je lui ai demandé, elle m'a dit de laisser tomber.[fix]
[ar:]تقول لي أن انسى[fix]
[ko:]내가 그에 대해 물어볼 때마다, 그녀는 내 말을 무시했다.[fix]
[ru:]Это она повторяла каждый раз, когда я спрашивал о нем.[fix]
[zh:]后来听说 彪子曾经和她很熟
[en:]Later I heard they were once very close...[fix]
[fre:]Plus tard, j'ai appris qu'ils étaient très proches,
[ar:]لاحقا سمعتُ أنهما كانا مقربين جدا[fix]
[ru:]Позже я узнал, что у них был роман...[fix]
[zh:]甚至还为她瞎了一只眼睛
[en:]and that he lost his eye on her account.[fix]
[fre:]et qu'il avait perdu un œil pour elle.
[ar:]وأنه فقد عينه بسببها[fix]
[ko:]훗날 들은바로는,  그들은 아주 가까운 사이였었고...[fix] 그는 그녀 때문에  실명(失明)을 했다고 했다.[fix]
[ru:]и глаз он потерял из-за нее.[fix]
[zh:]从那天起
[fre:]Depuis ce jour-là,
[zh:]刘忆苦竟公然以带着米兰自居
[en:]From then on,[fix] Liu Yiku openly took Mi Lan as his chic.[fix]
[fre:]Liu Yiku a fait de Mi Lan sa copine.
[ar:]، منذ ذلك فصاعدا ليو إيكو) أخذ (مي لان) علناً كفتاته)[fix]
[ko:]그 때부터,[fix] 류이쿠는 공개적으로  미란을 자기의 여자처럼 데리고 다녔다.[fix]
[ru:]После этого случая[fix] Лю Еку открыто стал называть Ми Лань своей девушкой.[fix]
[zh:]八月二十三号 罗马尼亚祖国解放日那天
[en:]August 23 was Romanian Liberation Day...[fix]
[fre:]Le 23 août fut le jour le la Libération de la Roumanie,
[ar:]يوم 23 أغسطس كان يوم التحرير الروماني[fix]
[ru:]23 августа был день освобождения Румынии[fix]
[zh:]也是我和刘忆苦的生日
[en:]and my and Liu Yiku's birthday.[fix]
[fre:]et c'était aussi le jour de mon anniversaire et celui de Liu Yiku.
[ar:]ويوم عيد ميلادي أنا (و(ليو إيكو[fix]
[ko:]8월 23일은 루마니아 독립 기념일이다...[fix]
[ru:]и день рождения - мое и Лю Еку.[fix]
[zh:]我们俩同月同日但是不同年
[en:]We were born the same day, different year.[fix]
[fre:]On est né le même jour, mais d'années différentes.
[ar:]ولدنا بنفس الشهر ونفس اليوم ولكن بسنتين مختلفتين[fix]
[ko:]그리고 나와 류이쿠의 생일이기도 하다.[fix]
[ru:]Мы родились в один день, только в разные года.[fix]
[zh:]晚上我们奔了老莫
[en:]We had a party at the Moscow Restaurant.[fix]
[fre:]On a fait la fête au Restaurant Moscovite.
[ar:]بتلك الليلة، ذهبنا إلى مطعم موسكو
[ko:]우리는 해(年)는 다르지만,  같은 날 태어났다.[fix] 우리는 모스크바 식당에서 파티를 했다.[fix]
[ru:]Вечеринку устроили в ресторане "Москва".[fix]
[zh:]好 好
[en:]Hello![fix]
[fre:]Enfin !
[ar:]رائع - !انظروا من أتى -[fix]
[ko:]안녕![fix]
[ru:]Привет![fix]
[zh:]来了
[zh:]你们好 你好
[en:]Hi! You're looking gorgeous![fix]
[fre:]Salut ! Tu es splendide !
[ar:]مرحبا يا شباب - مرحبا -[fix]
[ru:]Здорово! Классно выглядишь.[fix]
[zh:]见到你们格外亲嘛
[en:]I feel about you like the Masses about the Party.[fix]
[fre:]Je tiens à vous comme les Masses du Parti.
[ar:]شيء سار جدا رؤية الجميع معاً هنا[fix]
[ko:]안녕! 너 오늘 멋있다![fix]
[ru:]Я вас люблю, как Народ Партию.[fix]
[zh:]格外亲
[en:]Like the Masses about the Party![fix]
[fre:]Comme les Masses du Parti !
[ar:]!سار جدا[fix]
[ru:]Как Народ Партию![fix]
[zh:]看看我给俩位带了什么
[en:]Look what I've brought the birthday boys.[fix]
[fre:]Regardez ce que j'ai apporté pour vos anniversaires.
[ar:]انظروا ماذا أحضرتُ لأصحاب عيد الميلاد
[ko:]너 오늘 꼭 공산당 간부 같은데.[fix] 당 간부 같데![fix] 생일 맞은 친구들한테 뭘 가져왔는지 봐.[fix]
[ru:]Посмотрите, что я принесла в подарок мальчикам.[fix]
[zh:]手干净吗
[fre:]T'as les mains propres ?
[ar:]يدك نظيفة؟ - انظري -[fix]
[zh:]你瞧
[en:]Hands clean?
[fre:]Regarde toi-même.
[ru:]Руки чистые?
[zh:]好吧
[en:]Check them out.[fix] OK.[fix]
[fre:]OK.
[ar:]حسنا[fix]
[ko:]손 씻었어?[fix] 검사해 봐.[fix] 오케이.[fix]
[ru:]На, посмотри.[fix] Хорошо.[fix]
[zh:]一本诗集
[en:]Wow! Pushkin's poetry![fix]
[fre:]Wouah ! De la poésie de Poushkine !
[ar:]!كتاب شعر
[ko:]와우! 푸쉬킨 시집![fix]
[ru:]О! Поэзия Пушкина![fix]
[zh:]冬天戴上它去冰场 帅不帅
[en:]Won't you look sharp skating in that![fix]
[fre:]Tu ne seras pas chic, quand tu patineras avec ça ?
[ar:]أتظنون أنه سيبدو أنيقاً مرتدياً هذا في صالة التزلج  بالشتاء؟  - أنيق جدا[fix]
[ru:]А в нем ты будешь ходить кататься на коньках.[fix]
[zh:]帅 帅 帅 可以啊
[en:]Really sharp.[fix]
[fre:]Très chic.
[ar:]!خطأ[fix]
[ko:]그걸 하고 스케이트를 타면 멋질 것 같다![fix]
[ru:]А ему идет.[fix]
[zh:]不对
[fre:]Aucune fille ne pourra résister.[fix]
[zh:]妞都围着他 还用得着拍吗
[en:]No chick will be able to resist his advances.[fix] Wrong - they'll surround him. No need to advance.[fix]
[fre:]Ouais, il sera encerclé, plus besoin de draguer.[fix]
[ar:]هل ستتجمع الفتيات عليه دون أن يحاول حتى؟[fix] لا ينفع، هذا خطير[fix]
[ko:]정말 멋지다.[fix]
[ru:]Ни одна девчонка перед ним не устоит![fix] Наоборот - они облепят его. Он и двигаться не сможет.[fix]
[zh:]不成不成 太危险了
[zh:]妞都围成一团 非掉冰窟窿不可
[en:]No good, no good, that's too dangerous.[fix] If they surround him the ice will crack...[fix]
[fre:]Ce sera trop dangereux. Si elles l'entourent, la glace va casser.[fix]
[ar:]لو تجمعن عليه الجليد لن يتحمل
[ko:]네가 스케이트를 타고 나가면 여자들이 사족을 못쓸거야.[fix] 아니야. 여자들이 둘러쌀테니까, 앞으로 나갈 필요가 없지.[fix] 안 좋아, 안 좋아, 그건 너무 위험해.[fix]
[ru:]Плохо дело, это очень опасно.[fix] Они его окружат, лед провалится...[fix]
[zh:]哥 还让我戴吧
[fre:]Donne-moi ça, c'est plus sûr.[fix]
[ar:]عليك أن تدعني أرتديه يا أخي[fix]
[zh:]谢谢啊
[en:]...give that to me, it's safer.[fix] Thank you.[fix]
[fre:]Merci.
[ar:]شكرا
[ko:]여자들이 둘러싸면,  아이스링크가 깨질지도 몰라...[fix]
[ru:]подари лучше мне, это безопаснее.[fix] Спасибо.[fix]
[zh:]瞧你那样 光谢谢就得了
[en:]Look at you. You're just going to say 'thank you'?[fix]
[fre:]Regarde-toi. Tu as même dit "merci".
[ar:]يا عيني، لن تقول إلا شكرا فقط؟
[ko:]...그러니까 그거 나 줘. 그게 안전해.[fix] 고마워.[fix] 얘 봐.  겨우 '고마워'라는 말 뿐이야?[fix]
[ru:]Посмотрите на него. "Спасибом" не отделаешься.[fix]
[zh:]那还怎么着
[ar:]ماذا أقول غير ذلك؟[fix]
[zh:]你想吧
[en:]What should I do?[fix] Think about it.[fix]
[fre:]- Qu'est-ce que j'aurais dû faire ? - Cherche.[fix]
[ar:]فكر[fix]
[ru:]А что мне надо сделать?[fix] А ты подумай на досуге.[fix]
[zh:]看看你的马小军
[en:]Open yours, Ma Xiaojun.[fix]
[fre:]Ouvre le tien, Ma Xiaojun.
[ar:](افتح هديتك، (ماشياو جون
[ko:]내가 뭘 해줄까?[fix] 생각해 봐.[fix] 네 거 열어봐, 마샤오준.[fix]
[ru:]Открой свой, Ма Сяоцзюнь.[fix]
[zh:]哇 这种关怀得算无微不至了吧
[en:]She looks after you like the Party itself.[fix]
[fre:]Elle te regarde comme si tu étais le Parti.
[ar:]!عجيب، لقد اهتمت بك فعلا[fix]
[ru:]Плавки! Она заботится о тебе как Партия.[fix]
[zh:]操 你丫扯蛋
[en:]For once you've said something clever.[fix]
[fre:]Pour une fois que tu dis quelque chose d'intelligent.
[ar:]!ابعد يدك اللعينة عنه
[ru:]В кои веки что-то умное сказал.[fix]
[zh:]哎 试试 拿出来试试
[en:]Try it on.[fix]
[fre:]Essaye-le.
[ar:]جربه[fix]
[ko:]미란이 당(黨)처럼 널 보살핀다야~.[fix] 이번만은 똑똑한 소리하는구나.[fix]
[ru:]Примерь их.[fix]
[zh:]我看那腰肯定合适
[fre:]La taille a l'air bonne.
[ar:]مقاس الخصر مناسب بكل تأكيد[fix]
[zh:]腰合适 那不就得了
[en:]The waist looks right.[fix]
[fre:]Alors il doit t'aller ?
[ar:]إن كان مناسب بالخصر أليس هذا كافيا؟[fix]
[ko:]한 번 입어봐.[fix]
[ru:]В талии нормально.[fix]
[zh:]哎 那可不一定 马猴得试试
[en:]Then it'll fit, won't it?[fix] Not necessarily. Try it on.[fix]
[fre:]Pas forcément. Essaye-le !
[ar:]ليس بالضرورة...جربه يا قرد[fix] !جربه يا قرد[fix]
[ko:]가운데 부분이 오른쪽으로 치우친것 같다.[fix] 그래도 잘 맞을거야.[fix] 말할 필요 없이, 한 번 입어봐.[fix]
[ru:]Должны подойти.[fix] Не факт. Надо примерить.[fix]
[zh:]马猴试试 还是试试吧
[fre:]Essaye-le ! Essaye-le !
[zh:]操 流氓
[en:]Try it on! Try it on![fix] Gutter-heads![fix]
[fre:]Imbéciles !
[ar:]...اللعنة! حقيرين[fix] تجاهلهم. تمرن على السباحة وحسب[fix]
[ko:]입어봐! 입어봐![fix] 음흉한 놈들![fix]
[ru:]Примерь их! Примерь![fix] Вот ослы![fix]
[zh:]甭理他们 你加紧练吧
[en:]Ignore them. Just practice your swimming.[fix]
[fre:]Ignore-les. Continue de t'entraîner,
[ar:]ما زلت أعتمد عليك لتنقذني[fix]
[ru:]Не обращай внимания. Плавай почаще.[fix]
[zh:]我还等你来救我呢
[ru:]Не забывай - тебе еще меня спасать.[fix]
[zh:]得 那这么着 我也用不着谢你了
[en:]I'm still counting on you to save me.[fix] Well, then no need to thank you.[fix]
[fre:]je compte toujours sur toi pour me sauver. - Alors pas besoin de te remercier,[fix]
[ar:]أظن إذن لا داعي لشكرك إن كان الهدف بالنهاية أن أنقذك فقط[fix]
[ko:]애들말은 무시하고,  수영 연습이나 잘 해.[fix] 난 아직도 네가  날 구해줄거라고 믿으니까.[fix]
[ru:]А, ну тогда я и благодарить не буду.[fix]
[zh:]反正也是为了救你的命
[en:]It's only so I can save you, after all.[fix]
[fre:]si c'est juste pour aller te sauver.
[ru:]Ты же о себе заботилась, в конце концов.[fix]
[zh:]再说刚才刘忆苦 已经深情对你表示过谢意了
[en:]Consider Liu Yiku's deeply felt thanks from both of us.[fix]
[fre:]Considère que Liu Yiku te remercie pour nous deux.[fix]
[ar:]لذا اعتبري شكره الصادق من كلينا[fix]
[ko:]좋아, 그럼 고맙다는 말은 안 해도 되겠네.[fix] 그러니까 결국,  너를 구할 수 있도록 주는거잖아.[fix] 류이쿠는 우리 둘 다에게 깊이 감사해야겠군.[fix]
[ru:]Можешь считать "спасибо" Лю Еку благодарностью от нас обоих.[fix]
[zh:]也就代表我吧
[zh:]你可真没良心
[fre:]Crétin.
[ar:]!لا قلب لك فعلا[fix]
[zh:]得 就算没有吧
[en:]You're a jerk.
[fre:]Exactement.
[ar:].حسنا، إن كان هذا رأيك
[ru:]Ты мелкий поганец.
[zh:]同志 我们点的东西赶紧上吧
[en:]That's right.[fix]
[ar:]أيتها الرفيقة، هلا أسرعتِ بطعامنا؟ وصلنا كلنا الآن[fix]
[ru:]Это правда.[fix]
[zh:]我们人都来齐了
[en:]Comrade, could you bring us our food?[fix]
[fre:]Camarade, vous pouvez apporter la nourriture ?[fix]
[ko:]넌 바보야.[fix] 맞아.[fix] 동지, 여기 음식 좀 주세요.[fix]
[ru:]Товарищ, что там с нашей едой?[fix]
[zh:]不忙 给我们先来点水吧
[en:]Or at least some water first?[fix]
[fre:]Ou au moins de l'eau ?
[ar:]لا عجلة، أحضري لنا بعض الماء أولا[fix]
[ru:]Хотя бы воды дайте.[fix]
[zh:]哎 她怎么不说话呀
[en:]Bitch! She's ignoring us.[fix]
[fre:]La salope ! Elle nous ignore.
[ar:]ألا تستطيع تلك النادلة الكلام؟[fix]
[ko:]아니면 적어도 먼저 물이라도 주세요.[fix]
[ru:]Сука! Она нас игнорирует.[fix]
[zh:]咱先玩咱们的
[en:]Never mind. Let's have some fun.[fix]
[fre:]- C'est pas grave. - Amusons-nous.
[ar:]لنستمتع أولا - ماذا يمكن أن نلعب؟ -[fix]
[ko:]제기랄! 우리 말을 무시하고 있네.[fix]
[ru:]Да и черт с ней. Давайте развлекаться.[fix]
[zh:]有什么好玩的
[fre:]- Comment ? - Réfléchis ! Tu as toujours des idées.[fix]
[ar:]!فكر! دائما لديك أفكار كثيرة[fix]
[zh:]想想啊 你不是主意多吗
[en:]How? What’s[fix]
[ru:]Как?[fix]
[zh:]要玩咱玩丢手绢
[en:]Think! You're always got lots of ideas![fix] Let's play 'find the hanky'.[fix]
[fre:]Jouons à "trouver l'andouille".
[ar:]يمكننا أن نلعب لعبة البحث عن المنديل[fix]
[ko:]신경 쓰지 마. 우리 재밌게 놀자.[fix]
[ru:]Думайте! У вас всегда куча идей.[fix] Давайте поиграем в "найди платок".[fix]
[zh:]就拿马猴那红裤衩怎么样
[en:]We can use Ma Xiaojun's red undies.[fix]
[fre:]On peut utiliser le slip rouge de Ma Xiaojun.
[ar:]ونستخدم سروال (ماشياو جون) الداخلي الأحمر
[ko:]어떻게? 뭐할까?[fix] 생각해 봐! 넌 항상 아이디어가 많잖아.[fix] '손수건 찾기' 어때?[fix]
[ru:]В роли платка - красные трусы Ма Сяоцзюнь![fix]
[zh:]那叫丢裤衩
[en:]Then that's 'find the undies'.[fix]
[fre:]Et après à "trouver le slip".
[ar:]"هذه اسمها "البحث عن السروال الداخلي[fix]
[ko:]마샤오준의 빨간 속옷으로 하면 돼.[fix] 그럼 그건 '속옷 찾기'잖아.[fix]
[ru:]Это уже будет "найди труселя".[fix]
[zh:]得 这么着得了
[fre:]J'ai un jeu.[fix]
[ar:]حسنا، حسنا[fix]
[zh:]咱俩玩个游戏
[en:]I've got a game.[fix]
[ar:]لدي لعبة[fix]
[ru:]Я знаю игру.[fix]
[zh:]不许拿生日礼物乱糟蹋
[en:]You're not allowed to ruin your gift![fix]
[fre:]Tu n'as pas le droit de ruiner ton cadeau.
[ar:]ممنوع تخرب هدية عيد ميلادك[fix]
[ko:]그럼 이 게임하자.[fix]
[ru:]Я запрещаю тебе играть моим подарком.[fix]
[zh:]没问题 你放心
[en:]Relax, we don't need it.[fix]
[fre:]T'inquiète, on n'en a pas besoin.
[ar:]اطمئني، لا نحتاجها[fix]
[ru:]Расслабься, он здесь не нужен.[fix]
[zh:]哎 你们谁有钢蹦儿
[en:]Who's got a coin?[fix]
[fre:]Quelqu'un a une pièce ?
[ar:]من لديه عملة معدنية؟[fix]
[ko:]선물 망치는거 하면 안 돼![fix]
[ru:]У кого есть монеты?[fix]
[zh:]怎么玩啊
[en:]How do you play?[fix]
[fre:]Comment on joue ?
[ar:]كيف طريقة اللعب؟[fix] واحد يكفي؟ - سنقامر؟ -[fix]
[ko:]걱정마, 그건 필요없어.[fix] 누구 동전 있어?[fix] 어떻게 하는건데?[fix]
[ru:]А как играть?[fix]
[zh:]赌钱啦
[fre:]- Une seule ? - On parie ?[fix]
[zh:]今儿当众考验你的诚实和勇气
[en:]One enough? Gambling?[fix] No, it's a test of your honesty and courage,[fix]
[fre:]Non, c'est un test d'honnêteté et de courage,
[ar:]سنختبر اليوم علناً صدقك وشجاعتك
[ko:]하나면 돼? 도박하는거야?[fix]
[ru:]- Одной хватит? - А это на деньги?[fix] Нет, это проверка твоей честности, храбрости,[fix]
[zh:]看看你是否还是处女
[en:]and whether you are a virgin![fix]
[fre:]et qu'importe que tu sois vierge ou pas !
[ar:]!وإن كنتِ عذراء أم لا
[ko:]아니, 이건 네가 정직하고  용기가 있는지 시험하는거야.[fix] 그리고 네가 처녀인지 아닌지도![fix]
[ru:]и даже девственности.[fix]
[zh:]来吧
[en:]OK! Let's do it![fix]
[fre:]OK ! Vas-y !
[ar:]!حسنا، لنقم بذلك[fix]
[ru:]Ладно! Давай играть![fix]
[zh:]我把这个蹦子夹在这儿
[en:]I'm putting the coin here.[fix]
[fre:]Je place la pièce là.
[ar:]سأضع العملة هنا[fix] واسألك أسئلة[fix]
[ko:]좋아, 그거 하자.[fix]
[ru:]Я зажимаю монету пальцами[fix]
[zh:]向你提出一些问题
[en:]Each time I ask a question...[fix]
[zh:]你必须如实回答
[fre:]À chaque fois que je te pose une question, tu dois répondre la vérité[fix]
[ko:]동전을 여기다 놓고.[fix]
[ru:]и задаю вопрос...[fix]
[zh:]要简短
[zh:]而且要把这蹦儿从这儿抽出来
[en:]you have to answer truthfully while pulling out the coin.[fix]
[fre:]en tirant sur la pièce.[fix]
[ar:]عليك أن تجيبي بصدق وصراحة .بعد أن تسحبي العملة من يدي هنا[fix]
[ko:]내가 매번 질문할 때마다...[fix] 동전을 빼면서, 정직하게 대답해야 해.[fix]
[ru:]Ты должна честно ответить, вытаскивая монету.[fix]
[zh:]来吧 好吧
[fre:]Pas de sales tours, OK ?[fix]
[ar:]حسنا - طيب -[fix]
[zh:]你不许赖啊
[en:]No dirty tricks, all right?[fix]
[ar:]بدون حيل قذرة، حسنا؟  - حسنا -[fix]
[ko:]속임수 쓰기 없기다, 알았지?[fix]
[ru:]Только без грязных шуточек, ладно?[fix]
[zh:]第一个问题
[fre:]Première question.
[ar:]السؤال الأول
[zh:]你今年多大了
[en:]First question:[fix] how old are you?[fix]
[fre:]Quel âge as-tu ?
[ar:]كم عمرك؟[fix]
[ru:]Первый вопрос:[fix] Сколько тебе лет?[fix]
[zh:]不行 这问题我不能告诉你
[en:]No good, can't tell you.[fix]
[fre:]Pas bon, je ne peux pas te répondre.
[ar:]لا ينفع، لا أستطيع أن أخبرك[fix]
[ko:]첫번째 질문.[fix] 몇 살입니까?[fix]
[ru:]Бесполезно, я не скажу.[fix]
[zh:]反正比你们都大
[en:]Older than you.[fix]
[fre:]Plus que toi.
[ar:]أكبر منكم على أي حال[fix] حسنا، سأدعك تتجاوزين هذا السؤال[fix]
[ko:]싫어, 너한텐 말 못해.[fix]
[ru:]Больше чем тебе.[fix]
[zh:]得 先让你一把
[fre:]On passe celle-là.
[zh:]请问你的生日是几月几号
[en:]I'll let you pass on that one.[fix] But when's your birthday?[fix]
[fre:]Quand est ton anniversaire ?
[ar:]ولكن متى عيد ميلادك؟[fix]
[ko:]너보다 많아.[fix] 그거 하나는 통과시켜 주지.[fix] 생일은 언제입니까?[fix]
[ru:]Ладно, вопрос снимается.[fix] А когда у тебя день рождения?[fix]
[zh:]哎 你得先把蹦儿拔出来再说
[en:]Pull out the coin first.[fix]
[fre:]Tire la pièce d'abord.
[ar:]...ولدتُ يوم - اسحبي العملة أولا -[fix]
[ru:]Стоп, сначала монету вытащи.[fix]
[zh:]对啊 看人大蚂蚁都记住了
[en:]Right. Big Ant knows.[fix]
[fre:]C'est vrai. Big Ant connaît le jeu.
[ar:]صحيح. النملة الكبيرة يتذكر طريقة اللعب[fix] ما هو التاريخ؟[fix]
[ko:]동전을 먼저 빼.[fix]
[ru:]Правильно, Большой Муравей в курсе.[fix]
[zh:]来 几月几号
[en:]Right. What's the date?[fix]
[fre:]OK. C'est quand ?
[ru:]Итак, когда?[fix]
[zh:]一月一号 跟年是同一天生日
[en:]January 1, same as the year itself.[fix]
[fre:]Le 1er janvier, comme le Nouvel An.
[ar:]الأول من يناير، مثل السنة نفسها[fix]
[ko:]맞아, 왕개미가 잘 아네.[fix]
[ru:]Первого января, в первый день года.[fix]
[zh:]好 比你们俩罗马尼亚牛逼
[en:]That's more cool than Romanian Liberation Day.[fix]
[fre:]C'est plus cool que le Jour de la Libération de la Roumanie.
[ar:]هذا أروع بكثير من يوم التحرير الروماني
[ko:]자, 날짜는?[fix] 1월 1일, 연도는 아까대로고.[fix]
[ru:]Да, это прохладнее, чем в День освобождения Румынии.[fix]
[zh:]第二个问题 蹦还给我
[en:]Second question. Give me back the coin.[fix]
[fre:]Deuxième question. Rends-moi la pièce.
[ar:]السؤال الثاني. أعيدي العملة لي[fix]
[ko:]루마니아 독립기념일보다 더 추운 날이네.[fix]
[ru:]Второй вопрос. Отдай монету.[fix]
[zh:]你和你第一个男朋友认识时是多大
[en:]How old were you when you had your first boyfriend?[fix]
[fre:]À quel âge as-tu eu ton premier petit ami ?
[ar:]كم كان عمرك عندما صاحبتِ أول صديق حميم لك؟[fix]
[ko:]두번째 질문.  동전 다시 줘.[fix] 처음으로 남자 친구 사겼을 때,  몇 살이었습니까?[fix]
[ru:]Сколько тебе было, когда у тебя появился первый парень?[fix]
[zh:]十六
[en:]Uh... 16.[fix]
[fre:]Euh... 16 ans.
[ar:]16[fix]
[ru:]Ммм... 16.[fix]
[zh:]嗯 够小的
[en:]That's young![fix]
[fre:]C'est jeune !
[ar:]!سن صغير[fix]
[ko:]음...16.[fix] 그렇게나 일찍![fix]
[ru:]А не рано?[fix]
[zh:]第三个问题
[en:]Third question.[fix]
[fre:]Troisième question.
[ar:]السؤال الثالث[fix]
[ru:]Третий вопрос.[fix]
[zh:]你第一次和男朋友约会时 他都说了些什么
[en:]What did your boyfriend say to you on the first date?[fix]
[fre:]Que t'a dit ton copain lors du premier rencard ?
[ar:]في أول موعد مع صديقك ماذا قال لك؟[fix]
[ko:]세번째 질문.[fix] 당신의 남자 친구가 첫번째 데이트에서  당신에게 한 말은?[fix]
[ru:]Что тебе говорил тот парень?[fix]
[zh:]说了什么
[en:]Said what?[fix]
[fre:]Il a dit quoi ?
[ar:]ماذا قال؟[fix] ...هذا ضيق...إنه لا يخرج
[ko:]뭐라고 했지?[fix]
[ru:]Что сказал?[fix]
[zh:]什么
[fre:]Quoi ?
[ar:]ماذا؟
[zh:]我拔不出来
[en:]What?[fix] That's so tight! I can't pull it out![fix]
[fre:]Tu serres trop ! Je ne peux pas l'enlever ![fix]
[ar:]!لا أستطيع إخراجه
[ko:]뭐라고?[fix] 너무 꽉 잡았잖아! 못 빼겠어.[fix]
[ru:]Очень туго. Я не могу вытащить! Что?[fix]
[zh:]好 你个马猴 你不是人
[en:]Monkey, you are a beast.[fix]
[fre:]Monkey, tu es un monstre !
[ar:]اللعنة عليك يا قرد !أنت وحش[fix]
[ru:]Обезьяна, ты скотина.[fix]
[zh:]你这么坏啊
[en:]You are so bad![fix]
[fre:]Tu es méchant !
[ar:]!أنت فاسد جدا[fix]
[ko:]원숭아, 넌 짐승이야.[fix]
[ru:]Ты урод![fix]
[zh:]真没看出来
[ar:]!لم أتوقع ذلك أبدا[fix]
[zh:]打我脑袋干什么
[en:]What are you hitting my head for?[fix]
[fre:]Pourquoi tu me tapes sur la tête ?
[ar:]لماذا تضربين رأسي؟[fix]
[ko:]너무 못됐어![fix]
[ru:]Не смей трепать меня по голове![fix]
[zh:]我又不是你儿子
[en:]I'm not your son.[fix]
[fre:]Je ne suis pas ton fils.
[ar:]لست ابنك[fix]
[ru:]Я тебе не сынок.[fix]
[zh:]本来就傻 越打越笨了
[en:]I was dumb to begin with, but it gets worse with every hit.[fix]
[fre:]J'étais déjà assez bête, mais ça empire à chaque coup.
[ar:]كنتُ غبيا من الأساس لكن هذا يزداد سوءا مع كل ضربة[fix]
[ko:]내 머리는 왜 건드려?[fix] 난 니 아들이 아니야.[fix] 시작한 내가 바보지, 그렇지만, 때릴때마다 기분 나빠.[fix]
[ru:]Да, я зря это начал, но лучше не трогай меня.[fix]
[zh:]怎么啦 马小军
[en:]What's wrong, Ma Xiaojun?[fix]
[fre:]Qu'est-ce qui ne va pas Ma Xiaojun ?
[ar:]ما بك، (ماشياو جون)؟[fix] !لا تلمسيني[fix]
[ko:]왜 그래, 마샤오준?[fix]
[ru:]Что случилось, Ма Сяоцзюнь?[fix]
[zh:]哎 马小军
[fre:]Mao Xiaojun ?
[ar:]...(ماشياو جون)[fix]
[zh:]为什么 别碰我
[en:]Mao Xiaojun?[fix] What's going on? Don't touch me![fix]
[fre:]- Qu'est-ce qu'il y a ? - Ne me touche pas !
[ar:]ماذا هناك؟ - !لا تلمسيني -
[ko:]마샤오준?[fix] - 왜 그래? - 건들지 마![fix]
[ru:]Ма Сяоцзюнь?[fix] - Что происходит? - Не трогай меня![fix]
[zh:]马小军
[en:]Ma Xiaojun.[fix]
[fre:]Ma Xiaojun.
[ar:]...(ماشياو جون)[fix]
[ru:]Ма Сяоцзюнь.[fix]
[zh:]生气了
[en:]You're angry.[fix]
[fre:]Tu es en colère.
[ar:]أنت غاضب[fix]
[ru:]Ты сердишься.[fix]
[zh:]没生气
[en:]No...[fix]
[fre:]Non...
[ar:]لست غاضبا...ولم أغضب؟[fix]
[ko:]마샤오준.[fix] 너 화났구나.[fix]
[ru:]Нет...[fix]
[zh:]生什么气啊
[en:]why should I be angry?[fix]
[fre:]pourquoi je serai en colère ?
[ko:]아냐...[fix]
[ru:]Чего бы я сердился?[fix]
[zh:]那你怎么就急了
[ar:]إذن لماذا أنت منزعج هكذا؟[fix]
[zh:]谁急了 没急
[en:]So why are you so upset?[fix]
[fre:]- Alors pourquoi tu es si énervé ? - Qui est énervé ? Pas moi ![fix]
[ar:]من المنزعج؟ ليس أنا[fix]
[ko:]내가 왜 화가 나?[fix]
[ru:]И все таки - из-за чего ты расстроился?[fix]
[zh:]我说 我那点 我怎么招惹你了
[en:]Who's upset? Not me![fix] What did I ever do...[fix]
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que je t'ai fait[fix]
[ar:]كيف...ماذا فعلتُ لاستفزك هكذا؟[fix]
[ko:]그럼 왜 그렇게 놀래키는데?[fix] 누가 놀래켜? 난 아냐![fix] 내가 뭘 어떻게 했길래...[fix]
[ru:]Кто расстроился? Я не растроился.[fix] Я что-нибудь сделала,[fix]
[zh:]你对我这样
[fre:]pour que tu sois comme ça envers moi ?[fix]
[zh:]没有 没有 你没招我 没惹我 都挺好
[en:]to make you behave like this to me?[fix] Nothing, you've been great.[fix]
[fre:]Rien, tu es très bien.
[ar:]لا شيء، أفعالك طيبة[fix]
[ko:]나한테 이렇게 행동하는거야?[fix] 아니, 넌 다 잘했어.[fix]
[ru:]из-за чего ты так себя ведешь?[fix] Ничего. Все прекрасно.[fix]
[zh:]马小军
[en:]Ma Xiaojun,[fix]
[fre:]Ma Xiaojun,
[ar:](ماشياو جون)
[ru:]Ма Сяоцзюнь,[fix]
[zh:]今儿大家都挺高兴的
[en:]everyone was having a good time,[fix]
[fre:]tout le monde passait un bon moment,
[ar:]الكل كان مستمتع[fix]
[ru:]мы весело проводили время,[fix]
[zh:]你拿别人开心就行
[en:]you can dish it out...[fix]
[fre:]tu peux tout foutre en l'air...
[ar:]، لا مشكلة لديك إذا مازحتَ الآخرين[fix]
[ko:]마샤오준,[fix] 우리 모두 재밌게 놀고 있었어.[fix]
[ru:]у тебя испортилось настроение,[fix]
[zh:]别人碰你一下就这样
[en:]but you can't take it in.[fix]
[fre:]ou tu peux t'amuser.
[ar:]لكنك تجن بمجرد أن يلمسك أحد[fix]
[ko:]네가 하자고 했고...[fix]
[ru:]и ты не можешь объяснить почему.[fix]
[zh:]我动口不动手啊
[fre:]Je me sers de mon esprit, pas de mes mains.[fix]
[ar:]أمازح بالكلام وليس بيدي[fix]
[zh:]你也可以拿我开心啊
[en:]I use my wit, not my hands.[fix] Why don't you use yours?[fix]
[fre:]Pourquoi tu ne ferais pas pareil ?
[ar:]لا...لا يهمني إن مازحتِني
[ko:]그런데 네가 망쳤잖아.[fix]
[ru:]Я попытался пошутить.[fix] Почему бы тебе тоже не попытаться?[fix]
[zh:]你这样可不好
[en:]You're not being very nice.[fix]
[ar:]أنت لا تتصرف بشكل لطيف
[ru:]Что-то с тобой нехорошее творится.[fix]
[zh:]我是不好
[en:]I'm not a nice person.[fix]
[fre:]- Tu n'es pas très gentil. - Je suis gentil.[fix]
[ar:]لست شخصا لطيفا
[ko:]난 내 머리를 썼어, 손을 쓴게 아니라고.[fix] 너는 왜 손을 쓰는데?[fix] 너 아주 못됐구나.[fix]
[ru:]А я и сам не хороший.[fix]
[zh:]我是说 你对我不象以前那么好
[en:]I mean, you're not like you were before.[fix]
[fre:]Je veux dire, pas comme avant.
[ar:]أقصد أنك لست كما كنت من قبل معي[fix]
[ru:]Ты раньше таким не был, ты изменился.[fix]
[zh:]我以前对你这样 一直对你这样
[en:]I am too.[fix]
[fre:]Si, je le suis.
[ar:]أنا معك تماما كما كنت من قبل[fix] لم يكن الحال هكذا[fix]
[ko:]나 못됐어.[fix] 내 말은, 네가 전과 같지 안다는거야.[fix]
[ru:]Ты тоже.[fix]
[zh:]你以前不这样
[fre:]Non, tu ne l'es pas.
[zh:]你以前还不这样哪
[en:]No, you're not.[fix] Well, you're not either.[fix]
[fre:]D'accord, mais toi non plus.
[ar:]!أنت لم تكوني هكذا من قبل[fix]
[ko:]난 똑같아.[fix] 아니, 달라.[fix] 그럼, 너도 달라.[fix]
[ru:]Я не изменилась.[fix] Ну и я тоже.[fix]
[zh:]你是不是有点讨厌我啦
[en:]Are you sick of me?
[fre:]Tu en as marre de moi ?
[ar:]مللتَ مني؟
[ko:]이제 내가 싫어졌니?[fix]
[ru:]Я тебя раздражаю?
[zh:]讨厌怎么着
[en:]So what if I were?[fix]
[fre:]Et si je l'étais ?
[ru:]А что, если я скажу "да"?[fix]
[zh:]不讨厌怎么着
[en:]What if I were not?[fix]
[fre:]Et si je ne l'étais pas ?
[ar:]وإن مللت؟ وإن لم أمل؟[fix]
[ru:]А что, если скажу "нет"?[fix]
[zh:]不讨厌 我们就好好过生日
[en:]If you're not, I'll stay for your birthday.[fix]
[fre:]Si non, je reste pour ton anniversaire.
[ar:]إن لم تمل يمكننا الاحتفال بعيد ميلادك
[ko:]그러면 어쩔건데?[fix] 안 그러면 어쩔거고?[fix] 안 그렇다면, 여기 있을거고.[fix]
[ru:]Если нет, то я останусь на твоем дне рождения.[fix]
[zh:]讨厌我就走了
[fre:]Si oui, je m'en vais.
[ar:]ولكن إن مللتَ، يمكنني أن اذهب
[zh:]哎
[en:]If you are, I'll go.
[fre:]Camarade serveuse !
[ar:]أيتها الرفيقة النادلة
[ru:]Если да - я уйду.
[zh:]服务员同志 我们的菜得上了吧
[en:]Comrade Waitress![fix] Can't you bring us our food?[fix]
[fre:]On peut nous apporter la nourriture ?
[ar:]ألا يمكن إحضار طعامنا؟
[ko:]그렇다면,  난 갈거야.[fix] 종업원 동지![fix]
[ru:]Товарищ официантка![fix] Нам принесут еду или нет?[fix]
[zh:]大家都饿得不行了
[en:]We're so hungry we are getting cranky.[fix]
[fre:]On a si faim que certains commencent à devenir grincheux.
[ar:]من شدة الجوع صرنا عصبيين
[ru:]Нас уже шатает от голода.[fix]
[zh:]那你走吧
[en:]Then go.[fix]
[fre:]Alors pars.
[ar:]اذهب إذن[fix]
[ko:]여기 음식 안 줘요?[fix] 너무 배가 고파서,  우리 뒤집어지고 있어요.[fix] 그럼 가.[fix]
[ru:]Тогда уходи.[fix]
[zh:]我能问为什么吗
[en:]Can I ask why?[fix]
[fre:]Je peux connaître la raison ?
[ar:]ممكن اسأل ما السبب؟
[ru:]Могу я спросить - почему?[fix]
[zh:]不为什么
[en:]No reason.[fix]
[fre:]Il n'y en a pas.
[ar:]لا يوجد سبب
[ko:]이유가 뭐야?[fix]
[ru:]Нет, не можешь.[fix]
[zh:]马小军 你消消气
[en:]Calm down, Ma Xiaojun.[fix]
[fre:]Calme-toi, Ma Xiaojun.
[ar:]ماشياو جون)، هدئ أعصابك)[fix]
[ko:]이유 없어.[fix]
[ru:]Успокойся, Ма Сяоцзюнь.[fix]
[zh:]算了
[fre:]Laisse tomber.
[ar:]أجل، انسى يا قرد[fix]
[zh:]不行 你让她走
[en:]Drop it.[fix] No. Let her go![fix]
[fre:]Non. Qu'elle parte !
[ar:]!كلا! دعها تذهب
[ko:]마샤오준, 진정해라.[fix]
[ru:]Завязывай, а?[fix] Нет. Пусть она уйдет.[fix]
[zh:]哎呀 哥们 菜都上了
[ar:]يا قرد توقف يكاد يصل الطعام
[zh:]人家也饿了
[en:]Monkey, drop it. Hunger's put us on edge.[fix]
[fre:]Monkey, arrête. Ta colère nous met mal à l'aise.[fix]
[ar:]الجوع يسبب الغضب[fix] انظر إلي، حتى أنا منزعج قليلا انسى، حسنا؟[fix]
[ko:]그만 둬.[fix] 아니, 얘 가라고 해![fix] 원숭아, 그만 해라. 배고파서 그런가보다.[fix]
[ru:]Обезьяна, подвязывай. На тебя голод плохо влияет.[fix]
[zh:]哎 你怎么还不走啊
[en:]You still haven't left?[fix]
[fre:]Tu n'es toujours pas partie ?
[ar:]لم تذهبي بعد؟
[ru:]Ты все еще здесь?[fix]
[zh:]不是你自个儿说要走的吗 滚
[en:]Didn't you say you'd go? Fuck off![fix]
[fre:]Tu n'avais pas dit que tu partirais ? Dégage !
[ar:]ألم تقولي أنك ستذهبين؟[fix] !اخرجي[fix]
[ko:]왜 안 가고 있어?[fix] 간다고 말 안했어?  꺼져![fix]
[ru:]Ты же говорила, что уйдешь? Иди нахрен отсюда![fix]
[zh:]我还是走吧
[en:]I'd better go then.[fix]
[fre:]Je ferais mieux de partir alors.
[ar:]أظن أني سأذهب إذن[fix]
[ko:]그래, 가는게 좋겠다.[fix]
[ru:]Я пойду.[fix]
[zh:]就坐这儿
[en:]Sit down.[fix]
[fre:]Reste assise.
[ar:]اجلسي[fix]
[ru:]Садись.[fix]
[zh:]马小军 别让她走成不成 看在我面上
[en:]Ma Xiaojun? Give me a litter face and let her stay, all right?[fix]
[fre:]Ma Xiaojun ? Sois sympa et laisse la rester, OK ?
[ar:]ماشياو جون)، دعها تبقى) حسنا؟ احترمني قليلا[fix]
[ko:]앉아.[fix] 마샤오준. 할 말 있으면 나한테 하고, 미란은 그냥 있게 해라, 됐지?[fix]
[ru:]Ма Сяоцзюнь. Если хочешь разрядиться - дай мне в морду, и пусть она останется. ОК?[fix]
[zh:]我今天谁的面子都不看
[en:]No way.[fix]
[fre:]Pas question !
[ar:]لن احترم أحدا اليوم
[ru:]Никогда.[fix]
[zh:]谁要护着她 我就跟谁急
[en:]I'll take on anyone who's on her side.[fix]
[fre:]Je frapperai tous ceux qui sont de son côté.
[ar:]سأتحدى أي أحد ينحاز لجانبها[fix]
[ko:]싫어.[fix]
[ru:]Я вызову каждого, кто за нее впряжется.[fix]
[zh:]马小军 你别给脸不要脸啊
[ar:]ماشياو جون)، من لا يحترم) لا يُحترم[fix]
[zh:]我可没功夫搭理你
[fre:]Je le suis, alors tu vas me frapper ?[fix]
[ar:]أفتقد الصبر اللازم للتعامل معك
[ko:]누구든지 미란이 편드는 사람은 가만 안둘거야.[fix]
[ru:]Обезьяна, в последний раз предлагаю - брось быковать.
[zh:]我去你妈的 我今天就冲着你
[en:]Fuck you, it's you I'm pissed off at![fix]
[fre:]Va te faire foutre, c'est à toi que j'en veux !
[ar:]!اللعنة على أمك! سأتقاتل معك
[ru:]Мать твою, как ты меня достал![fix]
[zh:]抽你丫的
[en:]I'll kill you![fix]
[fre:]J'vais te tuer !
[ar:]!اخرس[fix]
[ko:]집어쳐, 내가 화가 나는 사람은  바로 너야![fix] 너 죽여버린다![fix]
[ru:]Я убью тебя![fix]
[zh:]我非叉了你
[en:]I'll get you! You're dead![fix]
[fre:]Je vais t'avoir ! T'es mort !
[ar:]!سأقطعك إربا[fix]
[ko:]가만 안 둘거야. 넌 죽었어![fix]
[ru:]Ну все. Ты покойник.[fix]
[zh:]千万别相信这个
[en:]Ha ha! don't believe any of it.[fix]
[fre:]Ha ha ! Tout ceci est faux.
[ar:]لا تصدقوا أي كلمة من هذا
[ru:]Не верьте ничему из показанного.[fix]
[zh:]我从来就没有这样勇敢过
[en:]I never did anything so "heroic" in my life.[fix]
[fre:]Je n'ai jamais rien fait d'aussi "héroïque" dans ma vie.[fix]
[ar:]لم يسبق أن فعلتُ شيئا بهذه البطولية والشجاعة[fix]
[ko:]하하~! 이 이야기를 믿지는 마시길...[fix]
[ru:]Никаких подобных "геройств" в моей жизни не было.[fix]
[zh:]这样壮烈过
[zh:]我不断发誓 要老老实实讲故事
[en:]I keep reminding my self to tell the truth.[fix]
[fre:]Je m'oblige à dire la vérité,
[ar:]إني أطلقُ الوعود أن اسرد القصة بصدق
[ko:]내 인생에서 그렇게 '영웅'적인 행동을 한 적은 없었다.[fix]
[ru:]Я постоянно напоминаю себе - говори только правду![fix]
[zh:]可是说真话的愿望有多么强烈
[en:]But no matter how I try,[fix]
[fre:]mais malgré ça,
[ar:]ولكن مهما كانت قوة رغبتي ، بقول الحقيقة
[ko:]그 때 있었던 일을 생각해내려고 하는데,[fix]
[ru:]Но все равно раз за разом[fix]
[zh:]受到的各种干扰就有多么大
[en:]something keeps interfering.
[fre:]quelque chose vient toujours interférer,
[ar:].يستمر تتداخل الأمور
[ko:]아무리 노력을 해도,[fix] 무언가가 자꾸 끼어들고,[fix]
[ru:]что-то продолжает вмешиваться
[zh:]我悲哀的发现
[en:]and the facts slip away.[fix]
[ru:]и факты ускользают.[fix]
[zh:]根本就无法还原真实
[fre:]et les faits dérivent.[fix]
[ar:]اكتشفتُ بشكل مأساوي أنه لا يمكن إطلاقا العودة للحقيقة الأصلية[fix]
[ko:]진실은 슬그머니 사라져버린다.[fix]
[zh:]记忆总是被我的情感改头换面
[en:]My memory plays with and betrays me.[fix]
[fre:]Ma mémoire me joue des tours.[fix]
[ru:]Моя память играет со мной и предает меня[fix]
[zh:]并随之捉弄我 背叛我
[ar:]ذاكرتي تجعل مشاعري تبدو سطحية وتتلاعب معي، وتخونني[fix]
[ko:]내 기억이 날 희롱하고 배반하는군.[fix]
[zh:]把我搞的头脑混乱
[en:]I don't know what the truth is myself.[fix]
[fre:]Je ne connais pas moi-même la vérité.[fix]
[ar:]وتلقي بعقلي لهذه الفوضى التي لا أميز فيها الحقيقة من الكذب[fix]
[ru:]И я не знаю, что было на самом деле.[fix]
[zh:]真伪难辨
[zh:]我现在怀疑和米兰 第一次相识就是伪造的
[en:]I even suspect I didn't meet Mi Lan for the first time...[fix]
[fre:]J'ai plutôt l'impression que je n'ai pas rencontré Mi Lan[fix]
[ar:]أظن الآن أن اللقاء الأول مع مي لان) كان محرّفاً)[fix]
[ko:]진실이 무엇인지는 나 자신도 모른다.[fix] 내가 처음에 미란을 길거리에서  만난게 아니라, 그녀가 방문했을 때,[fix]
[ru:]Я даже подозреваю, что впервые встретил Ми Лань не на улице,[fix]
[zh:]其实我根本就没在马路上遇见过她
[en:]on the street but when she visited.[fix]
[fre:]pour la première fois, dans la rue, mais quand elle est venue nous voir.[fix]
[ar:]وفي الواقع لم أرها أبدا في الشارع تلك المرة[fix]
[ru:]а в тот день, когда она пришла к нам.[fix]
[zh:]那天下午我和大蚂蚁 受刘忆苦的委派
[en:]That afternoon, Liu Yiku asked her over, and Big Ant and I...[fix]
[fre:]Ce soir-là, Liu Yiku lui a dit de venir, et moi et Big Ant,
[ar:]في عصر ذلك اليوم ...قال لي (ليو إيكو) أنا والنملة
[ko:]처음 만난게 아닌가하는 생각까지 든다.[fix] 그날 오후, 류이쿠가 그녀를 초대했고,  그래서 왕개미와 나는...[fix]
[ru:]Лю Еку все-таки зазвал ее, и мы с Муравьем[fix]
[zh:]在门口等米兰
[ar:]أن ننتظر (مي لان) عند البوابة
[zh:]才是我们第一次认识
[en:]waited at the gate for her...[fix] that's the first time we met...[fix]
[fre:]l'avons attendu à la porte... Ce fut notre première rencontre...[fix]
[ar:]كانت تلك أول مرة نلتقي فيها
[ko:]문간에서 그녀를 기다렸다...[fix]
[ru:]ждали ее у ворот.[fix] Там мы и познакомились.[fix]
[zh:]这也说明为什么我和 大蚂蚁去玩什么瓦西里
[en:]and that's why Big Ant and I played Vasily.[fix]
[fre:]et c'est pour ça qu'on a joué à Vasily,
[ar:]هذا السبب أني أنا والنملة (ذهبنا للعب دور (فاسيلي
[ko:]그게 우리의 처음 만남이었고...[fix] 왕개미와 내가  바실리 놀이를 한 이유였다.[fix]
[ru:]Именно поэтому мы с Муравьем играли в Василия,[fix]
[zh:]而没有参加谈话
[en:]and didn't talk a lot to her.[fix]
[fre:]et qu'on ne lui a pas beaucoup parlé.
[ru:]а не разговаривали с ней.[fix]
[zh:]因为我和米兰根本就不熟
[en:]I hardly knew her.[fix]
[fre:]Je la connaissais à peine.
[ar:]ولم أتحدث معها كثيرا .لأني لم أكن أعرفها جيدا حتى[fix]
[ko:]그래서 그녀와 말을 많이 나누지 못했다.[fix]
[ru:]Я едва знал ее.[fix]
[zh:]我和米兰从来就没熟过
[en:]In fact, I never really knew her.[fix]
[fre:]En fait, je crois ne l'avoir jamais vraiment connue.
[ar:]لم أكن مقربا من (مي لان) أبدا[fix]
[ko:]나는 그녀에 대해 거의 모른다.[fix] 사실, 그녀에 대해 아는게 진짜로 없다.[fix]
[ru:]По сути, мы практически не общались.[fix]
[zh:]天哪
[en:]Heavens![fix]
[fre:]Mon Dieu !
[ar:]...يا إلهي
[ru:]Боже мой![fix]
[zh:]米兰是照片上的那个女孩吗
[en:]Is Mi Lan the girl in the photograph?[fix]
[fre:]Est-ce que c'était Mi Lan sur la photo ?
[ar:]أكانت (مي لان) هي الفتاة بالصورة؟
[ko:]맙소사![fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань ли была та девочка с фотографии?[fix]
[zh:]还有余北蓓 怎么突然消失了呢
[en:]And whatever happened to Yu Beipei?[fix]
[fre:]Et qu'est-il arrivé à Yu Beipei ?
[ar:]ولماذا اختفت (يو بـيـپـي) فجأة؟[fix]
[ko:]그 사진속의 여자가 미란인가?[fix] 유베이페이에겐 무슨 일이 생겼던거지?[fix]
[ru:]И куда делась Юй Бэйпэй?[fix]
[zh:]或许
[en:]Maybe...[fix]
[fre:]Peut être que...
[ar:]...ربما
[ru:]А может быть... Может,[fix]
[zh:]或许她们俩 原本就是同一个人
[en:]she and Mi Lan were the same person?[fix]
[fre:]elle et Mi Lan sont la même et unique personne ?
[ar:](ربما أنها هي و(مي لان ذات الشخص؟[fix]
[ko:]어쩌면...[fix] 유베이페이와 미란은 같은 사람이었을까?[fix]
[ru:]она и Ми Лань были одним человеком?[fix]
[zh:]我简直不敢再往下想
[en:]I really don't dare think about it.[fix]
[fre:]Je n'arrête pas d'y penser.
[ar:]ببساطة لا أجرؤ على التفكير في ذلك كثيرا[fix]
[ko:]설마 진짜로 그럴거라고는  생각하지 않는다.[fix]
[ru:]Я даже не смею думать об этом.[fix]
[zh:]我以真诚的愿望开始讲述的故事
[en:]I started telling this story in all sincerity and...[fix]
[fre:]J'ai commencé cette histoire en toute sincérité,
[ar:]بدأتُ سرد هذه القصة بكل صدق[fix]
[ru:]Я начал рассказывать эту историю с предельной искренностью, и...[fix]
[zh:]经过巨大坚韧不拔的 努力却变成了谎言
[en:]then forced it to turn into a lie.[fix]
[fre:]et je me suis forcé à tout embellir.
[ar:]لكن برغم جهودي الجبارة والحازمة تحولت القصة لكذبة[fix]
[ko:]나는 이 이야기를 아주 성실하게  끌고 왔다...[fix] 그런데 그만 거짓말이 되버렸다.[fix]
[ru:]в какой-то момент заврался окончательно.[fix]
[zh:]难道就此放弃吗
[en:]Is that a reason to give it up?[fix]
[fre:]Mais c'est pas une raison pour l'arrêter !
[ar:]ولكن أهذا سبب لتركها تماما؟[fix]
[ru:]Стоит ли из-за этого бросить ее?[fix]
[zh:]不 绝不能
[fre:]Non, non.
[ar:]لا! بالتأكيد لا[fix]
[zh:]你忍心让我这样做
[en:]No, no.[fix] and you wouldn't want me to, either...[fix]
[fre:]et vous ne voudriez pas, vous non plus.
[ar:]كيف ستسامحوني إن فعلتُ ذلك؟[fix]
[ko:]이 이야기를 더 이상 하지 말까?[fix] 아니, 아니.[fix] 여러분들은 내가 그렇게하는걸 원치 않을 것이다.[fix]
[ru:]Нет, думаю, нет.[fix] Надеюсь, вы этого тоже не хотите.[fix]
[zh:]我现在非常理解
[zh:]那些坚持谎言的人的处境
[en:]How hard it is to keep your promises![fix]
[fre:]C'est si dur de garder une promesse ![fix]
[ar:]فهمتُ جيدا الآن مأزق الشخص الملازم للكذب[fix]
[ru:]Как тяжело исполнять обещания![fix]
[zh:]要做个诚实的人
[en:]True honesty is impossible.[fix]
[fre:]Une totale honnêteté est impossible.[fix]
[ru:]Истинная честность невозможна.[fix]
[zh:]简直不可能
[ar:].الذي يحاول أن يصبح صادقا هذا ببساطة مستحيل[fix]
[ko:]약속을 지킨다는 것이 얼마나 어려운 일인가![fix] 진실한 정직이란 불가능하다.[fix]
[zh:]听 你听
[en:]Listen,[fix]
[fre:]En fait,
[ar:]!اسمعوا، اسمعوا
[ru:]Помните -[fix]
[zh:]有时候一种声音或是一种味道
[en:]sometimes a sound or a smell...[fix]
[fre:]parfois un son ou une odeur
[ar:]أحيانا صوت معين أو رائحة معينة تعيدك للماضي الحقيقي[fix]
[ko:]계속하겠다,[fix]
[ru:]иногда случайный звук или запах[fix]
[zh:]可以把人带回真实的过去
[en:]takes you right back to the past.[fix]
[fre:]vous ramène dans le passé.
[ko:]때때로 소리 하나, 냄새 하나가...[fix] 당신을 곧바로 과거로 데리고 간다.[fix]
[ru:]ни с того, ни с сего вдруг возвращает нас в прошлое.[fix]
[zh:]现在我的头脑 如皎洁的月亮一般清醒
[en:]My head is as clear as the moon.[fix]
[fre:]Mon esprit est aussi clair que la lune maintenant.[fix]
[ar:]رأسي الآن واضح كقمر ساطع[fix]
[ko:]지금 내 머리는 달빛만큼이나 맑다.[fix]
[ru:]Сейчас я вернулся. Моя голова ясная как луна.[fix]
[zh:]好吧 就此继续说我们的故事
[en:]So I'll continue our story.[fix]
[fre:]Alors je continue notre histoire,
[ru:]Раз так, я продолжу свою историю.[fix]
[zh:]先不管它是真是假
[en:]Never mind whether it's the truth.[fix]
[fre:]peu importe si c'est la vérité ou non.
[ar:]لذا سأواصل قصتي سواء كانت الحقيقة أم لا[fix]
[ko:]그래서 우리 이야기를 계속하겠다.[fix] 그게 진실인지 아닌지는 신경쓰지 말도록![fix]
[ru:]И не спрашивайте меня - что было по-правде.[fix]
[zh:]记得过生日那天
[zh:]根本没发生过任何不快
[en:]Nothing bad happened...[fix] on my birthday.[fix]
[fre:]Il ne s'est rien passé de mal durant mon anniversaire.[fix]
[ar:]أتذكر أنه بيوم عيد ميلادي ذاك لم يحدث شيء إطلاقا[fix]
[ko:]내 생일날, 나쁜 일은...[fix] 일어나지 않았다.[fix]
[ru:]На моем дне рождения[fix] не случилось ничего страшного.[fix]
[zh:]我和刘忆苦都很高兴
[en:]Liu Yiku and I had a great time...[fix]
[fre:]Moi et Liu Yiku avons passé un bon moment,
[ru:]Лю Еку и я замечательно развлекались.[fix]
[zh:]还轮流和米兰碰杯
[en:]taking turns toasting Mi Lan.[fix]
[fre:]trinquant chacun notre tour avec Mi Lan.
[ar:]استمتعت أنا و(ليو إيكو) بالتناول (في الشرب نخب (مي لان[fix]
[ko:]류이쿠와 나는  아주 즐거웠고...[fix] 미란과 차례로 축배를 들었다.[fix]
[ru:]попеременно выпивая за Ми Лань.[fix]
[zh:]哦 对 余北蓓也在
[en:]Yu Beipei was there too.[fix]
[fre:]Yu Beipei était là aussi.
[ar:]وبالمناسبة، (يو بيـپـي) كانت حاضرة أيضا
[ru:]Юй Бэйпэй тоже была там.[fix]
[zh:]差点又忘了
[en:]I almost forgot.[fix]
[fre:]J'ai failli oublier,
[ar:].كدت انسى
[ko:]그곳엔 유베이페이도 있었다.[fix]
[ru:]Я чуть не забыл об этом.[fix]
[zh:]大家还送了很多礼品
[en:]There were stacks of gifts.[fix]
[fre:]il y avait des tonnes de cadeaux.
[ar:]كان هناك أكوام هدايا[fix]
[ru:]Были стопки подарков.[fix]
[zh:]米兰对我也格外亲切
[en:]Mi Lan was really affectionate,[fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan était vraiment gentille,
[ar:]و (مي لان) كانت ودودة بي بشكل واضح
[ko:]거의 기억에는 없지만,[fix] 그곳엔 선물도 잔뜩 쌓여있었다.[fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань была очень нежной[fix]
[zh:]那锥子般的目光频频凝视着我
[en:]fixing me with that gimlet gaze of hers.[fix]
[fre:]me fixant avec ce regard si particulier.
[ar:]تحدق بي مرارا وتكرار .بنظرتها الخارقة تلك[fix]
[ko:]미란은 정말 매혹적이었고,[fix] 그녀의 시선은 나를 꼼짝못하게 했다.[fix]
[ru:]И пристально следила за мной своими невозможными глазами.[fix]
[zh:]后来
[zh:]我们都醉了
[en:]We all got very drunk.[fix]
[fre:]On avait tous beaucoup bu.[fix]
[ar:]في النهاية، ثملنا جميعنا[fix]
[ko:]우리 모두는 아주 취했다.[fix]
[ru:]Мы все нажрались как свиньи.[fix]
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan![fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:]!(مي لان)[fix]
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan![fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:]!(مي لان)
[ko:]미란![fix] 미란![fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань![fix]
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan![fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:]!(مي لان)[fix]
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan![fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:]!(مي لان)[fix]
[ko:]미란![fix] 미란![fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань![fix]
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan![fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:]!(مي لان)
[ko:]미란![fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань![fix]
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan![fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:]!(مي لان)[fix] !(مي لان)[fix]
[ko:]미란![fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань![fix]
[zh:]米兰
[en:]Mi Lan![fix]
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:]!(مي لان)
[ko:]미란![fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань![fix]
[zh:]米兰
[fre:]Mi Lan !
[ar:]مي لان)؟)
[zh:]马小军
[en:]Mi Lan![fix] Ma Xiaojun?[fix]
[fre:]Ma Xiaojun ?[fix]
[ar:]ماشياو جون)؟)[fix]
[ko:]미란![fix] 마샤오준?[fix]
[ru:]Ми Лань![fix] Ма Сяоцзюнь?[fix]
[zh:]怎么啦
[en:]What is it?[fix]
[fre:]Qu'est-ce qu'il y a ?
[ar:]ما الأمر؟
[ru:]Что с тобой?[fix]
[zh:]你怎么了
[en:]What's wrong?[fix]
[fre:]Ça ne va pas ?
[ar:]ماذا هناك؟
[ko:]뭐야?[fix] 왜 그래?[fix]
[ru:]Что случилось?[fix]
[zh:]你到底怎么了 快告诉我
[en:]Tell me, what's wrong?[fix]
[fre:]Dis-moi, qu'est-ce qui ne va pas ?
[ar:]قل لي، ما بك؟[fix]
[ru:]Скажи мне - что произошло?[fix]
[zh:]我喜欢你
[en:]I really like you.[fix]
[fre:]Je t'aime vraiment.
[ar:]!أحبك[fix]
[ko:]말해 봐, 왜 그래?[fix]
[ru:]Я люблю тебя.[fix]
[zh:]你说什么
[en:]What?[fix]
[fre:]Quoi ?
[ar:]ماذا؟[fix]
[ko:]니가 진짜 좋아.[fix] 뭐라고?[fix]
[ru:]Что?[fix]
[zh:]你刚才说什么
[en:]What are you saying?[fix]
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que tu dis ?
[ar:]ماذا قلت؟
[ru:]Что ты сказал?[fix]
[zh:]我车掉沟里了
[en:]I... my bike... my bike fell in the ditch.[fix]
[fre:]Je... mon vélo... mon vélo est tombé dans le fossé.
[ar:]سقطت دراجتي في الحفرة[fix]
[ko:]뭐라고 했어?[fix] 내...내 자전거가...자전거가... 도랑에 빠졌어.[fix]
[ru:]Я... мой велик... мой велик упал в канаву.[fix]
[zh:]雨过天晴
[fre:]Après ça,
[zh:]似乎什么事都没发生过
[en:]Afterwards...[fix] it seemed that nothing had happened.[fix]
[fre:]elle fit comme si rien ne s'était passé.
[ar:]عندما توقف المطر و صفت السماء بدا وكأن لاشيء قد حدث[fix]
[ko:]그후...[fix] 아무 일도 일어나지 않았던 것처럼 보였다.[fix]
[ru:]Впоследствии...[fix] казалось, что ничего не было.[fix]
[zh:]我试图提醒她
[en:]I tried to remind her of that,[fix]
[fre:]J'ai essayé de lui y refaire penser,
[ru:]Я попытался напомнить ей об этом,[fix]
[zh:]可她仍没反应
[en:]but she didn't react at all.[fix]
[fre:]mais elle n'a pas réagi.
[ar:]حاولت أن أذكّرها بذلك لكنها لم تبدي أي ردة فعل[fix]
[ru:]но она никак не реагировала.[fix]
[zh:]对我仍然是亲切中带有客气
[en:]She still treated me nicely.[fix]
[fre:]Elle me traitait toujours avec gentillesse.
[ar:]كانت لاتزال تعاملني بمودة وأدب[fix]
[ko:]난 그녀에게 그 일을 기억하게 하려고 했지만,[fix] 그녀는 전혀 반응을 보이지 않았다.[fix] 그녀는 여전히 나를 상냥하게 대했다.[fix]
[ru:]Она продолжала очень мило со мной общаться.[fix]
[zh:]难道下雨那天晚上 发生的事儿是不真实的
[en:]Is it possible that what happened that night wasn't real?[fix]
[fre:]Ce qui s'est passé ce soir-là n'était-il pas réel ?
[ar:]أيمكن أن ما حدث بتلك الليلة الممطرة ليس حقيقيا؟[fix]
[ko:]그날 밤 일어났던 일이  진짜가 아니었다는 것이 가능할까?[fix]
[ru:]Действительно, возможно ли, что случившегося ночью, на деле не было?[fix]
[zh:]可是我身上摔伤的地方还在疼
[en:]But the part where I was injured still hurts![fix]
[fre:]Pourtant ça me fait toujours mal là où je suis tombé !
[ar:]لكن المكان الذي أصبت فيه من السقوط لازال يؤلمني[fix]
[ko:]그 때 받았던 상처가 지금도 아프다![fix]
[ru:]Но место, куда я был ранен, все еще болит[fix]
[zh:]马小军
[en:]Ma Xiaojun.[fix]
[fre:]Ma Xiaojun.
[ar:]ماشياو جون)؟)[fix]
[ko:]마샤오준.[fix]
[ru:]Ма Сяоцзюнь.[fix]
[zh:]啊
[ar:]ماذا تفعل؟
[zh:]你干什么
[fre:]Qu'est-ce que tu fais !
[ar:]!دعني[fix]
[zh:]放开我
[en:]What are you doing?
[fre:]Laisse-moi !
[ru:]Что ты делаешь?
[zh:]快放开我
[en:]Let me go![fix] Let me go![fix]
[fre:]Laisse-moi !
[ar:]!دعني حالا[fix]
[ko:]뭐하는거야?[fix] 놔![fix] 놔![fix]
[ru:]Отпусти меня![fix]
[zh:]你
[zh:]你觉得这样有劲吗
[en:]This is how you get your kicks?[fix]
[fre:]C'est comme ça que tu tires tes coups ?
[ar:]أهذا ما يثيرك؟[fix]
[ru:]Так вот что тебе было надо?[fix]
[zh:]有劲
[en:]You bet![fix]
[fre:]C'est ça !
[ar:]!أجل
[ko:]그래 재미 좋았어?[fix] 그래![fix]
[ru:]А то![fix]
[zh:]米兰和我彻底掰了
[en:]Mi Lan and I were no longer friends.[fix]
[fre:]Moi et Mi Lan ne sommes plus restés amis.
[ar:]كانت علاقتي بـ(مي لان) قد انتهت تماما
[ko:]미란과 나는 더 이상 친구가 되지 못했다.[fix]
[ru:]Так кончилась наша дружда с Ми Лань.[fix]
[zh:]不久
[fre:]Bientôt,
[zh:]我被大家孤立起来
[en:]Soon.[fix] the others began to stay away from me as well.[fix]
[fre:]les autres ont commencé aussi à me repousser.
[ar:]بعد ذلك صرتُ منبوذا من الجميع[fix]
[ko:]얼마 후,[fix]
[ru:]Вскоре[fix] и остальные начали избегать меня.[fix]
[zh:]在万分痛苦中度过一天又一天
[en:]I passed my days in bitterness and pain.[fix]
[fre:]Je vécus alors dans l'amertume et la douleur.
[ar:]بمعاناة هائلة، أمضيتُ الأيام .يوما بعد يوم[fix]
[ko:]다른 애들도 역시  나와 사이가 멀어지기 시작했다.[fix] 쓰디쓴 고통속에서 시간이 흘러갔다.[fix]
[ru:]И я проводил дни в горечи и боли.[fix]
[zh:]米兰和我们断绝了来往
[en:]Two months later. Mi Lan stopped hanging out with us.[fix]
[fre:]Deux mois plus tard, Mi Lan a arrêté de traîner avec nous.
[ar:](بعد شهرين، توقفت (مي لان عن التسكع معنا[fix]
[ko:]두달 후, 미란은 우리와  더 이상 어울리지 않았다.[fix]
[ru:]Месяца через два Ми Лань прекратила болтаться с нами.[fix]
[zh:]年底 刘忆苦又当兵走了
[en:]At the end of the year, Liu Yiku went back to the army...[fix]
[fre:]À la fin de l'année, Liu Yiku est reparti à l'armée,
[ar:]بنهاية السنة، عاد (ليو إيكو) للجيش[fix]
[ru:]В конце года Лю Еку вернулся в армию[fix]
[zh:]而且有了正式的女朋友
[en:]and found a proper girlfriend.[fix]
[fre:]et s'est trouvé une petite amie.
[ar:]ووجد صديقة مناسبة[fix]
[ko:]그해가 끝날 때쯤, 류이쿠는 군대로 되돌아갔고...[fix]
[ru:]и нашел себе приличную подругу.[fix]
[zh:]后来我们也都分别去了部队
[en:]Later, we all went into the army.[fix]
[fre:]Plus tard, on s'est tous engagés.
[ar:]لاحقا، تفرقنا جميعنا لوحدات عسكرية مختلفة
[ko:]어울리는 여자 친구를 만났다.[fix]
[ru:]Позже мы все тоже ушли в армию.[fix]
[zh:]听说刘忆苦在南边打仗的时候
[en:]I heard that Liu Yiku went mad...[fix]
[fre:]J'ai appris que Liu Yiku était devenu fou
[ar:]، سمعتُ أن في الحرب الحدودية مع فيتنام[fix]
[ko:]훗날, 우리 모두는 군대에 갔다.[fix]
[ru:]Я слышал, что Лю Еку сошел с ума[fix]
[zh:]被炮弹震傻了
[en:]in the border war with Vietnam.[fix]
[fre:]lors des guerres à la frontière du Vietnam.
[ar:]عانى (ليو إيكو) من اضطراب عصبي[fix]
[ko:]류이쿠는 베트남과의 국경 분쟁의 와중에,[fix]
[ru:]в пограничной войне с Вьетнамом.[fix]
[zh:]再后来 以至音信皆无
[en:]We all lost touch after awhile.[fix]
[fre:]On s'est tous perdus de vue pendant un bon moment.
[ar:]، بعد فترة[fix] لم يعد هناك تواصل تماما بين الجميع[fix]
[ko:]미쳐버렸다는 소식이 들렸다.[fix] 얼마 후, 우리 모두는 소식이 끊어졌다.[fix]
[ru:]Через какое-то время мы все потеряли друг друга.[fix]
[zh:]你们看这是谁在这儿
[fre:]Quoi ? Qu'est-ce qu'il y a ?
[ar:]انظروا، أليس هذا...؟[fix]
[zh:]这不是谁吗
[en:]What now? What's going on?
[fre:]Qui c'est ?
[ar:]من هذا؟ - !اوبا -[fix]
[ru:]Ну что еще? Что происходит?
[zh:]古伦木
[en:]Who's that?[fix] Oo! Oo-ba![fix]
[fre:]Oo ! Oo-ba !
[ar:]ما تعني بـ"اوبا" ؟ !"إنها "غلومو[fix]
[ru:]Кто это?[fix] Оо! Оо-ба![fix]
[zh:]对 对 对 古伦木
[en:]What do you mean "Oo-ba"? It's "Gooloomoo"![fix]
[fre:]Pourquoi tu dis "Oo-ba" ? C'est "Gooloomoo" !
[ar:]!أوه، صحيح! غلومو[fix]
[ko:]아니, 저게 뭐야?[fix] 저게 누구야?[fix]
[ru:]Что значит это "Оо-ба!"? А "Гулуму"?[fix]
[zh:]古伦木
[en:]Gooloomoo![fix]
[fre:]Gooloomoo !
[ar:]!غلومو - !غلومو -[fix]
[ko:]오! 오-바![fix] - "오-바"라니, 무슨 말이야? - 저기 "구루무"야!.[fix] 구루무![fix]
[ru:]Гулуму![fix]
[zh:]哎 古伦木
[en:]Hey! Gooloomoo![fix]
[fre:]Hé ! Gooloomoo !
[ru:]Эй! Гулуму![fix]
[zh:]古伦木
[en:]Gooloomoo![fix]
[fre:]Gooloomoo !
[ko:]어이, 구루무![fix] 구루무![fix]
[ru:]Гулуму![fix]
[zh:]古伦木
[en:]Gooloomoo![fix]
[fre:]Gooloomoo !
[zh:]古伦木
[en:]Gooloomoo![fix]
[fre:]Gooloomoo !
[zh:]傻逼
[en:]Cretin.[fix]
[fre:]Crétins !
[ar:]!أغبياء[fix]
[ko:]구루무![fix] 구루무![fix] 바보.[fix]
[ru:]Идиоты.[fix]
[zh:]-=The Last Fantasy=- 荣誉出品，谢谢观赏
[ar:]ترجمة: أحمد البوقس